<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>goals on PLA Cycling Log</title>
    <link>https://pla.bike/tags/goals/</link>
    <description>Recent content in goals on PLA Cycling Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 16:30:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pla.bike/tags/goals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>✔ 10,000 Miles in 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20201206/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 16:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20201206/</guid>
      <description>After 130 miles yesterday I did not want to get back on the bike today but with my mileage goal within reach I saddled up. Glad I did. Goal accomplished. Currently have 10,004 logged miles for 2020. There are still 25 days left in the year. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll shoot for 11,000 or maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll chill.
VeloViewer
Ride on. ☮



 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100th Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20201114/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 15:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20201114/</guid>
      <description>Completed my one hundredth century ride. Feels good to accomplish another goal. My first century ride logged on Strava was May 26, 2018. I actually think I rode a few more century rides before this one but I&amp;rsquo;ll call this the first one. 903 days later I completed by 100th. Here they are on VeloViewer.
The remaining two goals for 2020 are 10,000 miles and covid-free. 9,299 miles so far. If I accomplish the last goal I should get the mileage goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awendaw Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200816/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200816/</guid>
      <description>On the road by 3:40 AM. Heading east on Hwy 402 and Steed Creek roads I could see lightning from an offshore thunderstorm. The stars were bright overhead along with a waning crescent moon. So happy I screamed &amp;ldquo;The universe is mine!&amp;quot;.
After sunrise the clouds moved in and the temperature never rose above 75℉. In hindsight I didn&amp;rsquo;t need to wake up so early.
2020 is more than half over but I finally decided on 4 goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Double Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200621/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 21:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200621/</guid>
      <description>Riding 200 miles is something that intrigued me and started to haunt me after my 160 mile Georgetown ride. What&amp;rsquo;s 40 more miles, right? A lot. I&amp;rsquo;m not getting any younger so I knocked this goal out while I still can.
Scheduling wasn&amp;rsquo;t wise on my part as it was dangerously hot. Bike computer read 104℉ a couple of times.
The first century went pretty well and was enjoyable. The second century, not so much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Childsbury Towne Heritage Preserve Again</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190609/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190609/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m really digging the ride to the Childsbury Towne Heritage Preserve. If I recall correctly I&amp;rsquo;ve cycled to it 3 weekends straight. Hwy 402 and Dr Evans Rd have a nice surface and low weekend traffic. On the way I stopped by the new YMCA in Cane Bay. From the outside this looks like a super nice facility. My favorite amenity is the water bottle refill station out by the tennis courts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>