<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>maintenance on PLA Cycling Log</title>
    <link>https://pla.bike/tags/maintenance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in maintenance on PLA Cycling Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 20:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pla.bike/tags/maintenance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bent Derailleur Hanger Repaired</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190221/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190221/</guid>
      <description>Old Yeller fell over after Tuesday&amp;rsquo;s commute. Taking a photo and the wind knocked it over bending the derailleur hanger. Took a 3 hour lunch to Mike&amp;rsquo;s Bikes on Folly Rd. They had about 50 hangers in stock but none fit mine. The technician used a derailleur hanger alignment gauge to whip it back in to shape. He also replace a jockey wheel. I finished up the day at work and went for an evening ride.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gators and Armadillos</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190217/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190217/</guid>
      <description>While repairing my two punctures yesterday I realized it was time for new tires. The Specialized Armadillo tires had a few cuts, holes and dry rot. I replaced them with Continental GatorSkin DuraSkin tires. There is nothing wrong with the Specialized Armadillo brand. It was just more convenient and quicker to add the Gatorskins to my Amazon cart instead of going to Specialized&amp;rsquo;s website.
I drove the Bolt EV back to the location of my first puncture yesterday to do some investigating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bike Fit and Maintenance</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181113/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181113/</guid>
      <description>Matty Floyd of Affordabike in Charleston performed a bike fit on me. First bike fit I&amp;rsquo;ve had. It was something I felt I should do at least once so I took the day off to get it done. I can&amp;rsquo;t remember the last time I took a day off.
Matty with the help of the GURU Dynamic Fit Unit made some changes to my fit. Raised my seat post, installed a new stem, adjusted by hoods, etc&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m sitting allot higher on the Giant Anyroad 1 bicycle now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bike Check and Product Annoyances</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180729/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180729/</guid>
      <description>Shifting was less than stellar during yesterday&amp;rsquo;s ride. Checked the chain and it is at .75% wear. Time for a replacement.

I see some wear on the cassette as well. I may get that replaced. I will drop off the Giant Anyroad 1 at Mike&amp;rsquo;s Bikes today.

The Park Cyclone Chain Scrubber works well but the rivets that hold the clips fall out. I&amp;rsquo;ve lost one rivet. The other one falls out occasionally.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>