<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on PLA Cycling Log</title>
    <link>https://pla.bike/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on PLA Cycling Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 16:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pla.bike/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Savannah</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180819/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180819/</guid>
      <description>I drove the Chevrolet Bolt EV down to Savannah GA. I parked the car at a convenience store and plugged in to their charger. I hopped on my bike to explore Savannah. Riding around the city was pretty nice but it got old after a while having to stop every block. I left the city and headed down to the Savannah National Wildlife Refuge. This was a great ride. I prefer the open roads to city riding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Bike to Work Day</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180518/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180518/</guid>
      <description>Today was National Bike to Work Day. I usually bike to work on Tuesday and Thursday but I switched this week to Wednesday and Friday to align with BTWD. We had on and off again rain all day. I managed to escape all but a few drops here and there. Pretty nice rides. Below is a snippet of my ride home. I&amp;rsquo;m not proud of this part of my ride but I just don&amp;rsquo;t feel like stopping in traffic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wednesday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180516/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180516/</guid>
      <description>Picked up Old Yeller from Mike&amp;rsquo;s Bikes yesterday. It has a new rear derailleur, chain, rear tire, and cassette. The ride to work was super smooth. Really glad to have the Giant Anyroad 1 back. It is so much nicer than my backup bike, Giant Defy 3. I can&amp;rsquo;t recall an average MPH of 20 so I think this was a personal best. There is something motivational about a new drivetrain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bushy Park</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180513/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180513/</guid>
      <description>Cycled through Cane Bay on my way to Bushy Park. Had to walk for a couple of hundred yards over a sandy road in the neighborhood under construction. Looking forward to when there is a paved road to either Black Tom Rd or 17-A. The rest of the ride was pleasant. Not as hot as yesterday and traffic was light.
 Photo album</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mmmm Cookies</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180512/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180512/</guid>
      <description>Started my morning ride off with cookies from the Cookie Chick at the Summerville Farmers Market. Cookie Chick bakes the best cookies. I ate an oatmeal rum cookie and saved a toasted almond cookie for after lunch. Good stuff. My main bike is still at the LBS so I rode the backup bike. Fortunate to have a backup bike. My primary bike seems to spend allot of time at the LBS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday Commute, Post Chipotle Ride and Topeak Chain Tool</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180510/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 19:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180510/</guid>
      <description>Thursday&amp;rsquo;s commute was uneventful. I rode to Chipotle for dinner and afterwards rode up Hwy 78. I was going to take N Maple St to the Nexton Parkway but couldn&amp;rsquo;t find N Maple St. Looked at Google Maps when I got home and realized I should have traveled a few more blocks. I headed back up 17-A and took Holiday Dr to Nexton Parkway instead. Even though I had been on Nexton Parkway many times this was the first time with automobile traffic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180508/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180508/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday&amp;rsquo;s commute was uneventful. I snapped a photo of The Corner Cafe Bakery in Moncks Corner SC. It recently closed. A Starbucks recently opened and I assume that might have played into The Corner&amp;rsquo;s decision to close. I had a rare tailwind on the way home which enabled me to break my 50 minute barrier again. Nice!
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snapped Rear Derailleur Hanger</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180506b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 19:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180506b/</guid>
      <description>A microfiber cloth flew out of my top tube bag right into my rear derailleur causing the hanger to snap. I was pulling my phone out of the bag at the time. I usually have the microfiber cloth stored in a sandwich bag but not today. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t injured. My plan was to use my chain tool to remove a section of the chain so I could ride back home. Unfortunately I have lost the pin for the chain tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garmin Insights</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180506a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 07:17:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180506a/</guid>
      <description>The Garmin Connect mobile app for Android has a feature called Insights. You can compare your fitness stats to others. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how many users there are and if there was an opt-in option for this. Some folks recommend not comparing yourself to others which is good advice. Just do your own thing and stay moving. Seeing how you stack up to others is kind of interesting and hard to resist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Folly Beach</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180505/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180505/</guid>
      <description>Another beautiful day in the lowcountry. Blue sky, low humidity and temperatures topping off in the 80&amp;rsquo;s ℉. I cycled to Folly Beach. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be happier with the way my Giant Anyroad 1 bicycle performed after being serviced yesterday at my LBS. Mike&amp;rsquo;s Bikes on Coleman Blvd Mt Pleasant replaced my rear bearing balls and cups. The drive train was silky smooth and quiet. Super nice ride.
 Photo album</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintenance Friday and Why I Don&#39;t Use Clipless Pedals</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180504/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180504/</guid>
      <description>Heard noise from my rear hub on my Thursday commute. Took the Giant Anyroad 1 into Mike&amp;rsquo;s Bikes. They replaced the bearing balls and cups. I had introduced water and dirt into the bearings when I washed my bike with a pressure washer. I thought I was being gentle with the washer. Obviously not gentle enough. Lesson learned. Being an apartment dweller I don&amp;rsquo;t have access to a water hose. That is why I was going to the car wash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180503/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180503/</guid>
      <description>Wheee - just having fun! Gorgeous weather continues. I didn&amp;rsquo;t like the way my rear hub was sounding so I dropped off my Giant Anyroad 1 bike at Mike&amp;rsquo;s Bikes in Mt Pleasant. Asked them to check all the bearings. Hopeful it will be a one day turn around so I can have it for the weekend. If not I&amp;rsquo;ll be riding my Giant Defy 3 and wishing I was on my Anyroad 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180501/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180501/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday&amp;rsquo;s commute had a big temperature swing. According to my Garmin 520 bicycle computer the minimum temperature was 39℉ and the maximum temperature was 82℉. That is a 43℉ swing.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley River</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180429/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180429/</guid>
      <description>Rode to the Ashley River. Temperature was about 10 degrees cooler than yesterday and a little more wind. Still had a clear blue sky. Pretty nice.
 Photo album</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Moultrie Loop</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180428/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180428/</guid>
      <description>Absolutely a gorgeous day for a long ride. Started out in the low 50&amp;rsquo;s ℉ and ended in the mid 70&amp;rsquo;s ℉. There wasn&amp;rsquo;t a cloud in the sky and the winds were light. Perfect! I chose to loop around Lake Moultrie.
 Photo album</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180426/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180426/</guid>
      <description>My Thursday commute was dry, comfortable, and uneventful. I got up at 5 AM and was on the road by 5:30 AM. I think I will stick with this schedule. I&amp;rsquo;d like to sleep an hour later but it is not worth the increased traffic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180424/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180424/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday commute started out wet with mist and a couple of showers. The ride home was dry, unlike my shoes, and partly cloudy. One thing is for sure the traffic is far better at 5:30 AM than at 6:30 AM. The traffic is lighter and a little less frantic. Absolutely worth getting up at 5 AM for.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Moultrie</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180422/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180422/</guid>
      <description>Sunday ride to the lovely Lake Moultrie. So grateful to have this lake within riding distance from my apartment. The dike surface is gravel and dirt. As long as it hasn&amp;rsquo;t rained it is easy to navigate. I must say my Giant Anyroad 1 with 32c tires handles the terrain comfortably. Got up on the dike at the end of W Dike Rd in Pinopolis SC and exited at the Hatchery Boat Ramp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charleston Triangle</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180421/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180421/</guid>
      <description>Saturday ride to Charleston Battery and over to West Ashley Greenway. I love the West Ashley Greenway. It is a 8.25 hike and bike trail. Mostly paved with a few gravel sections. Took the longer route home up Highway 165. The route has a triangle shape. The average temperature was 64℉ with partly cloudy skies. Pretty much perfect weather for a long weekend ride.
 Photo album</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Best on AM Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180419/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 19:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180419/</guid>
      <description>Had a rare tailwind this morning and it helped me achieve my personal best moving time of 46:59. I also had a little help from a slow moving 18 wheeler.
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contemplating the Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180418/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180418/</guid>
      <description>Contemplating my twice-a-week bicycle commute. It is 16.2 miles between Moncks Corner and Summerville. Most of the ride is on Hwy 17-A which is a busy 4 lane highway. The section from my apartment in Summerville to Cypress Gardens Rd is the busiest section. Cypress Gardens Rd intersection to Moncks Corner is lower traffic and a pleasant ride.
Pros  4 hours of exercise a week Green Commute Enjoyable Accomplishing 2 things a once (commute and exercise)  Cons  Dangerous Abuse from drivers (yelling, honking, revving, close drive by)  The benefits are many but sometimes feel that I am being irresponsible to my family and to my employer by risking my life on my bike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laps in the wind</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180415/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180415/</guid>
      <description>Recovering from an FBI event Thursday night. Ate some Golden Flake peanuts that sat in my car seat all afternoon soaking up the sun and transforming into some evil shite. This ride was 3 laps on along the I-26 frontage roads, Drop Off Dr and Red Bay Rd. Windy AF. Weak.
At the start of this ride the Garmin Edge 520 powered off for some unknown reason. That is the second Strava embed below with only 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday evening ride in lieu of a Friday commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180412/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180412/</guid>
      <description>Meeting some friends after work Friday so instead of a Friday commute I rode Thursday evening. This is my first ride with my Topeak Toploader. I like it. Nice to have my phone, gels, and batteries easily accessible. Much better than reaching around my back to my jersey pockets. The only time my knees touched the bag was when I got sloppy out of the saddle.
 Photo album</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Wednesday April 11, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180411/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180411/</guid>
      <description>Broke my cheap clear sunglasses before I got out the door. On the ride to work I got honked at once and yelled at once. A passenger in a truck yelled &amp;ldquo;Get on the sidewalk!&amp;rdquo;. Yeah, that ain&amp;rsquo;t happening. 16 miles on a sidewalk would not be fun.
We&amp;rsquo;ve got new pavement on Main St in Moncks Corner SC. So nice. The road was in really bad shape. Love cycling on new tarmac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Larry&#39;s Giant Subs</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180410/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 19:34:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180410/</guid>
      <description>Rode across town to Larry&amp;rsquo;s Giant Subs on Old Trolley Rd Summerville SC. Dropped my cheap sunglasses on the road scratching them pretty good. Slammed a turkey sub. Ran into a childhood friend and his son. Good to catch up with him.
I&amp;rsquo;m not a real fan of eating and immediately riding. It was a short ride of 6 miles so wasn&amp;rsquo;t too bad but I prefer the restaurants on my side of town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trial a longer, potentially safer route to work</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180408/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180408/</guid>
      <description>I commute twice a week from Summerville to Moncks Corner SC via Hwy 17-A which is a busy 4 lane highway. The video was taken during my trial to stay off highways as much as possible. I came out the back of Nexton, through Cane Bay, through Del Webb, onto Black Tom Rd, and finally back onto Hwy 17-A. This route is about 20 miles vs my normal route of 16 miles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overnight bicycle tour Santee SC</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180331/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180331/</guid>
      <description>Cycled to Santee SC Saturday and spent the night at the Holiday Inn. Took Hwy 6 to Santee SC and Hwy 176 on the way home. Hwy 176 is one of my least favorite roads but it is the shortest route. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t too busy on Easter Sunday.
  Photo album</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overnight bicycle tour Georgetown SC</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180324/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180324/</guid>
      <description>Cycled to Georgetown SC Saturday and spent the night at the Hampton Inn. Saturday was chilly with a headwind. The sun peaked out a few times. Sunday morning it was raining until about checkout time 11 AM. I got on the road and had a nice tailwind home. Not allot a sun but a good ride.
  Photo album</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>