<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on PLA Cycling Log</title>
    <link>https://pla.bike/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on PLA Cycling Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 13:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pla.bike/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bee City Zoo</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180908/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180908/</guid>
      <description>Biked to Bee City Zoo on some roads I had not traveled. The route limited the amount of time spent on busy two lane highways 78 &amp;amp; 61. Campbell Thickett Road was the most interesting. It turns into a clay gravel road. One the roughest roads I&amp;rsquo;ve cycled. Plenty of craters and the clay is harder than concrete.
Bee City Zoo has a wide variety of animals. Everything appeared well maintained.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday September 6, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180906/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180906/</guid>
      <description>Biked to work just one day this week due to me being a light weight after my Labor Day century ride. I&amp;rsquo;ll get two commutes next week. ☮
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labor Day Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180903/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180903/</guid>
      <description>First time riding on the Lake Marion dike and The Santee Dam. Took me a little while to find the gate to the dike. It was still dark when I arrived. I ended up at Wilson&amp;rsquo;s landing which is several miles from where I needed to be. The entrance to the dike is a yellow gate behind a Santee Cooper garage to the right of the Harry&amp;rsquo;s Fish Camp entrance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tri-County Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180901/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180901/</guid>
      <description>Woke up around 3 AM and was on the road at 4:40 AM. From Summerville I rode through Moncks Corner, Bonneau, St Stephen, Pineville, Cross, Holly Hill, and Harleyville. It was a little chilly this morning until the sun came up. Not looking forward to summer ending.
I think I fueled too much too quickly. My stomach was a little sore.
At the end of my ride I rode by the Summerville Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market for some Cookie Chick cookies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday August 30, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180830/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180830/</guid>
      <description>There was a fatal automobile accident at the Black Tom Rd and Hwy 17-A intersection this morning. Rest in ☮. I reached the scene about 20 minutes afterwards. The police had the intersection taped off. All traffic was diverted. I was able to cycle around the barrier and get to work.
My Topeak backloader bag was not strapped as tight as it should have been and sounded like a frog for most of the AM commute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday August 28, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180828/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180828/</guid>
      <description>Good work commute. Already dreaming about where I&amp;rsquo;ll ride over the upcoming Labor Day holiday three day weekend.

  Relive &amp;lsquo;Commute AM&amp;rsquo; 
Relive &amp;lsquo;Commute PM&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Folly Beach Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180825/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180825/</guid>
      <description>Woke up around 3 AM and was on the road at 4:18 AM. Nice tail wind for 70 miles. Tough head wind on the last leg of the ride. Shifting on Old Yeller is a little slow but other than that she is riding like a champ. Good day in the saddle.
 Photo album
Relive &amp;lsquo;Folly Beach Century&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180823/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180823/</guid>
      <description>Cycling yields quality spirits. I am happy with the way the photo in front of Watkins Package Store developed. 📷 It was a split decision to take a photo here. So much so I almost wipe out when I turned off the road into a sand mound. Crisis averted and photo snapped.
Up at 5 AM and pedaling by 5:21 AM. Had a head wind on the way to work and a tail on the way home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180821/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180821/</guid>
      <description>Made it to work in 46 minutes thanks to a tail wind. The wind didn&amp;rsquo;t shift during the day so I had a stiff head wind on the way home. The wind giveth and taketh away.
I haven&amp;rsquo;t commuted on the bike lately in lieu of evening rides. This commute was a little different in that I carried my clothes to work in my Topeak Backloader bag. Normally I store clothes in my office when I drive the EV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Well, I&#39;m a steamroller, baby ♪♫♬</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180819/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 19:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180819/</guid>
      <description>Ran into some rain on the last 3rd of Sunday&amp;rsquo;s ride. Cypress Gardens Rd in under repair. There were cones down the center of the road and made it difficult for cars and trucks to pass me. I got off the road at Lazy Hill Rd so the long line of cars could get in front of me.
First two thirds of the ride were pretty chill. I&amp;rsquo;ll take it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Middleton Place Gardens</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180818/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 08:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180818/</guid>
      <description>Woke up before 3 AM and was on the road by 4:10 AM. Rode down to Charleston and took Highway 61 home. I have taken Highway 61 only one other time, Thanksgiving day 2017. It is not a good road for cycling. It is very scenic but dangerously narrow. Today&amp;rsquo;s trip up Highway 61 was before 7 AM and traffic was light. I counted only 24 automobiles passed me in the lane I was traveling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday Evening Ride</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180814/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 17:21:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180814/</guid>
      <description>A pretty strong thunderstorm rolled through the area. After the rain quit the temperatures really dropped. The Garmin 520 recorded a low temperature of 66.2 °F and I believe it. I knew this ride would be short because I have a work thing tonight starting at 10 PM. I tried to keep the effort high. My average cadence was 90 rpm with a maximum cadence of 112 rpm. Good enough for a 57 year old.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday Afternoon Ride</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180812/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 17:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180812/</guid>
      <description>Almost bit off more than I could chew. My intention was to knock out an easy 30 mile ride under overcast skies. A few minutes into the ride the clouds cleared and the heat returned. I finished up with 56 miles. After yesterday&amp;rsquo;s century ride I was pretty whipped. The end of today&amp;rsquo;s ride was tough going.
 Relive &amp;lsquo;Sunday Afternoon Ride&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Century Saturday 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180811/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 11:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180811/</guid>
      <description>This is my 4th weekend century in a row. I&amp;rsquo;m getting to the point if I don&amp;rsquo;t ride 100 miles I feel lazy.
Today&amp;rsquo;s ride started at 4:57 AM. Nice to have the roads all to myself for a while. There was a summer shower in West Ashley but the rest of the ride was dry. Good day.
 Photo album
Relive &amp;lsquo;Century Saturday&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Round The Ville</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180807/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 22:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180807/</guid>
      <description>A nice unremarkable ride around my town.
 Relive &amp;lsquo;Round The Ville&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kingstree Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180804/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 23:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180804/</guid>
      <description>Rode to Kingstree SC for the second time this year. Traffic was light. Temperatures were pleasant. Wind was calm. Riding a century every weekend is becoming a habit. Not sure why.
For my post ride meal I ate eggs, grits, and toast at Waffle House. It was delicious but pretty much anything tastes good after a century ride. I was expecting Waffle House to be a little livelier it being midnight on a Saturday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Folly Beach</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180802/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 21:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180802/</guid>
      <description>Mike&amp;rsquo;s Bikes installed a new drivetrain and performed a general tune-up on my Giant Anyroad 1. I picked up Old Yeller after work and headed to Folly Beach and later over to The Charleston Battery. Nice smooth comfy ride.
 Photo album
Relive &amp;lsquo;Folly Beach&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mt Pleasant Pier</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180731/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 23:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180731/</guid>
      <description>Old Yeller is still in the shop getting a new drivetrain so I took the backup bike for a night ride to the Mt Pleasant Pier. Comfortable temperatures, nice sky, and a tailwind home. Pretty much a perfect summer evening. I was concerned about my lights dying but they hung on to the very end around 11 PM.
 Photo album
Relive &amp;lsquo;Mount Pleasant Pier night ride&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Montague</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180729a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 22:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180729a/</guid>
      <description>Old Yeller is in the shop getting a new drivetrain so I took the backup bike for a night ride. The Giant Defy 3 rode pretty well. Not as comfy as the Giant Anyroad 1 but I&amp;rsquo;m fortunate to have a decent backup.
The temperatures were pleasant. I could see lightning off in the distance for most of the ride but I avoided the rain. 20 minutes after getting home it was pouring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bike Check and Product Annoyances</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180729/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180729/</guid>
      <description>Shifting was less than stellar during yesterday&amp;rsquo;s ride. Checked the chain and it is at .75% wear. Time for a replacement.

I see some wear on the cassette as well. I may get that replaced. I will drop off the Giant Anyroad 1 at Mike&amp;rsquo;s Bikes today.

The Park Cyclone Chain Scrubber works well but the rivets that hold the clips fall out. I&amp;rsquo;ve lost one rivet. The other one falls out occasionally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charleston Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180728/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180728/</guid>
      <description>Mapped out my route Friday night and pretty much stuck to it. This is my third century ride for July 2018. It was a enjoyable ride except for Highway 402. It is the worst road surface I&amp;rsquo;ve ever ridden. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I will ride that highway again until they pave it which will probably be a very long time from now.
My favorite segments were the West Ashley Greenway, Charleston Battery, and Arthur Ravenel Jr Bridge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Breeze</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180724/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 22:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180724/</guid>
      <description>Afternoon thunderstorms cleared for a nice evening ride. I dropped by the Ashley River. Good times.
I overestimated the charge in my two rear lights. They both died about 30 minutes prior to the end of my ride. That was a little dicey. I need to make a habit when I get home to immediately remove my lights from my bike and connect them to the charger. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll do it later&amp;rdquo; doesn&amp;rsquo;t work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Moultrie Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180722/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180722/</guid>
      <description>Frequently I get on my bike without a plan. Today was one of those days.
I do like to ride through Cane Bay on Sunday to check on the progress near Black Tom Rd. So that is were I headed. They have asphalt almost to Black Tom Rd. Looking good.
I then headed towards Moncks Corner and decided to get on the Lake Moultrie dike. Once I got to Bonneau I wanted to find where I could continue on the dike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charleston Triangle</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180721/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180721/</guid>
      <description>Had a nice tailwind to Charleston and mostly head and cross winds home. Temperatures were great. The Garmin says the average was 69.9 °F. I find that a little hard to believe. It was nice but not that nice. Rode the West Ashley Greenway. I love that segment.
On the way home I stopped by the Summerville Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market to pick up a couple Cookie Chick cookies. They weren&amp;rsquo;t selling any oatmeal based cookies today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rain Avoidance Routing</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180719/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 21:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180719/</guid>
      <description>Cloudy evening with rain threatening. I was able to avoid the rain and settled for some drizzle. Mission accomplished.
Still considering a night century. Perhaps Saturday or Sunday night.
 Relive &amp;lsquo;Rain avoidance routing&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knight Rider</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180715/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 22:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180715/</guid>
      <description>Pleasant 73.5°F average temperature and low traffic. This has me thinking about riding a night century.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turkeys, bison, rabbit, heron, cranes</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180714/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180714/</guid>
      <description>The ride was filled with wildlife sightings. At the bottom of the Lake Moultrie dike I spotted a flock of turkeys. Along Highway 311 I spotted a cotton tail rabbit and a herd of bison on a farm. Along Highway 453 between Holly Hill and Harleyville I saw a wide variety of birds including heron and crane. There are sections of cypress swamps along Highway 453 providing a nice break from the industrial environment of that highway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180710/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180710/</guid>
      <description>The Garmin 520 recorded 59°F as the low temperature. That is crazy low for July. I almost needed my arm warmers. High temperature on the ride home was 86℉ which was pleasant.
I must admit waking up before 5 AM to beat the traffic is getting old. Still waiting on a road to connect to Black Tom Rd that may provide a safer and later ride.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tour de Charleston</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180707/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180707/</guid>
      <description>I was thinking of a short ride this morning since I rode a century on Wednesday but one road led to another ending with 72 miles in the books. It was a good uneventful ride. Had a head wind on the way home. Felt a little tired but not tired enough to skip a detour to the Summerville Farmer&amp;rsquo;s market for a couple of Cookie Chick cookies.
Tour de France 2018 started today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edisto Beach Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180704/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180704/</guid>
      <description>I woke up at 4 AM and was on the road by 5 AM. The rain started at mile 25 and didn&amp;rsquo;t let up much until I returned to Summerville. But hey at least I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about the heat. It was a cool ride in many ways. I love the scenery. Traffic was light for the most part. On the way home when the rain was really coming down a kind human in a pickup truck with a bicycle in the back asked if I wanted a lift.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley River</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180701/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180701/</guid>
      <description>Took a late morning ride to the Ashley River. Passed a snake on the Sawmill Branch trail. I should have stopped and snapped a picture. A road cyclist passed me on a section of the Sawmill Branch trail. I fell behind by about 20 seconds and was struggling to keep up with him while he looked like he was out for a casual Sunday spin. Oh well. Where the end of the trail empties onto a rock road, me and my 32c tires kept rolling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Moultrie Then Blinding Torrential Rain</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180628/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 22:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180628/</guid>
      <description>Trip to Lake Moultrie. Rode the dike from Pinopolis to the Hatchery. Took Highway 6 then Old Whitesville Road to 17A. Nearing Black Tom Rd the rain began. On Black Tom Rd the rain was torrential and I could not see where to turn off. After a couple of misses I found the turn. I rode through the mud for about a mile and then hit pavement for a smooth ride home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crit Races and Nextburg Loops</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180626/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 22:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180626/</guid>
      <description>The weather was pleasant for the criterium racers, not as hot as it has been the last 10 days. I watched the category 5 and 4 races.
After watching the races I felt like riding in circles so I cycled 3 Nextburg loops. Nextburg is what I&amp;rsquo;m calling Nexton Parkway to Jedburg Rd. The road names between Nexton Parkway and Jedburg Rd are Drop Off Dr and Red Bay Rd. This was my first proper ride on the All-City Big Block since installing the drop handlebars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drop Handlebars</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180625/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 22:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180625/</guid>
      <description>Replaced the Kalloy 700mm Riser handlebars with Giant Connect XR drop handlebars. These are the same handlebars that are on my Giant Anyroad 1 bicycle. I am using the Tektro RL520 lever set and have Sunlite Road foam grips for simplicity and comfort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday Evening Ride</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180624/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 22:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180624/</guid>
      <description>Started my Sunday ride around 8 PM. The sun went down around 8:30 along with the temperatures. There was a nice breeze and my legs felt alive. I ate a few bugs. I can use the protein. Traffic was a little hairy on Hwy 52 in Goose Creek but other than that traffic was mostly light being Sunday evening. The moon was at 87% illumination and on the other side of the sky was a lightning show.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low Energy</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180623/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180623/</guid>
      <description>My legs were dead this morning. Don&amp;rsquo;t know if it is the heat or the 40 mile ride Thursday night on the single speed. Hopefully tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s ride will be better. Took some different roads on this Charleston trip. Rode by the airport, Park Circle, and came back home on Dorchester Rd.
Photo album
 Relive &amp;lsquo;Low Energy&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Too hip for PLA</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180621/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 22:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180621/</guid>
      <description>After flying over the handlebars performing a crotch skid I decided the fixed gear life was not for me. I installed a White Industries ENO 16 tooth freewheel on my All-City Big Block single speed bicycle and went for a ride. Much more enjoyable with the freewheel than the fixed gear. I can always flip the wheel around to go back to fixed if I&amp;rsquo;m feeling reasonably dangerous.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heat Advisory Headwind</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180619/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180619/</guid>
      <description>Rode the bicycle to work since I dropped off my Chevy Bolt EV yesterday for scheduled maintenance. Left work a little after 3PM and cycled to Rick Hendrick Chevrolet in Charleston to pick up the Bolt. There was a heat advisory and a headwind. The Garmin recorded 100.4 °F as the high and 94.0 °F as the average. Not sure what the humidity was but it was high. I faced a headwind today which I guess is fair since I had a tailwind yesterday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rick Hendrick Chevrolet</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180618/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 19:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180618/</guid>
      <description>Dropped off my Chevy Bolt EV at Rick Hendrick Chevrolet on Savannah Hwy in Charleston for regular scheduled maintenance. Rode my bike home. Nice ride with favorable winds and traffic lights.
I will cycle to work in the morning and probably leave around 3 PM to cycle back to Rick Hendrick Chevrolet. Tomorrow is going to be a scorcher. The ride will be a bit of a challenge.
Photo album</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pimlico</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180617/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180617/</guid>
      <description>Sunday&amp;rsquo;s ride started at 6:15 AM just in time to catch a foggy misty sunrise. I came out the back of Nexton, through Cane Bay, hopped on the newly paved Black Tom Rd, crossed Hwy 17-A onto Gaillard Rd to Old Hwy 52 to Cypress Gardens Rd. In Pimlico at the end of Albert Storm Dr there is a trail leading to the Cooper River. I went mudding and stopped for a photo of the river.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>West Ashley Loop</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180616/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180616/</guid>
      <description>Saturday&amp;rsquo;s ride started off around 6:45 AM. Temperature and humidity were comfortable at the start but rose quickly.
I was baffled by the amount of traffic on Hwy 165. It is normally pretty sparse. The opposite lane was streaming with cars. I searched the web when I got home and discovered that there is a Lacrosse event June 16 &amp;amp; 17, 2018 t the Hyde Park Farm &amp;amp; Polo Club. This promotional video makes Lacrosse look pretty exciting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Moultrie Dike</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180615/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180615/</guid>
      <description>After the work week was complete I rode my Giant Anyroad 1 up to the Watermark Bar &amp;amp; Grill in Bonneau SC. From work I took Hwy 52, Jessamine Dr, a wrong turn on Powerhouse Rd, Old Black Oak Rd to the Lake Moultrie dike. The dike is a nice gravel ride which my 32c tires handle nicely. The ride to the bar was hot. Drank a couple of Yuenglings with friends, paid my tab and headed back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Bike Day</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180613/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180613/</guid>
      <description>Resist no more. Purchased an All-City Big Block from Mike&amp;rsquo;s Bikes located on Coleman Blvd in Mt Pleasant SC.
Been thinking about a fixed gear for some time. I blame it on fixed gear YouTube videos. They make it look like so much fun. This is my first fixed gear. It is like learning to ride all over again. I just keep repeating to myself while riding, no coasting, no coasting, no coasting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180612/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180612/</guid>
      <description>Gloomy overcast day. No sun but no rain either. Had a bit of a tailwind on the way home giving me a decent moving time of 47:29.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bushy Park</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180610/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180610/</guid>
      <description>On the road at 6 AM Sunday for a ride to Bushy Park. I went through Cane Bay / Del Webb so I could check up on the development near Black Tom Rd. Still no pavement in the last development. Had to ride a mile of dirt to Black Tom Rd. Good to see Black Tom Rd resurfacing progressing nicely. I&amp;rsquo;d say they are about 70% complete. Now if they could work on Bushy Park Rd that would be ace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unseated</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180609/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180609/</guid>
      <description>Saturday&amp;rsquo;s ride started off good enough at 6 AM. Roads were wet but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t raining until I got on Meeting St in North Charleston. It rained pretty heavy for a mile or two then eased up. 22 miles in my rear wheel unseated while I was going over the railroad tracks on Meeting St near Magnolia Cemetery. The bump also knocked my seat out of place. Luckily I stayed upright.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180607/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180607/</guid>
      <description>Good ride into work in under 50 minutes moving time. Always pleased with sub 50 minute rides. The ride home had a rain delay. Planned to leave work at 4 PM but a shower popped up and rained pretty hard. Worked for another hour. The road was steaming for the first few miles and all dry the rest of the way home. After showering I cycled over to Taco Bell for some black bean burritos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180605/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180605/</guid>
      <description>Was treated to a beautiful sunrise on the way to work. The ride home was nice too with temperatures in mid 80s ℉ and relatively low humidity.
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summerville Farmers&#39; Market and Ashley River</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180602/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180602/</guid>
      <description>Grabbed a Peanut Butter Toffee Chip cookie and a Cranberry White Oatmeal Chocolate cookie from the Cookie Chick stand at the Summerville Farmers&amp;rsquo; Market. Ate one on the spot and saved the other for after lunch. On the way to the river I got stung on my left ankle by what I assume was a bee. No big deal. After stopping for a photo at the river I headed down Ladson Rd, College Park Rd and Hwy 17-A back home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180601/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180601/</guid>
      <description>Long day. Woke up at 4:00 AM and was on the road by 5:00 AM. Left the office around 5:20 PM.
My bike has a clicking squeaky noise. I&amp;rsquo;m guessing it is from the saddle. Took the saddle off and removed a good bit of dirt. Hopefully that was cause.
Temperatures are on the way up. It was approaching 90 ℉. May 2018 was the wettest month ever in Charleston SC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wet Wednesday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180530/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180530/</guid>
      <description>Rain and more rain. As of this writing this is second wettest May of all time for Charleston SC. Bring on a dry hot June.
I brought my Nvidia Shield to work for a coworker to borrow. I packed it in my Topeak Backloader bicycle bag and it stayed dry. Yay! I was able to cycle to lunch without getting rained. Yay again! The ride home was a soaker but at least the winds were calm and the temperature was a comfortable 69.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subtropical Slider</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180528/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180528/</guid>
      <description>Cycling too fast for conditions. I went for a ride to Ravenel SC on Memorial Day 2018. The ride didn&amp;rsquo;t start out too great. The roads were wet as we were getting rain bands from subtropical storm Alberto. Turning off of Jedburg Rd we took a slide. I had just put on new bar tape the day before. The tape only lasted about 9 miles. LOLZ. The bike is fine. I was fine and continued on with the ride without further incident.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memorial Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180526/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180526/</guid>
      <description>Woke up around 3 AM and could not go back to sleep. I knew I wanted to ride a century today and my excitement cost me some sleep. Oh well. I was on the road by 5 AM which was a good thing. The summer is coming on strong. The earlier in the day I ride the better. The entire ride was on 4 lane highways. The traffic was light from home to Kinstree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180524/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180524/</guid>
      <description>Tried a new route on the morning commute. I got off of Hwy 17-A at Gaillard Rd over to Old Hwy 52. Nice change of scenery. It was not quite a mile longer.
The afternoon commute got off to a slow start. Before I could work up a sweat I was stopped by not one but two trains. The first freight train was long and slow. Towards the end with just a dozen cars left to pass the crossing a second freight train coming from the opposite direction appeared.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180522/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180522/</guid>
      <description>Nice rides to work and back. No uptight automobile drivers. Damp tarmac and a little drizzle on the way home. No worries.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charleston Battery</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180520/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180520/</guid>
      <description>Enjoyed a pleasant Sunday ride to the Charleston Battery. Not much wind, temperatures were around 70℉ and automobile traffic was light.
Relive &amp;lsquo;Charleston Battery&amp;rsquo; 
 Photo album</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Savannah</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180519/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180519/</guid>
      <description>It was raining this morning with a forecast of showers all day so I drove the Chevrolet Bolt EV down to Savannah GA. I parked the car at a convenience store and plugged in to their charger. I hopped on my bike to explore Savannah. Riding around the city was pretty nice but it got old after a while having to stop every block. I left the city and headed down to the Savannah National Wildlife Refuge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Bike to Work Day</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180518/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180518/</guid>
      <description>Today was National Bike to Work Day. I usually bike to work on Tuesday and Thursday but I switched this week to Wednesday and Friday to align with BTWD. We had on and off again rain all day. I managed to escape all but a few drops here and there. Pretty nice rides. Below is a snippet of my ride home. I&amp;rsquo;m not proud of this part of my ride but I just don&amp;rsquo;t feel like stopping in traffic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wednesday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180516/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180516/</guid>
      <description>Picked up Old Yeller from Mike&amp;rsquo;s Bikes yesterday. It has a new rear derailleur, chain, rear tire, and cassette. The ride to work was super smooth. Really glad to have the Giant Anyroad 1 back. It is so much nicer than my backup bike, Giant Defy 3. I can&amp;rsquo;t recall an average MPH of 20 so I think this was a personal best. There is something motivational about a new drivetrain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bushy Park</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180513/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180513/</guid>
      <description>Cycled through Cane Bay on my way to Bushy Park. Had to walk for a couple of hundred yards over a sandy road in the neighborhood under construction. Looking forward to when there is a paved road to either Black Tom Rd or 17-A. The rest of the ride was pleasant. Not as hot as yesterday and traffic was light.
 Photo album</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mmmm Cookies</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180512/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180512/</guid>
      <description>Started my morning ride off with cookies from the Cookie Chick at the Summerville Farmers Market. Cookie Chick bakes the best cookies. I ate an oatmeal rum cookie and saved a toasted almond cookie for after lunch. Good stuff. My main bike is still at the LBS so I rode the backup bike. Fortunate to have a backup bike. My primary bike seems to spend allot of time at the LBS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday Commute, Post Chipotle Ride and Topeak Chain Tool</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180510/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 19:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180510/</guid>
      <description>Thursday&amp;rsquo;s commute was uneventful. I rode to Chipotle for dinner and afterwards rode up Hwy 78. I was going to take N Maple St to the Nexton Parkway but couldn&amp;rsquo;t find N Maple St. Looked at Google Maps when I got home and realized I should have traveled a few more blocks. I headed back up 17-A and took Holiday Dr to Nexton Parkway instead. Even though I had been on Nexton Parkway many times this was the first time with automobile traffic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180508/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180508/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday&amp;rsquo;s commute was uneventful. I snapped a photo of The Corner Cafe Bakery in Moncks Corner SC. It recently closed. A Starbucks recently opened and I assume that might have played into The Corner&amp;rsquo;s decision to close. I had a rare tailwind on the way home which enabled me to break my 50 minute barrier again. Nice!
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snapped Rear Derailleur Hanger</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180506b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 19:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180506b/</guid>
      <description>A microfiber cloth flew out of my top tube bag right into my rear derailleur causing the hanger to snap. I was pulling my phone out of the bag at the time. I usually have the microfiber cloth stored in a sandwich bag but not today. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t injured. My plan was to use my chain tool to remove a section of the chain so I could ride back home. Unfortunately I have lost the pin for the chain tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garmin Insights</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180506a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 07:17:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180506a/</guid>
      <description>The Garmin Connect mobile app for Android has a feature called Insights. You can compare your fitness stats to others. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how many users there are and if there was an opt-in option for this. Some folks recommend not comparing yourself to others which is good advice. Just do your own thing and stay moving. Seeing how you stack up to others is kind of interesting and hard to resist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Folly Beach</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180505/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180505/</guid>
      <description>Another beautiful day in the lowcountry. Blue sky, low humidity and temperatures topping off in the 80&amp;rsquo;s ℉. I cycled to Folly Beach. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be happier with the way my Giant Anyroad 1 bicycle performed after being serviced yesterday at my LBS. Mike&amp;rsquo;s Bikes on Coleman Blvd Mt Pleasant replaced my rear bearing balls and cups. The drive train was silky smooth and quiet. Super nice ride.
 Photo album</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintenance Friday and Why I Don&#39;t Use Clipless Pedals</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180504/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180504/</guid>
      <description>Heard noise from my rear hub on my Thursday commute. Took the Giant Anyroad 1 into Mike&amp;rsquo;s Bikes. They replaced the bearing balls and cups. I had introduced water and dirt into the bearings when I washed my bike with a pressure washer. I thought I was being gentle with the washer. Obviously not gentle enough. Lesson learned. Being an apartment dweller I don&amp;rsquo;t have access to a water hose. That is why I was going to the car wash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180503/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180503/</guid>
      <description>Wheee - just having fun! Gorgeous weather continues. I didn&amp;rsquo;t like the way my rear hub was sounding so I dropped off my Giant Anyroad 1 bike at Mike&amp;rsquo;s Bikes in Mt Pleasant. Asked them to check all the bearings. Hopeful it will be a one day turn around so I can have it for the weekend. If not I&amp;rsquo;ll be riding my Giant Defy 3 and wishing I was on my Anyroad 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180501/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180501/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday&amp;rsquo;s commute had a big temperature swing. According to my Garmin 520 bicycle computer the minimum temperature was 39℉ and the maximum temperature was 82℉. That is a 43℉ swing.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley River</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180429/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180429/</guid>
      <description>Rode to the Ashley River. Temperature was about 10 degrees cooler than yesterday and a little more wind. Still had a clear blue sky. Pretty nice.
 Photo album</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Moultrie Loop</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180428/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180428/</guid>
      <description>Absolutely a gorgeous day for a long ride. Started out in the low 50&amp;rsquo;s ℉ and ended in the mid 70&amp;rsquo;s ℉. There wasn&amp;rsquo;t a cloud in the sky and the winds were light. Perfect! I chose to loop around Lake Moultrie.
 Photo album</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180426/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180426/</guid>
      <description>My Thursday commute was dry, comfortable, and uneventful. I got up at 5 AM and was on the road by 5:30 AM. I think I will stick with this schedule. I&amp;rsquo;d like to sleep an hour later but it is not worth the increased traffic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180424/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180424/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday commute started out wet with mist and a couple of showers. The ride home was dry, unlike my shoes, and partly cloudy. One thing is for sure the traffic is far better at 5:30 AM than at 6:30 AM. The traffic is lighter and a little less frantic. Absolutely worth getting up at 5 AM for.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Moultrie</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180422/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180422/</guid>
      <description>Sunday ride to the lovely Lake Moultrie. So grateful to have this lake within riding distance from my apartment. The dike surface is gravel and dirt. As long as it hasn&amp;rsquo;t rained it is easy to navigate. I must say my Giant Anyroad 1 with 32c tires handles the terrain comfortably. Got up on the dike at the end of W Dike Rd in Pinopolis SC and exited at the Hatchery Boat Ramp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charleston Triangle</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180421/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180421/</guid>
      <description>Saturday ride to Charleston Battery and over to West Ashley Greenway. I love the West Ashley Greenway. It is a 8.25 hike and bike trail. Mostly paved with a few gravel sections. Took the longer route home up Highway 165. The route has a triangle shape. The average temperature was 64℉ with partly cloudy skies. Pretty much perfect weather for a long weekend ride.
 Photo album</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Best on AM Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180419/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 19:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180419/</guid>
      <description>Had a rare tailwind this morning and it helped me achieve my personal best moving time of 46:59. I also had a little help from a slow moving 18 wheeler.
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contemplating the Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180418/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180418/</guid>
      <description>Contemplating my twice-a-week bicycle commute. It is 16.2 miles between Moncks Corner and Summerville. Most of the ride is on Hwy 17-A which is a busy 4 lane highway. The section from my apartment in Summerville to Cypress Gardens Rd is the busiest section. Cypress Gardens Rd intersection to Moncks Corner is lower traffic and a pleasant ride.
Pros  4 hours of exercise a week Green Commute Enjoyable Accomplishing 2 things a once (commute and exercise)  Cons  Dangerous Abuse from drivers (yelling, honking, revving, close drive by)  The benefits are many but sometimes feel that I am being irresponsible to my family and to my employer by risking my life on my bike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laps in the wind</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180415/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180415/</guid>
      <description>Recovering from an FBI event Thursday night. Ate some Golden Flake peanuts that sat in my car seat all afternoon soaking up the sun and transforming into some evil shite. This ride was 3 laps on along the I-26 frontage roads, Drop Off Dr and Red Bay Rd. Windy AF. Weak.
At the start of this ride the Garmin Edge 520 powered off for some unknown reason. That is the second Strava embed below with only 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday evening ride in lieu of a Friday commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180412/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180412/</guid>
      <description>Meeting some friends after work Friday so instead of a Friday commute I rode Thursday evening. This is my first ride with my Topeak Toploader. I like it. Nice to have my phone, gels, and batteries easily accessible. Much better than reaching around my back to my jersey pockets. The only time my knees touched the bag was when I got sloppy out of the saddle.
 Photo album</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Wednesday April 11, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180411/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180411/</guid>
      <description>Broke my cheap clear sunglasses before I got out the door. On the ride to work I got honked at once and yelled at once. A passenger in a truck yelled &amp;ldquo;Get on the sidewalk!&amp;rdquo;. Yeah, that ain&amp;rsquo;t happening. 16 miles on a sidewalk would not be fun.
We&amp;rsquo;ve got new pavement on Main St in Moncks Corner SC. So nice. The road was in really bad shape. Love cycling on new tarmac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Larry&#39;s Giant Subs</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180410/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 19:34:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180410/</guid>
      <description>Rode across town to Larry&amp;rsquo;s Giant Subs on Old Trolley Rd Summerville SC. Dropped my cheap sunglasses on the road scratching them pretty good. Slammed a turkey sub. Ran into a childhood friend and his son. Good to catch up with him.
I&amp;rsquo;m not a real fan of eating and immediately riding. It was a short ride of 6 miles so wasn&amp;rsquo;t too bad but I prefer the restaurants on my side of town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trial a longer, potentially safer route to work</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180408/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180408/</guid>
      <description>I commute twice a week from Summerville to Moncks Corner SC via Hwy 17-A which is a busy 4 lane highway. The video was taken during my trial to stay off highways as much as possible. I came out the back of Nexton, through Cane Bay, through Del Webb, onto Black Tom Rd, and finally back onto Hwy 17-A. This route is about 20 miles vs my normal route of 16 miles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overnight bicycle tour Santee SC</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180331/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180331/</guid>
      <description>Cycled to Santee SC Saturday and spent the night at the Holiday Inn. Took Hwy 6 to Santee SC and Hwy 176 on the way home. Hwy 176 is one of my least favorite roads but it is the shortest route. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t too busy on Easter Sunday.
  Photo album</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overnight bicycle tour Georgetown SC</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180324/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180324/</guid>
      <description>Cycled to Georgetown SC Saturday and spent the night at the Hampton Inn. Saturday was chilly with a headwind. The sun peaked out a few times. Sunday morning it was raining until about checkout time 11 AM. I got on the road and had a nice tailwind home. Not allot a sun but a good ride.
  Photo album</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>