<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on PLA Cycling Log</title>
    <link>https://pla.bike/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on PLA Cycling Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 19:34:28 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pla.bike/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Larry&#39;s Giant Subs</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180410/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 19:34:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180410/</guid>
      <description>Rode across town to Larry&amp;rsquo;s Giant Subs on Old Trolley Rd Summerville SC. Dropped my cheap sunglasses on the road scratching them pretty good. Slammed a turkey sub. Ran into a childhood friend and his son. Good to catch up with him.
I&amp;rsquo;m not a real fan of eating and immediately riding. It was a short ride of 6 miles so wasn&amp;rsquo;t too bad but I prefer the restaurants on my side of town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trial a longer, potentially safer route to work</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180408/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180408/</guid>
      <description>I commute twice a week from Summerville to Moncks Corner SC via Hwy 17-A which is a busy 4 lane highway. The video was taken during my trial to stay off highways as much as possible. I came out the back of Nexton, through Cane Bay, through Del Webb, onto Black Tom Rd, and finally back onto Hwy 17-A. This route is about 20 miles vs my normal route of 16 miles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overnight bicycle tour Georgetown SC</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180324/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180324/</guid>
      <description>Cycled to Georgetown SC Saturday and spent the night at the Hampton Inn. Saturday was chilly with a headwind. The sun peaked out a few times. Sunday morning it was raining until about checkout time 11 AM. I got on the road and had a nice tailwind home. Not allot a sun but a good ride.
  Photo album</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>