<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PLA Cycling Log</title>
    <link>https://pla.bike/</link>
    <description>Recent content on PLA Cycling Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 18:30:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pla.bike/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday October 29, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20201029/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20201029/</guid>
      <description>Remnants of hurricane Zeta provided a kind tailwind to work and soggy headwind on the way home.
Meanwhile I am teed off at my body. My right knee and hip ain&amp;rsquo;t right. From what I gather through YouTube is I may have an IT band issue probably brought on by my two falls on 4 October and 11 October.
Got goals to complete. No time to be taking time off the bike to heal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Folly Beach Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20201024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 16:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20201024/</guid>
      <description>One of the many great things about sandals is being able to wade in the ocean, river or lake. The cool ocean water felt great.
Gorgeous weather today. Partly cloudy with temperatures peaking in the 80s℉.
The outer back of my right knee starting hurting on the way home. Hopefully a one-off. Likely will take tomorrow off and monitor.
Have I mentioned lately that I like yellow? Roadside daisies have been filling me with joy the last two weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday October 22, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20201022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20201022/</guid>
      <description>Wet ride to work but at least it was warm. Good commute.
Ride on. ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday October 20, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20201020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20201020/</guid>
      <description>Another day, another dollar. Good commute.
Ride on. ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Yeller Rides Again Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20201018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 16:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20201018/</guid>
      <description>Zach at The Bicycle Shoppe finished a herculean repair job on Old Yeller yesterday. So I had to go for a ride. Felt so good to be back on Old Yeller especially with a new drivetrain. Rode like a dream.
Weather was fantastic. Sunny 70&amp;rsquo;s ℉ for most of the ride.
Pretty good weekend with back to back century rides. Not sure I&amp;rsquo;ve done that before. Glad to know it is doable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Loop Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20201017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 15:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20201017/</guid>
      <description>Turning around and going home crossed my mind a couple of times when the cool headwind was like a brick wall. Kept pedaling and it paid off. The second half of the ride the winds were favorable.
Still riding the backup bike but got a call from the bicycle mechanic while I was on Cane Gully Rd that Old Yeller was ready for pickup. There is still work to do but it is rideable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday October 15, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20201015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20201015/</guid>
      <description>Hip is healing slowly but surely. ☺
Ride on. ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday October 13, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20201013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20201013/</guid>
      <description>Pretty sweet this weather is. Good commute.
Ride on. ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley River</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20201011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20201011/</guid>
      <description>Fell on my right hip again while turning onto the wet slimy Herbert H Jessen Public Boat Landing boardwalk. So mad at myself. I know how slippery boardwalks can be. After yesterday&amp;rsquo;s ride I felt pretty good and was on the mend. Then I go pull this stunt. 2020 just keeps on giving.
Ride on. ☮

 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mepkin Abbey Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20201010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 15:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20201010/</guid>
      <description>Always a pleasure to visit Mepkin Abbey. Moss covered oak trees, green grass and a river. What&amp;rsquo;s not to like?
Last night I was going to replace parts on Old Yeller that were damaged last week. Unfortunately one of the screws for the derailleur hanger was stripped. Not having a drill or spare screws the project came to a screeching halt. After this ride on my backup bike I stopped into The Bicycle Shoppe behind my apartment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chill, spill and a whole lotta luck Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20201004/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 15:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20201004/</guid>
      <description>Took a spill at mile 57. While riding through the Riverfront Park I went from concrete to gravel and tried to get back on the concrete and fell over. The lip of the concrete was higher than I thought and acted like a rail. Fell over onto the concrete on my right side. Injured my hip, elbow and ribs. I could still ride pain free but walking was a different story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday October 1, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20201001/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20201001/</guid>
      <description>Tried an alternate route on the way home. One that would minimize the time on Hwy 17-A. I took Bonnoitt St, Whitesville Rd, and Old Whitesville Rd. All 3 roads have pretty rough tarmac and are 2 lane. I will stick with Hwy 17-A. At least it is 4 lanes and has good tarmac.
The segment I really want to replace is Black Tom Rd. A 2 lane 55 mph race track filled with impatient drivers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Wednesday September 30, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200930/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200930/</guid>
      <description>This is a rarity. Had headwinds both ways. In the morning the wind was blowing from the south and on the way home it was a northerly wind. Sweet.
Ride on. ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ridgeville</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200927/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 17:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200927/</guid>
      <description>The streams flowing through Ridgeville were swollen from the recent rains. The ride highlight was spotting a good looking red headed woodpecker.
Pretty pleasant ride with the exception of some irate male in an automobile screaming at the top of his lungs. I was descending the Nexton Parkway I-26 4-lane overpass in the far right lane and he was turning left onto the interstate highway. We were the only two folks on the entire road.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bald Eagle Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200926/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200926/</guid>
      <description>Bizarre when your route is a loop and you have a headwind the entire ride. Expected the sun to come out sooner. So glad to see it when it finally did.
The highlight of the ride was getting a leadout by a bald eagle on Cane Gully Rd. Such a magnificent bird. Saw a big owl early in the ride. Also impressive. The most entertaining animal goes to the goat. Saw a couple of pastures with goats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Friday September 25, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200925/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200925/</guid>
      <description>Had a family dinner in Mt Pleasant Thursday so I biked to work on Friday this week. The remnants of tropical storm Beta dumped some heavy rain. I managed to miss most of it.
Ride on. ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday September 22, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200922/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200922/</guid>
      <description>Cool start to the week. 48℉ according to the Wahoo Elemnt Bolt bicycle computer. Not looking forward to what is coming. Good commute.
Ride on. ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Botany Bay Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200920/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200920/</guid>
      <description>Super high tide consumed the Botany Bay beach. One of the visitors on the way back said the water was thigh deep on the walk to the beach. Next time I will schedule my trip to Botany Bay during a low tide. Took a few photos and decided to go to Edisto beach. There was water on Palmetto Blvd with police blocking off the flooded section. Took a quick stroll on the beach and headed back home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Friday September 18, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200918/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200918/</guid>
      <description>Another week is in the books. Good commute.
Ride on. ☮
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday September 15, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200915/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200915/</guid>
      <description>Nice tailwind. 20 mph average. Good commute.
Ride on. ☮
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seewee Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200912/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200912/</guid>
      <description>Ride turned out easier than I anticipated. 5 hours of sleep after a pretty active week made me think today was going to be a hard one. Thankfully it wasn&amp;rsquo;t.
First time on Doar Rd in Awendaw. Wanted to get to the Atlantic Intracoastal Waterway. Forest Service Rd 260-B was my best bet. Took off down the gravel road and was saddened to see it end before getting to the waterway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Friday September 11, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200911/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200911/</guid>
      <description>After yesterday&amp;rsquo;s puncturefest I decided to replace the tires and tubes on the single speed. The Wabi Classic is now sporting Continental Gatorskins 700x28c tires. Also, started carrying the Zefal HPX-3 frame pump ditching the mini pump. Storing the Zefal between the bag and top tube.
The new tires perform well. The former tires were 32c. The 28c tires might be a littler squirrelier.
Morning ride was rather foggy and the evening ride was pretty moist as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday September 10, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200910/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 07:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200910/</guid>
      <description>My first did not finish (DNF) commute. A tack was the culprit. Before installing the new tube I felt around the tire twice and did not find anything. Needless to say the new tube punctured after about a mile. Searched for some water to find the hole in the tube. Stepped in ankle deep mud getting to the water. Found the hole in the tube and then was able to find the tack in the tire, patched the new tube.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday September 9, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200909/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200909/</guid>
      <description>Paid the price on the way to work fighting a stiff headwind. Gratuitously reimbursed on the way home with a fun tailwind.
Good commute. ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flower Power Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200907/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 17:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200907/</guid>
      <description>Whew. This century ride was far less exhausting than Friday&amp;rsquo;s. Main goal was to not repeat Friday&amp;rsquo;s ride. Kept telling myself to slow down. Just take what the road is giving me. So when the headwind stiffened I dropped to a lower gear and maintained my cadence. Felt much better at the end of the ride.
The wildflowers growing on the side of the road were nice. Lots of yellow, blue, and dark red flowers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edisto Beach Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200904/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200904/</guid>
      <description>Burned all my matches about 30 miles in and paid for it dearly. Tried a change to my normal route to Edisto Beach. Took Old Jacksonboro Rd off of Hwy 165. This segment runs parallel with Hwy 17 above it. Everything was fine until Old Jacksonboro Rd crossed New Rd. At that point it turned from pavement to a deep soft sand road. My 32c tires sunk in the sand like a hot knife in butter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Wednesday September 2, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200902/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200902/</guid>
      <description>Our CEO is giving us Friday off so I decided to move my Thursday commute up a day. The plan is to rest Thursday for a century ride Friday.
Good commute. ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday September 1, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200901/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200901/</guid>
      <description>The march continues on. Will this be a September to remember or one that we&amp;rsquo;ll try to forget?
Good commute. ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charleston Triangle Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200830/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200830/</guid>
      <description>Couldn&amp;rsquo;t decide on today&amp;rsquo;s route. I just headed out the door and made it up as I went. Never felt comfortable with my position and pace but knocked it out. Weather was nice with a little bit of wind.
Ride on. ☮






 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday August 27, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200827/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200827/</guid>
      <description>Enjoying the Wabi Classic single speed as my commuter.
Good commute. ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday August 25, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200825/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200825/</guid>
      <description>Started the day with a nice sunrise. Ended the day with a rainbow. Can&amp;rsquo;t beat that.
Good commute. ☮



  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Jolly Folly Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200823/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 23:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200823/</guid>
      <description>Rained a good portion of the day. By the afternoon I was sad that the weekend was coming to a close. Thinking I&amp;rsquo;ve never completed consecutive century rides I should try that tonight. Hopped on my bicycle and rode to the beach.
Passed by a yellow Volkswagen beetle broken down on the side of the road. Had to turn around and get a photo with Old Yeller.
Opening CLIF bar packages is frustrating especially when my hands are sweaty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Armadillo Dance Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200822/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200822/</guid>
      <description>Passed a 100 dead Armadillos on the road in the last few years. This morning I had my first live encounter. In Cross SC on Hwy 6 while still dark I thought I was riding up on a possum. It turned out to be an armadillo. We startle each other. I swerved and it danced. Heard its claws tapping on the pavement while it decided like a squirrel on which way to go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday August 20, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200820/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200820/</guid>
      <description>Felt energetic on the way to work. Not so much on the way home.
New iSSi Thump pedals feel good. Don&amp;rsquo;t quite match the color of my frame. Oh well.
Good commute.
Ride on. ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday August 18, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200818/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200818/</guid>
      <description>A block down the road and the skies opened up on the way to work. On the way home the rain started when I hit Cane Bay. Pretty hard at times. I had flash backs to my 2019 Good Friday ride to Myrtle Beach.
Good commute.
Ride on. ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awendaw Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200816/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200816/</guid>
      <description>On the road by 3:40 AM. Heading east on Hwy 402 and Steed Creek roads I could see lightning from an offshore thunderstorm. The stars were bright overhead along with a waning crescent moon. So happy I screamed &amp;ldquo;The universe is mine!&amp;quot;.
After sunrise the clouds moved in and the temperature never rose above 75℉. In hindsight I didn&amp;rsquo;t need to wake up so early.
2020 is more than half over but I finally decided on 4 goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cookie Ride</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200815/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 08:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200815/</guid>
      <description>The Cookie Chick SC was at the Ladson Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market 1200 Discovery Rd, Ladson SC. I hopped on the Wabi Classic single speed and picked up a couple of delicious cookies. Afterwards decided to drop by the Summerville Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market to see what that looks like now since reopening after COVID-19. Everyone was wearing a mask and keeping their distance.
Ride on. ☮





 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Wednesday August 12, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200812/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200812/</guid>
      <description>Working late tonight and will be too brain dead to ride my bicycle tomorrow. I rode today instead. Had a wet and cool ride home. Nice change of pace.
Good commute.
Ride on. ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday August 11, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200811/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200811/</guid>
      <description>A steel single speed and a little tail wind is cycling nirvana.
Fun commute.
Ride on. ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Loop Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200809/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200809/</guid>
      <description>Watched Josh Ibbett&amp;rsquo;s bike check for GBDuro last night. One of his snacks are M&amp;amp;M&amp;rsquo;s. I picked up a small bag at Mac Daddy&amp;rsquo;s in Cross SC. Josh won GBDuro 2020 and I finished my ride so M&amp;amp;M&amp;rsquo;s are a go!
Moved a turtle off Cane Gulley Rd. Has been months since the last time I&amp;rsquo;ve done that. During nesting season I was rescuing turtles every ride. Check out this turtle&amp;rsquo;s stare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday August 6, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200806/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200806/</guid>
      <description>Good bit of rain this week. I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to skirt around all of it.
Took Cane Bay Blvd all the way to Black Tom Rd on both commutes today. The traffic was light and the ground was saturated so I skip the dirt short-cut.
Good commute.
Ride on. ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday August 4, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200804/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200804/</guid>
      <description>Didn&amp;rsquo;t even take a photo on Tuesday. Shame on me. Good commute.
Ride on. ☮
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>West Ashley Greenway Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200801/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200801/</guid>
      <description>Haven&amp;rsquo;t been to Charleston on my bicycle since the rona took off. Good to ride on the West Ashley Greenway again, even during predawn.
Slept a little over 4 hours last night. Woke up tired and never found my mojo but enjoyed riding through Charleston.
Ride on. ☮






 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday July 30, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200730/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200730/</guid>
      <description>Having a bit of unstable weather in the lowcountry with some stronger winds. For that reason I decided to ride Old Yeller instead of my single speed.
Black Tom Rd is a little busier now with the Cane Bay Blvd connection. Still better than the Carnes Crossroads route.
Ride on. ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday July 28, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200728/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200728/</guid>
      <description>There is one Cane Bay road that exits onto Black Tom Rd. Hoping there will be another one that is closer to Hwy 17-a than Hwy 176. The less time I spending on Black Tom Rd the better.
Good commute.
Ride on. ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>McClellanville Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200726/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200726/</guid>
      <description>Rode to my favorite small town, McClellanville. Out the door at 3:30 AM. Very little wind and pleasant temperatures until the last 1.5 hours made for a pleasant ride.
Felt pretty good after this ride. Wish I could figure out why I&amp;rsquo;m whipped after some century rides. I don&amp;rsquo;t really do anything different but the level of exhaustion varies widely. 🤔
Ride on. ☮





 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday July 23, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200723/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200723/</guid>
      <description>Installed Issi bright yellow composite pedals Wednesday night so I rode Old Yeller to work instead of the single speed. Pedals feel and look good.
Ride on. ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday July 21, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200721/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200721/</guid>
      <description>Comfortable temperatures on the way home. Afternoon rain shower cooled things down to an acceptable level. Good commute.
Ride on. ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Santee Dam Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200718/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200718/</guid>
      <description>Out the door before 4 AM. Saw a couple of deer in Nexton near the same location as last week.
I rode to the Santee Dam. Makes me sad that I can&amp;rsquo;t ride across the dam, legally. It is such a good route to get the Manning. Google Maps navigation still recommends that route. I submitted a flag about it being illegal. The submission probably lands in a bit bucket.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday July 16, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200716/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200716/</guid>
      <description>Mid July already. Bummer.
Last night I received a frame commemorating my double century ride from my brother. His better half created the drawing in the middle. Super nice. 💙
Good commuting this week. 👍
Ride on. ☮


  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday July 14, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200714/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200714/</guid>
      <description>Didn&amp;rsquo;t get much sleep due to alarms at work. Still managed to get up early enough to bike to work. Good commute.
Ride on. ☮


  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ridgeville Loop</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200712/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200712/</guid>
      <description>Streak of 10 weeks with at least one century ride comes to an end. Took a few days off to heal my left knee. I think I tweaked it when I hit a pot hole a week ago. Guessing that was the reason for the pain. My position on the bike hasn&amp;rsquo;t changed since my bike fit November 2018. Knee feels okay today. Fingers crossed.
This morning started out foggy but the fog evaporated quickly as the sun rose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Friday July 10, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200710/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200710/</guid>
      <description>Woke up at 4 AM and couldn&amp;rsquo;t go back to sleep so I hopped on my bike. On the Lake Moultrie dike I watched the sunrise. Sweet.
Instead of storing clothes at work I carried them in my back loader. The back loader isn&amp;rsquo;t quite big enough for my clothes, towels and my repair kit. The repair kit fell out the back of the bag on the way to work. Luckily I heard it hit the road and repacked it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Wheel Day July 7, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200707/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 21:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200707/</guid>
      <description>MASON x HUNT 4 Season Disc alloy wheelset installed on Old Yeller.
Ordered this wheelset after watching an interview with a couple HUNT employees on the Path Less Pedaled YouTube channel. The wheels are manufactured in Taiwan, shipped to the HUNT UK headquarters for QA and finally shipped to the customer.
The installation went pretty well for a noob mechanic. Only regret is I didn&amp;rsquo;t have new tires. Took Old Yeller out for a spin and nothing fell off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edisto Sunrise Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200705/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200705/</guid>
      <description>Goosebumps on my way to the beach. The sun was rising on my left, a full moon was setting on my right, I was surrounded by water, and the smell of pluff mud was permeating the air. Sensory overload.
To beat the heat was on the road at 3:30 AM. Wanted to be on the beach for sunrise but was a few minutes late. The segment from the Intracoastal Waterway to the beach takes much longer than you&amp;rsquo;d think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awendaw Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200703/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200703/</guid>
      <description>Out the door before 4 AM. While still in Nexton had my first encounter with wildlife. Six deer foraging in someone&amp;rsquo;s yard were spooked by my bike and crossed the road in front of me. Neat to hear 12 hooves clacking on the asphalt.
Nearly a full moon with a warm orange tint. As the ride progressed the fog lowered which signifies no wind. Yay! It was a moist ride.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Wednesday July 1, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200701/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200701/</guid>
      <description>June came and went quickly. Logged 875 miles. Time needs to slow down and let us enjoy the summer if that is possible during a pandemic.
Good commutes this week. Looking forward to a long ride Friday to kick off the subdued Independence Day weekend.
To help get me in the mood I added fireworks photo from the Ravenel Bridge opening celebration back on July 14, 2005.
Ride on. ☮</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Monday June 29, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200629/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200629/</guid>
      <description>Sorry heat haters. I love riding in the 80&amp;rsquo;s℉. 85℉ for me is a sweet spot. Just keep pedaling and it feels great.
This is a holiday week so I am commuting Monday and Wednesday instead of Tuesday and Thursday. Going to attempt a couple of century rides this Independence Day weekend. One Friday and one Sunday. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how that goes.
Will ride rural again to lessen my chances of catching Covid-19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunrise Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200627/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200627/</guid>
      <description>Didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like riding this week after my 200 mile ride Sunday. Started getting the itch to ride last night. Woke up at 3 AM to avoid the heat of the day.
Hoped to see a spectacular sunrise this morning with a Saharan dust plume reaching the coast. Sunrise was nice but not spectacular.
Did see a fox this morning leaving Nexton and a deer a few minutes after the sunrise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Double Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200621/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 21:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200621/</guid>
      <description>Riding 200 miles is something that intrigued me and started to haunt me after my 160 mile Georgetown ride. What&amp;rsquo;s 40 more miles, right? A lot. I&amp;rsquo;m not getting any younger so I knocked this goal out while I still can.
Scheduling wasn&amp;rsquo;t wise on my part as it was dangerously hot. Bike computer read 104℉ a couple of times.
The first century went pretty well and was enjoyable. The second century, not so much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday June 18, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200618/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200618/</guid>
      <description>Nothing blue about a blue sky. Hopefully we are done with cool, gloomy, and damp weather. Although we may have to deal with a Saharan dust plume.
Ride on. ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday June 16, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200616/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200616/</guid>
      <description>This is not the South Carolina I signed up for. The weather has been gloomy, windy, and chilly for days. This morning&amp;rsquo;s ride was a wet one. Misting in Summerville and 57℉ according to the bicycle computer. I wore a jacket to and from work. This is June, right?
On the plus side the wind in my face on my way to work didn&amp;rsquo;t shift and was at my back on the way home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Santee Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200613/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200613/</guid>
      <description>The morning air was cool and dry for a day in June. Ride started with 3 turkeys and 2 deer showing their faces near Ridgeville. From Ridgeville I traveled through Harleville, Santee, Eutawville, Eutaw Springs, Cross and back home.
Good bit of wind. Sometimes favorable but mostly not.
Crossed paths and momentarily rode with a couple of cyclist from Harleyville. They were must faster than me. I was expecting to find out who they were via Strava Flyby but they must not be on Strava or if they are they don&amp;rsquo;t post publicly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday June 11, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200611/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200611/</guid>
      <description>Little bit of rain on the ride home. When it is warm, rain is not a problem and sometimes welcomed. Good commute.
Weekend here we come.
Ride on. ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday June 9, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200609/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200609/</guid>
      <description>Nice having two totally different bikes to alternate. Wabi Classic is steel, stiff and light. Giant Anyroad is comfortable and heavier. Switching back and forth makes you appreciate the other one&amp;rsquo;s qualities.
Good commute with near perfect riding weather, temperatures in the 70&amp;rsquo;s℉. Nice.
Ride on. ☮


  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Georgetown Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200607/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200607/</guid>
      <description>Rode to the city where I spent many weekends and holidays as a youth. My mother&amp;rsquo;s side of the family is from Georgetown. Everyone has died or moved away but the city is still near and dear to my heart. Good times.
Heading out of Georgetown I took South Island Rd all the way until it ends at the Yawkey Wildlife Center ferry. It added a couple of miles but it was well worth it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday June 4, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200604/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200604/</guid>
      <description>Another work week almost done and dusted as the YouTubers say. Enjoying the warm weather. Looking forward to the weekend.
Good commute.
Ride on. ☮


  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday June 2, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200602/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200602/</guid>
      <description>Which Wich, my favorite sandwich shop, reopened today after a couple of months. My plan was to leave work 1 hour early at 4, ride my bike home, shower and be there by 5:30 PM. I rode probably harder than any other commute against a headwind. Got there by 5:25 PM to find the doors locked with a sign &amp;ldquo;We are closing at 5:30 due to the curfew&amp;rdquo;. Maybe tomorrow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ridgeville</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200531/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200531/</guid>
      <description>Rode Old Yeller to Ridgeville. Dry on the way up and wet on the way back. Brought back memories of my 2019 Good Friday ride to Myrtle Beach.
I was think about the song I&amp;rsquo;m Singing in the Rain. My version is better.
I&#39;m riding in the rain Just riding in the rain What a glorious feelin&#39; I&#39;m happy again I&#39;m laughing at clouds So dark up above The sun&#39;s in my heart And I&#39;m ready for miles Let the stormy clouds chase Everyone from the place Come on with the rain I&#39;ve a smile on my face I ride down the lane With a happy refrain Just riding, Riding in the rain Gardenias have the best fragrance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edisto Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200530/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200530/</guid>
      <description>Took the single speed for a century ride.
Recurring theme for Saturday rides is moving at least one turtle off the road. Today&amp;rsquo;s turtle was a little larger than the two last week. As I was telling it to stay off the road it tried to pee on me. Thankfully the stream went between my legs.
I traveled some new-to-me roads: Horseford Rd, Sandridge Rd, Old Beech Hill Rd, and Zion Rd just to name a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday May 28, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200528/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200528/</guid>
      <description>Busy week at work. So nice to let off some steam on the ride home. Looking forward to the weekend. I think I&amp;rsquo;ll ride my bicycle.
Good commute.
Ride on. ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday May 26, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200526/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200526/</guid>
      <description>Witnessed a colorful sunrise and enjoyed a strong tailwind on the way home, averaging 20 mi/h. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen without a tailwind.
Great commute.
Ride on. ☮
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>McClellanville Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200523/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200523/</guid>
      <description>Rode to one of my favorite towns, McClellanville. Moved a couple of turtles off the road on the way.
Beautiful sunny warm day in the lowcountry. Temperatures ranged from 72℉ to 97℉ according to my bike computer.
This was my 72nd century ride. They ain&amp;rsquo;t getting any easier.
Good day on the saddle.
Ride on. ☮












 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday May 21, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200521/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200521/</guid>
      <description>Rode my single speed to work. I managed to miss the rain. Pretty good commute.
Ride on. ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday May 19, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200519/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200519/</guid>
      <description>Rode my backup bicycle today, Giant Defy 3. Nothing wrong with Old Yeller. Just giving the backup a little attention.
Spotted a turtle trying to cross four lanes of Hwy 17-A. No way it would have survived that crossing. I carried it, legs flailing, to the edge of the woods and told it to have a good evening.
Good commute.
Ride on. ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single Speed Sunday</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200517/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200517/</guid>
      <description>Rode the single speed to Ridgeville. Breezy with very light rain showers here and there. Enjoyable ride except for the Hwy 78 segment.
Met my weekly goal of 200 miles with 28 to spare. Looking forward to the upcoming Memorial Day weekend. Hopefully the weather will be good. 🤞
Ride on. ☮




 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salty Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200516/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200516/</guid>
      <description>Average temperature was 82℉ with peaks above 90℉. My shorts were covered with salt.
Helped a small turtle cross the road. Saw some goats.
Took a wrong turn off of Calamus Pond Rd. Ended back on Hwy 176, the very road I was trying to avoid. Oh well.
Instead of taking Hwy 52 out of St Stephen I continued on Hwy 45 eventually riding Harristown Rd back to Hwy 17-A. Nice change of scenery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday May 14, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200514/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200514/</guid>
      <description>Great weather today. Good commute. I love riding my bicycle.
Ride on. ☮


  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday May 12, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200512/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200512/</guid>
      <description>46℉ this morning. Pretty chilly for the middle of May. Persistent pesky headwind on the way to work. Favorable wind on the way home.
Starting my commute an hour later seems to be working out OK. Still finishing my breakfast by the time 8 AM rolls around. Waking up at 5:30 AM instead of 4:30 AM makes a big difference.
Good commute.
Ride on. ☮


  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wampee</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200510/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 15:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200510/</guid>
      <description>Rode the single speed to the end of the Pinoplis peninsula on lake Moultrie. The Santee Cooper guard at the Wampee entrance just bought a Ridley mountain bike. He felt after 20 years he needed a new bike. Congrats on hanging on to a bike for that long and happy trails with your new ride.
The weather was nice. A little warmer than yesterday which was appreciated. The warmer the better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cookie Fueled Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200509/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200509/</guid>
      <description>Cookie Chick SC is usually at the Summerville Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market but for now she fulfills online orders on Saturdays in North Charleston starting at 11 AM. The minimum order is a dozen. I was about 45 minutes early so I rode into Hanahan to burn some time.
Picked up my assorted dozen, ate one, and put the rest in the Topeak backloader.
Had a nice tailwind into Charleston. Took the James Island connector over to Maybank Highway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Wednesday May 6, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200506/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200506/</guid>
      <description>Trying out a later start. I was getting up around 4:30 AM, getting to work before 6:00 AM, cooling down, eating breakfast and changing clothes. All that was done before others arrived at the office. There are some advantages to starting early like less automobile traffic and privacy when you are the first to arrive at the office. The down side is getting up so dang early and leaving work at 4 PM when there is always someone needing something at the end of the day from me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orangeburg Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200502/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 19:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200502/</guid>
      <description>Not much to see in Orangeburg but it was a ride I wanted to complete at least once. There is an 8 mile stretch on Hwy 78 that is pretty stressful traffic wise. I dreaded that segment on the way up and back. Things chill out once you get on Hwy 178. The majority of the ride is on Hwy 178.
After taking a spin around Orangeburg I took a wrong turn and asked Google navigation to get me home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boat Landing Way</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200430/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 20:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200430/</guid>
      <description>Hurried home from work to get this ride in before too late. Worked out well.
A few crazy impatient drivers on Hwy 176, Mudville Rd, and Hwy 17-A but I survived.
High temperature was 73℉ dropping to 63℉ at the end of the ride. Good ride.
Ride on. ☮





 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Moultrie</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200428/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200428/</guid>
      <description>The highlight of the ride was the fragrance of gardenia bushes when I turned onto Winter St in Moncks Corner. Really woke up the olfactory system in a wonderful way.
I had plans to ride to Cross but I got hung up at work and started a little late. Cut the ride off at Lake Moultrie. Good ride.
Ride on. ☮



 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colonial Dorchester State Historic Site</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200426/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200426/</guid>
      <description>Rode the Wabi Classic single speed to Colonial Dorchester State Historic Site. The park is closed until Friday May 1, 2020.
Nice temperatures and breezy. Met my 200 mile goal with only 3 rides this week.
Ride on. ☮

 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;on Swamp Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200425/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200425/</guid>
      <description>First time visiting I&amp;rsquo;on Swamp. Scenic ride on a well maintained gravel forestry road. 👍
Crossing the Cooper River I chose the road instead of the multi-use path. There were too many pedestrians and cyclist for the COVID-19 era. I assume it is perfectly legal but probably frowned upon by motorist and police. I survived.
This is the first century ride since March 21, 2020 in which I was exhausted at about mile 50.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Moultrie West Dike</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200421/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200421/</guid>
      <description>Shooting for four 50+ mile rides this week. One down three to go.
Breeze was mostly favorable. Temperatures were on both sides of 70℉. The gnats were out on the dike.
Good ride.
Ride on. ☮







  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Childsbury Towne Heritage Preserve</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200419/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200419/</guid>
      <description>Rescued a turtle and saw a corn snake. Got home just as the rain started.
Ended up with 225 this week. Any week over 200 miles is good.
Good ride.
Ride on. ☮






 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charleston Triangle</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200418/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200418/</guid>
      <description>Thursday&amp;rsquo;s windless ride was so nice. Today the wind was back with a vengeance. The temperatures were on both sides of 80℉. That was nice.
Rode the West Ashley Greenway because I wanted to refill my water bottles and it is the only fountain around. Unfortunately there was a lot of pedestrian and bicycle traffic on the greenway. I held my breath as I passed folks. Hope i didn&amp;rsquo;t catch COVID-19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bulow Landing</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200416/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 20:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200416/</guid>
      <description>For the first time in I can&amp;rsquo;t remember how long there was no wind. So much nicer.
Had a great ride down to Bulow Landing. It is beautiful especially when the tide is high and the sky is blue.
I had plenty of energy. Must be all the food I&amp;rsquo;m eating while working from home.
Ride on. ☮



 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ridgeville</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200414/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200414/</guid>
      <description>Hopped on the single speed after working from home. Rode to Ridgeville. Pretty chill except for Hwy 78.
Fun riding the Wabi Classic single speed. Thankfully not much wind to deal with.
Ride on. ☮


 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tannenbaum Rd</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200412/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200412/</guid>
      <description>Passed Tannenbaum Rd many times on the way to Charleston but never rode down it until today. After a mile or two it dead ends with an auto auction junkyard on one side and a horse on the other. Now I know.
Quite windy today but the temperatures where pleasant in the mid 70&amp;rsquo;s℉.
Pretty good week of riding covering 199.5 logged miles.
Ride on. ☮</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charleston</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200411/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200411/</guid>
      <description>Eerily quite on King St. The battery had a few folks enjoying the sunshine. Everyone appeared to be acting responsibly.
Traffic was light making it a pretty chill spin. Nice ride.
Ride on. ☮






 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bushy Park</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200410/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200410/</guid>
      <description>16 MPH wind changed my mind about riding a century today. Rode to Bushy Park instead.
Near record temperatures the last couple of days. Not today, around 70℉. Not bad but I prefer the 80s.
Ride on. ☮


 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday Interrupted</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200407/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 19:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200407/</guid>
      <description>What started out to be a pretty chill ride turned intense. A domain controller at work puked. I started getting phone calls about not being able to authenticate. Was about half way through my 32 mile ride. Made a few phone calls trying to figure out what was going on. Our network engineer resolved the issue with the domain controller as I sprinted home against a headwind. All worked out in the end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley River</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200405/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200405/</guid>
      <description>Rode down to the river. Breathed a cup of pollen. All good though.
Ride on. ☮



 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holly Hill</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200404/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 16:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200404/</guid>
      <description>Cooped up in the apartment all week. Had to get out. Rode to Harleyville and over to Holly Hill. Temperatures were in the low 70&amp;rsquo;s ℉. Nice ride.
Ride on. ☮




 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Moultrie West Dike</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200329/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 19:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200329/</guid>
      <description>Another beautiful day in the SC lowcountry. Rode along the west dike of Lake Moutlrie on Old Yeller.
Spotted a huge alligator swimming the cove near the Hatchery boat ramp.
There were a few folks sunbathing, walking, fishing, boating, and jet skiing. Hopefully those in boats were all family members.
Was going to ride through Moncks Corner on the way home but the was road closure at the railroad tracks so I turned around and headed home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday March 28, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200328/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 19:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200328/</guid>
      <description>Several things going on.
A week ago I road a century ride. Not unusual. I&amp;rsquo;ve completed 67 centuries so I have a good idea what it feels like. What was unusual was my level of fatigue. The exhaustion started half way through the ride. I wondered what caused it. Was it pollen, the heat, poor fueling, too much elevation for a single speed, or did I have COVID-19.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cainhoy Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200321/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 15:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200321/</guid>
      <description>Great weather. Temperatures were mostly in the 80&amp;rsquo;s ℉ although the bike computer read 91℉ at one point.
Had to ride through a controlled burn on Cainhoy Rd. Not a smart thing to be doing during a global pandemic causing respiratory illness.
The Ravenel Bridge and West Ashley Greenway multi-use paths were quite congested. Hopefully sweat and snot rockets were not shared.
Ride on. ☮</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday March 19, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200319/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200319/</guid>
      <description>Late night working Wednesday. Was going to sleep late and drive my car to work but woke up early enough for a bike commute.
Good one.
Ride on ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday March 17, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200317/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200317/</guid>
      <description>Good commute. Work is crazy.
Ride on ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Folly Beach Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200314/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 14:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200314/</guid>
      <description>Rather windy on the coast but the temperatures were warm enough to go just jersey, shorts, and sandals. Love it.
Rode the single speed today. Good fun.
Ride on. ☮






 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday March 12, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200312/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200312/</guid>
      <description>Two dry commutes in a row. Nice.
Good commute.
Ride on ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday March 10, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200310/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200310/</guid>
      <description>OK, we got the temperature rising. Now if the wind could calm down it would be ideal.
Good commute.
Ride on ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edisto Beach Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200308/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 17:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200308/</guid>
      <description>With the time change I was able to squeeze in an afternoon century and get home before dark. Nice!
Rode Old Yeller today instead of the single speed. It feels like the rolling resistance is greater on Old Yeller than the Wabi Classic single speed. I think the last couple of century rides on the single speed were easier than today&amp;rsquo;s. The extra gears are nice for bridges and headwinds but if I enjoy riding the single speed more perhaps I just need to toughen up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Wednesday March 4, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200304/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200304/</guid>
      <description>Rain all week, sunny and cool on the weekend is this year&amp;rsquo;s weather pattern. Enough already.
Another sloppy ride home. Still better than sitting on my butt in a car.
Morning commute was pleasant.
Ride on ☮
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stono River County Park Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200301/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 16:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200301/</guid>
      <description>Rode the not-yet-open Stono River County Park. It is super nice. There is a long board walk across the marsh. The view is beautiful. There is a bicycle repair station too. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen photographs of stations like this one but this is the first one I&amp;rsquo;ve put my hands on. Love it.
It was windy but not as strong as yesterday. I was able to squeeze in a century ride on the Wabi Classic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley River</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200229/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200229/</guid>
      <description>Short ride to the Ashley River. Quite windy which sucks the fun out of any ride especially when you are on a single speed.
There is a new Krispy Kreme doughnut shop on Ladson Rd. It was busy. So much so that there was someone in the parking lot directing traffic. No grease sponge for me. Just stopped for a photo of the sign.
Ride on. ☮</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Wednesday February 26, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200226/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200226/</guid>
      <description>Awoke to a 4 AM thunderstorm. Showered up and hit the road after the worst of the rain had passed. Wet and sloppy AM and PM commutes. At least the temperatures were on both sides of 60 ℉.
Sure wish they would pave a road connecting Black Tom Rd to Cane Bay. That segment is a mud fest.
Good commute.
Ride on ☮


  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Marion Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200223/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 16:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200223/</guid>
      <description>Rode up to Lake Marion and around Lake Moultrie. The single speed is perfect when it is flat and the headwinds are gentle. It is tough when climbing hills and bridges. Headwinds are no fun either. I definitively work harder on the Wabi Classic than I do on the Giant Anyroad 1. The simplicity of the single speed is very appealing. It is also the funnest bike I&amp;rsquo;ve ridden.
Ride on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wildgame Rd</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200222/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200222/</guid>
      <description>Went out the back of Nexton onto Sheep Island Rd. Took a left onto Wildgame Rd off of Jedburg Rd. My plan was to cut through Del Web Nexton but there was too much water. I road back up Wildgame Rd and took the longer route home.
Ride on. ☮


 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Monday February 17, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200217/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200217/</guid>
      <description>The weather forecast is not looking great this week. Rain every day with a cold snap towards the weekend. Given that forecast I decided to bike to work on a Monday. Luckily I dropped off a pair of work outfits last Friday.
This morning on the dirt section near Black Tom Rd a pigeon and I had a close encounter. We both startled each other equally. I sure wish they would pave that last section so I could hop on Black Tom Rd without getting muddy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday February 13, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200213/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200213/</guid>
      <description>Clear morning and a rainy ride home. Wet and 62℉ is not great but better than freezing. 80 miles of commuting on the single speed this week. Wheee. Just having fun.
Good commute.
Ride on. ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday February 11, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200211/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200211/</guid>
      <description>Started out on Old Yeller but the rear wheel locked up after a few miles. Reseated the rear wheel and hobbled home. Got on the single speed and headed back out.
We broke an 81 year old record today with a high temperature of 80℉. Love it!
Good commute.
Ride on. ☮


   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bulow Landing</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200209/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200209/</guid>
      <description>Another sun filled day in the South Carolina lowcountry. After riding by the road to Bulow Landing dozens of times I decided to check it out today. The road to the landing is lined on the right with big expensive new houses and marsh land on the left. Really nice but short ride to the landing on Rantowles Creek which is beautiful.
After visiting the landing I rode to Shadowmoss and then to the West Ashley Greenway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charleston</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200208/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200208/</guid>
      <description>Rode down to Charleston on the Wabi Classic. Clear blue sky and tempertures on both sides of 50 made for a nice ride. Still loving the single speed even with its aggressive riding position.
Ride on. ☮





 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday February 6, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200206/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200206/</guid>
      <description>Nice strong tailwind this morning made for an easy AM commute. Rainy headwind on the way home made was a little more adventurous. At least the temperatures were warm, mid to upper 60&amp;rsquo;s℉.
Saddled the single speed today. That bike is a blast to ride.
Good commute.
Ride on. ☮



   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday February 4, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200204/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200204/</guid>
      <description>AM 40&amp;rsquo;s and PM 60&amp;rsquo;s℉. Nice. New jersey day too. Yay! The zippers on the old jersey wore out. I dropped it off by a seamstress before Christmas. Haven&amp;rsquo;t heard a thing from her. Checked on it a couple of times already. Crickets.
Good commute.
Ride on. ☮



  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chandler Bridge Creek</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200202/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 12:48:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200202/</guid>
      <description>Found a nice trail off of Old Trolly Rd and rode it to Ladson Rd. It parallels Chandler Bridge Creek. A nice little gem.
Good afternoon spin.
Ride on. ☮

 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haney Branch Rd</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200201/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200201/</guid>
      <description>Found my way out of the back of a new subdivision in Nexton which empties onto Sheep Island Rd. From there I rode, for the first time, on Haney Branch Rd. Always fun to travel new-to-me roads.
Good evening spin.
Ride on. ☮

 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday January 28, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200128/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200128/</guid>
      <description>Rode the Wabi Classic single speed to work. A chilly morning low of 34℉. Nice afternoon ride in the 50&amp;rsquo;s℉.
Good commute.
Ride on. ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rosebrock Park</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200125/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200125/</guid>
      <description>Took a spill on a trail. Got a little too cocky on the single speed.
The left brake lever took the brunt of the ground impact. The lever was pushed down as well as the handlebars. The front brake was locked up but I was able to free it. Concerned about the bike and the possibility of having to walk home I didn&amp;rsquo;t think to check for my phone which got thrown from my jacket.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single Speed Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200118/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 21:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200118/</guid>
      <description>The Wabi Classic continues to surprise me. The 46/18 gearing is about perfect. Getting over bridges and cutting through a headwind is tough but other than that the Wabi Classic feels really good. I&amp;rsquo;m even contemplating making this my main bike. Didn&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;d ever demote Old Yeller but watch out. The simplicity of the single speed is just so attractive. Fun times.
There was a group of about 6 teenage motorcycle riders on the West Ashley Greenway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Wednesday January 15, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200115/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200115/</guid>
      <description>On my. This is a fun bike to ride. The single speed Wabi Classic arrived yesterday. Assembled and test ridden last night. Rode it work work today. I was a little apprehensive that it might be too tough for this old man to ride. Turns out the 46/18 gearing is just about perfect for the flat lowcountry. Speedy yet not spinny. Tough up a hill but not too tough. It might be too tough in a strong headwind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday January 14, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200114/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200114/</guid>
      <description>Making the most of this warm weather. Forecast a week from now is for below freezing temperatures.
Installed, poorly, a saddle I had laying around last night (Specialized Elaston). Came loose riding over a rock construction entrance about 8 miles from work. Rode it in like that. Was out of the saddle a good bit. Got it sorted for my lunch ride and commute home.
Good commute.
Ride on. ☮</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley River</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200112/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 14:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200112/</guid>
      <description>Rode down to the Ashley River. Roads were wet and it rained a little during the ride but the temperatures were in the seventies. It was all good.



 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200110/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 21:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200110/</guid>
      <description>I lost my cycling mojo. Monday I worked late and didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like getting up at 4:30 AM Tuesday so I decided to bike to work Wednesday instead. Wednesday morning I got geared-up and headed out for my 20 mile commute. The first 6 miles I was asking myself why am I doing this? It is fricking 31℉ and I&amp;rsquo;m not having any fun. I turned around and went home. I didn&amp;rsquo;t bike to work this week at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Friday January 3, 2020</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200103/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200103/</guid>
      <description>Ordered a fisheye lens from Amazon a couple of days ago and shipped it to work. Carried my DSLR to work today anticipating delivery of the lens. Arrived a few minutes before the end of my work day. Took a few snaps on the way home. I think I&amp;rsquo;m going to like the fisheye lens. You can get really close to the subject and still capture everything. Nice.
Commute was great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bonneau Ferry</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200101/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200101/</guid>
      <description>Revisited Bonneau Ferry for some gravel fun and scenery. Carried my Nikon D5500 and a 35mm fixed lens again. Kinda enjoy messing about with a real camera. Good ride.
Ride on. ☮
Photo album
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday December 31, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191231/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191231/</guid>
      <description>Last commute for this decade was a good one. No issues. Tolerable temperatures.
Here&amp;rsquo;s to a fresh new decade of accident free bicycle commuting.
Cheers!
Ride on. ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charleston Triangle</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191224/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191224/</guid>
      <description>I lugged my Nikon D5500 DSLR camera and a 35 mm lens on today&amp;rsquo;s ride. I wanted to see how much of a pain it would be to carry and if the photos were significantly better than photos from my Pixel 4.
Carrying it wasn&amp;rsquo;t bad. The strap would occasionally slide letting the camera off my back and around to my front. Might look into something like what Francis Cade uses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10,000 Miles in 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191220/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191220/</guid>
      <description>Today I met my goal of 10,000 miles riding my bicycles in 2019. Feels good. 585 hours of good old fashioned fun.
Not sure what my goal will be for 2020. Probably won&amp;rsquo;t be distance related.
Commute this morning was 21 miles in the twenties. The lowest temperature was 25℉. Chilly for this southern boy.
Ride on. ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday December 17, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191217/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191217/</guid>
      <description>A trend I can get behind. Temperatures in the 70&amp;rsquo;s℉ the second Tuesday in a row. Super nice.
Good commute.
Ride on. ☮


  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday December 17, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/201912170/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/201912170/</guid>
      <description>A trend I can get behind. Temperatures in the 70&amp;rsquo;s℉ the second Tuesday in a row. Super nice.
Good commute.
Ride on. ☮


  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday December 17, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/201912171/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/201912171/</guid>
      <description>A trend I can get behind. Temperatures in the 70&amp;rsquo;s℉ the second Tuesday in a row. Super nice.
Good commute.
Ride on. ☮


  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday December 17, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/201912172/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/201912172/</guid>
      <description>A trend I can get behind. Temperatures in the 70&amp;rsquo;s℉ the second Tuesday in a row. Super nice.
Good commute.
Ride on. ☮


  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191215/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 17:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191215/</guid>
      <description>Didn&amp;rsquo;t think I would log a century ride today. Ride on the Lake Moultrie dike was taxing. It was windy and the trail was spongy from the recent rains. The best segment was on Hwy 45 where I had a nice tailwind. Without that I probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have made this a century ride. For the first time since Tuesday the temperature was comfortable, hanging around in the 60&amp;rsquo;s℉ for a while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dungannon Plantation Heritage Preserve/Wildlife Management Area</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191214/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191214/</guid>
      <description>First visit to Dungannon WMA. It has nice pine needle covered trails leading to a swamp. There was more to explore. Skipped the trails that were under water. It rained yesterday. Good ride.
Ride on. ☮




  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday December 12, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191212/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191212/</guid>
      <description>I paid for a nice tailwind home with a 33℉ brutal headwind this morning. Lets call it even Mrs Winter. Bring that those seventies I enjoyed on Tuesday.
Ride on. ☮
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday December 10, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191210/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191210/</guid>
      <description>Seeing today&amp;rsquo;s forecast over the weekend I immediately decided to take a long route to work. Out the back of Nexton, Hwy 176, Mudville Rd, Hwy 6, Lake Moultrie west dike, Hwy 6 to work. Glorious morning.
Afternoon ride was good but windy. 65 miles for the day. I&amp;rsquo;ll take it.
Ride on. ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley River</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191208/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191208/</guid>
      <description>Rode to the Ashley River Sunday afternoon. Good ride.
Ride on. ☮
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BFC 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191207/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191207/</guid>
      <description>Rode to Snee Farm for the Big Family Christmas gathering. Took the long route there and the short route home. 91 miles for the day. Good day with the family.
2019 goal update. 9,614 of 10,000 miles so far. 386 miles to go.
Ride on. ☮

   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday December 5, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191205/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191205/</guid>
      <description>Another day, another dollar. Good commute rides this week. Looking forward to the weekend. Will be riding to Mt Pleasant for a family gathering Saturday. Not sure where I&amp;rsquo;ll go Sunday.
Ride on. ☮


  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday December 3, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191203/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191203/</guid>
      <description>31℉ on the ride to work this morning. Mid 40&amp;rsquo;s℉ on the way home. Not my favorite time of the year but it could be worse.
Ride on. ☮
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooper River</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191201/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191201/</guid>
      <description>It has been a good Thanksgiving holiday. Wracked up 293 miles this week with rides on Tuesday, Thursday, Friday, Saturday and Sunday. Pretty good for me.
Ride on. ☮</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>West Ashley Greenway</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191130/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191130/</guid>
      <description>Rode down to Charleston and hopped on my favorite cycling path the West Ashley Greenway, part of the East Coast Greenway. Mild temperatures with some sun made for a good ride.
Ride on. ☮</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Moultrie West Dike</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191129/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191129/</guid>
      <description>Rode along the west dike of Lake Moultrie. Clear blue sky was nice.
I got a puncture on the dike. Post ride inspection points towards a thorn through the side of the tire. I had several thorns in my leg warmers so this theory seems plausible. Strangely it was a slow leak.
The repair did not go smoothly. I have all the proper tools. Two spare tubes, two CO2 cartridges, a hand pump, patches and a tire lever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rear View Mirrors</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/mirrors/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/mirrors/</guid>
      <description>If you are riding on the road with automobile traffic I highly recommend a rear view mirror. Being able to see what it is coming up behind you while keeping an eye on what is in front of you is critical.
Below are some rear view mirrors I&amp;rsquo;ve tried. The last one in the list is the one I use.
These are fixed to the handlebar ends. It is hard to site-align with traffic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191128/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191128/</guid>
      <description>Rode to a Thanksgiving feast with the family. 38℉ the first hour of the ride. After the sun kicked in it warmed up nicely.
An hour after the feast I headed back home via different route. Talked with a cycling fisherman at the North Bridge Park while I snapped a couple of photos.
Ride on. ☮
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday November 26, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191126/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191126/</guid>
      <description>33℉ on the AM commute and a sunny 55℉ on the PM commute. Took the Cane Bay route home. First time since we had a rainy period. All good now.
Right wrist is slowing healing. Have a couple of saddle sores from Saturday&amp;rsquo;s 150 mile ride but no biggie. Looking forward to the 4 day Thanksgiving holiday weekend.
Ride on. ☮
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Georgetown Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191123/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 17:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191123/</guid>
      <description>Made the most of the mild temperatures by spending all day on the saddle. Rode to my favorite city Georgetown SC. Georgetown is South Carolina&amp;rsquo;s third oldest city behind Charleston and Beaufort. According to Wikipedia it is also the birthplace of former First Lady Michelle Obama&amp;rsquo;s grandfather, Fraser Robinson. Many of Michelle Obama&amp;rsquo;s Robinson relatives still reside in Georgetown. Very cool in my book.
The shortest route is 130 miles but returning on the same route is boring so I chose the longer route home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday November 21, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191121/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191121/</guid>
      <description>36℉ on the way to work and 55℉ on the way home with plenty of sunshine. Saturday&amp;rsquo;s temperature should top out in the 70s. Looking forward to it.
My right wrist is feeling better but not fully healed from my century ride around Lake Murray. Minimizing my gear shifting to aid the healing process.
Broke 9,000 miles for 2019. Need to knock out 1,000 more in the next 40 days to reach my goal of 10k.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday November 19, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191119/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191119/</guid>
      <description>41℉ on the AM commute and a sunny 53℉ on the PM commute. The weather has turned the corner away from rain and clouds to some sun. Pretty good day.
My right wrist is still not healed from Saturday&amp;rsquo;s century ride around Lake Murray. Come on. Hurry it up already.
Ride on. ☮
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mepkin Abbey</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191117/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191117/</guid>
      <description>Toyed with riding a century today but once I hit the headwinds I nixed that thought. Rode to the beautiful Mepkin Abbey instead. Probably should have waited a couple of hours because the sun came out on my way home. Sunshine, I&amp;rsquo;ve missed you. Don&amp;rsquo;t be a stranger.
My right wrist is still hurting from the Lake Murray Century ride. ☹
Ride on. ☮
Mepkin Abbey  Mepkin Abbey  Cooper River near Childsbury Towne Heritage Preserve  Tailrace Canal    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley River</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191116/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191116/</guid>
      <description>Rode down to the Ashley River before the rain returned. It was 43℉ with gusty winds. Not ideal conditions but it could be much worse. Looking forward to a glimpse of the sun tomorrow.
Ride on. ☮
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday November 12, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191112/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191112/</guid>
      <description>Feel pretty wimpy for leaving work at noon to beat the cold rain. Tonight it will dip down into the upper 20&amp;rsquo;s℉. Bah, humbug. It is going to be a challenge to get miles in with this rainy cold weather. I just need to toughen up. This weather is pretty tame compared to other locations.
My right wrist is swollen and sore from Saturday&amp;rsquo;s century ride around Lake Murray. I think because I changed gears so much due to the hills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Murray Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191109/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191109/</guid>
      <description>Drove the Chevy Bolt EV to Swansea, SC and parked at the Lexington County Library. Cleared it with the librarian and hit the road on Old Yeller.
First time cycling this part of the South Carolina. Surprised by the amount of urban sprawl around Lake Murray and the hills on this route. With an average temperature of 46℉ I never felt comfortable. The cool wind, hills, and heavy traffic prevented me from relaxing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday November 5, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191105/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191105/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve watched The Game Changers and Forks Over Knives. Both are informative providing a plethora of reasons why we should be eating a plant based diet. Solves so many problems for our environment and our health.
Good commute.
Ride on. ☮
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyde Park Rd</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191103/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191103/</guid>
      <description>Rode down to Hyde Park Rd and back.
Experienced some pleasant human interactions which is usually not the case.
On the corner of Hwy 165 and County Line Rd there is a farmhouse with a couple of roosters that are always crowing. The property owner was outside and I let him know how I love hearing the roosters when I ride by. I had stopped on the side of the road to eat a fig newton.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Lakes Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191102/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191102/</guid>
      <description>A chilly start at 40℉. On the lake dike it was about 8 degrees warmer. Water is still warm. Nice.
Pretty good ride although I didn&amp;rsquo;t have much punch in my legs so I took it easy.
Ride on. ☮
Photo album
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday October 31, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191031/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191031/</guid>
      <description>No tricks this week. All good except for a lady yelling at me to ride the bicycle path. I would if there was one from Moncks Corner to Summerville.
October is done and dusted. It has been a warm one and I&amp;rsquo;ve loved it. This morning started off in the 70&amp;rsquo;s℉. Tomorrow morning will be 30 degrees cooler. Boo.
The miles by month in 2019
 807 January 553 Feburary 982 March 726 April 827 May 868 June 826 July 1043 August 1050 September 835 October 8,517 miles so far in 2019  Ride on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday October 29, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191029/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191029/</guid>
      <description>Little foggy this morning, drizzling on the way home but mild temperatures. Good commute.
Old Yeller is performing well. Need to replace the splitting foam grips on my handlebars before Thursday&amp;rsquo;s commute.
Ride on. ☮
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colonial Dorchester State Historic Site</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191027/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191027/</guid>
      <description>Chill Sunday afternoon ride after the rain fell to Old Fort Dorchester.
Ride on. ☮



 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charleston Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191026/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191026/</guid>
      <description>Incredibly nice weather for late October. Mid 80s℉. I&amp;rsquo;ll take it.
Chose to ride Cainhoy Rd instead of Hwy 41 at the last moment. Good decision. Hwy 41 is straight as an arrow, busier, and less scenic than Cainhoy Rd.
Rode thorough Dunes West subdivision to avoid the busiest section of Hwy 41. I haven&amp;rsquo;t memorized the route through Dunes West yet. I tend to doubt my turns. Had to look at my phone a couple of times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday October 24, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191024/</guid>
      <description>After a couple of weeks of acquiring tools, parts, and knowledge I have Old Yeller back on the road. Replaced the slipping freehub with a new one last night. Rode Old Yeller to work today. Super nice. Good tailwind home. Average speed 20 MPH.
Took several days of research to find the correct freehub, SRAM MTH 506. It shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be that hard.
Whip it good 
Took a while to get a 11mm hex wrench</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday October 22, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191022/</guid>
      <description>Loving this weather. Late October and we hit 88℉ according to the bike computer. Thought I was going to get rained on today but lucked out, again. Good commute.
Current gear issues:
 Spoke missing on Giant Defy 3 rear wheel Identify and repair tick sound while pedaling Defy 3 Waiting on freehub to be delivered for Giant Anyroad 1 Replacement Wahoo Elemnt Bolt bike computer is on the way Need to ship defective bike computer to Wahoo tomorrow  Ride on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nestor lead out Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191019/</guid>
      <description>Up at 3 AM and on the road by 4 AM to beat the post-tropical cyclone Nestor rain. Worked out pretty well. Rain started at mile 90. Still riding the back-up bike. Can&amp;rsquo;t find the correct freehub for Old Yeller.
The only downside was the Summerville Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market was mostly closed. The vegetable stands were open but the main row with the Cookie Chick didn&amp;rsquo;t open due to Nestor. No cookies for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday October 17, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191017/</guid>
      <description>Another week on the backup bike. I received two hex wrenches today. They were supposed to be both 11 mm. One of them was a 10 mm. Glad I ordered two. Removed the freehub and if I get the correct one tomorrow I might be riding Old Yeller Saturday. Rain or shine.
Good commute this week. I had a family gathering after work today so I put a little extra effort in the ride home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday October 15, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191015/</guid>
      <description>Riding the backup bike while I try to figure out freehub replacement on Old Yeller. Better figure it out soon because my backup bike is missing a spoke in the rear wheel.
Gave some thought of buying the Giant Contend AR 1 2020 as the geometry and components are fairly close to my Giant Anyroad 1 but that is not the proper thing to do. Keep repairing Old Yeller until the frame snaps in two.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>South Tibwin Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 03:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191012/</guid>
      <description>A friend suggested I check-out the South Tibwin Hiking Trail so that is what I did today. I had passed the entrance to this trail on my trips to McClellanville but never ventured in. I was pleasantly surprised by the amount of water access. It is beautiful. Accidentally ran over a black snake&amp;rsquo;s tail. I hope it survived. The trail is a mix of grass, pine straw, downed tree limbs, and roots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday October 10, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191010/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191010/</guid>
      <description>Time is flying by. Actually wore a jacket on the way to work this morning.
Back on the Defy 3. The Anyroad 1 has a slipping freehub. It&amp;rsquo;s always something.
Good commute. Ride on. ☮
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday October 8, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191008/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191008/</guid>
      <description>Drive train is not performing well, once again.
Ride on. ☮
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walterboro Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191005/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 02:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191005/</guid>
      <description>Didn&amp;rsquo;t have a route planned when I hopped on the bike this morning. I knew I wanted a couple of cookies from the Summerville Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market. Made a loop around Summerville before heading out to Walterboro. Hwy 17-A is not great.Two lanes, plenty of vehicular traffic at 55+ MPH. I survived the trip there and took a different route home. A strong northerly wind made for a slow ride home. Temperatures were in the 70s ℉ so that was pretty sweet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday October 3, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191003/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191003/</guid>
      <description>Chain is worn. Skips when I get out of the saddle. Gonna replace it Friday night. Probably will ride another century Saturday for the 15th consecutive weekend.
Commute was good. New PM route is working out good. If they can get that exit off of Black Tom Rd paved it would be ace.
Ride on. ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday October 1, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191001/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191001/</guid>
      <description>Great weather continues. Good commute. That is all.
Ride on. ☮
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snee Farm</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190929/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190929/</guid>
      <description>Rode to Snee Farm for a family gathering. Great weather. Still nice and warm.
Logged 243 miles this week. Pretty good for me.
Ride on. ☮

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edge of America Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190928/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 01:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190928/</guid>
      <description>Another beautiful Saturday in the SC lowcountry. Had a nice ride to Folly Beach.
End of Q3 already. I&amp;rsquo;ve logged a century ride for the last 14 weekends. Going to try to keep that streak going until the end of 2019. We&amp;rsquo;ll see.
Ride on. ☮
Photo album
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday September 26, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190926/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190926/</guid>
      <description>Looking forward to a paved road from Cane Bay to Black Tom Rd. As of this post it is still a construction zone. Probably the toughest part of this route.
On the PM commute I had a water truck tailing me into a round-a-bout and I took the first out instead of the second. Before I realized what I had done I was half way to a dead end. Ended up in the woods again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday September 24, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190924/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190924/</guid>
      <description>Took the multi-use path in Cane Bay until it ended. Tried to get back on track by cutting through the woods. Ended up on Hwy 176 in front of the under construction Nexton Parkway. Hopped on the gravel and headed home. Made the PM commute almost 22 miles. Cool.
Ride on. ☮
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Santee Coastal Reserve Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190921/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 03:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190921/</guid>
      <description>The Santee Coastal Reserve is another hidden gem. The cape is absolutely gorgeous. Water fowl galore and plenty of gators too. As I rode out on the cape, sunning gators would scurry into the water. The most stunning site was a large flock of white egrets or herons flying. A look-out tower near the South Santee River provides breathtaking views.
As far as the ride goes it was great. I started from Moncks Corner instead of Summerville.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday September 19, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190919/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190919/</guid>
      <description>The new PM route through Cane Bay is growing on me. Really the only sketchy part is Black Tom Rd. Getting off of Black Tom Rd and into Cane Bay is a little precarious too. The entrance is lined with golf ball size rocks, then sand, and finally a construction machinery crossing. Once I hit the pavement it is good. The automobile traffic picks up the closer I get to Hwy 176.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday September 17, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190917/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190917/</guid>
      <description>Took the usual route in the AM and a different route in the PM. Entered the back of Cane Bay via Black Tom Rd. The difference is a toss up. Hwy 17-A, the usual route, is busy but at least it is 4 lanes. Black Tom Rd is only two lanes with trucks and cars that won&amp;rsquo;t slow down for a cyclist. The Cane Bay route is about 5 miles longer which isn&amp;rsquo;t a big deal but the chance of getting hit by a motor vehicle is about the same on both routes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Century Saturday 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190914/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 01:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190914/</guid>
      <description>Wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure I had it in me today. Knew I was at least going to get a couple of cookies from the Cookie Chick at the Summerville Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market. Made the decision to continue the ride after taking a minute to eat one of the cookies. Glad I pressed on.
While emptying the trash from my jersey pocket at the farmer&amp;rsquo;s market my leg brushed against a poisonous plant. I guess it was poison oak or ivy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday September 12, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190912/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190912/</guid>
      <description>Uneventful commute this week. I gnashed my shin with my pedal at a traffic light. Bled like a fountain. Other than that it was a quiet week. Looking forward to the weekend. Probably knock out a century Saturday.
Sunday I have an appointment to see a cottage at Nexton. The new line of homes are supposed to be smaller than the mansions they normally build. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll get out of this apartment one day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday September 10, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190910/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190910/</guid>
      <description>Another bicycle rider was killed Sunday around 10 AM on a road I&amp;rsquo;ve traveled a few times. 33 year old Megan Walters Rafferty was a counselor at Ashley Ridge High School. RIP Megan.
All good with my commute. I didn&amp;rsquo;t die.
My 10k goal is on track. Cracked 7K this weekend. Currently at 7,065 towards my goal of 10,000 quality cycling miles in 2019.
Ride on. ☮
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Moultrie West Dike</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190908/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 21:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190908/</guid>
      <description>Too tired after yesterday&amp;rsquo;s century to ride in the AM and too hot during the day I waited until the evening. Caught a nice sunset on the Lake Moultrie dike. The temperatures cooled off nicely.
Ride on. ☮
Photo album
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wee Tee Wildlife Management Area Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190907/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 01:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190907/</guid>
      <description>Oh my. What a hidden treasure. Wee Tee WMA is awesome. You can access it right off of Hwy 17-A north of Santee River. Surprised to see hills surrounding several beautiful lakes. Absolutely beautiful.
My plan was to cut across to St Stephen SC but I ended up back on Hwy 17-A. Not a fan of returning home via the same route so I headed to Andrews SC and caught Hwy 521.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Friday September 6, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190906/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190906/</guid>
      <description>Hurricane Dorian left the roads lined with pine needles, leaves, and limbs providing a fresh pine scented ride.
Almost collided with an opossum crossing Hwy 17-A.
So glad to see some sunshine today.
Ride on. ☮
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday September 3, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190903/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190903/</guid>
      <description>Hurricane Dorian is taking its time getting to South Carolina. Expecting a brush-by on Thursday so I doubt I&amp;rsquo;ll commute by bike on Thursday.
Today&amp;rsquo;s commute was good. Had a nice tailwind on the way home.
Ride on. ☮
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labor Day Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190902/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190902/</guid>
      <description>Bit of a breeze blowing. I planned the route so I would have a tailwind on the way home. I thought a couple of time of turning and going home when the wind was blowing in my face. I&amp;rsquo;m glad I stuck with it. Good ride.
Ride on. ☮
Photo album
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edisto WMA</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190901/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190901/</guid>
      <description>This ride did not live up to expectations. I was thinking I could get to the Edisto river but it didn&amp;rsquo;t work out. I did see some nice trails and cypress swamps but no water. Nothing like yesterday&amp;rsquo;s ride which was off the charts.
I can&amp;rsquo;t believe it is September already. Summer please don&amp;rsquo;t go.
Ride on. ☮
Photo album
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bonneau Ferry Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190831/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190831/</guid>
      <description>Wow, what a beautiful ride. I was having a hard time deciding where to ride. Decided to explore Rice Hope Plantation and Bonneau Ferry Wildlife Management Area. Good decision. Rode miles of gravel roads. The scenery was off the chart. Truly gorgeous area. To cap the ride off I rode the Lake Moultrie west dike.
I love riding my bicycle.
Ride on. ☮
Photo album
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday August 29, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190829/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190829/</guid>
      <description>Really digging Keen sandals. So much so I ordered a second pair. This pair is trimmed in yellow to match my bike, jersey, helmet, and watch strap. Sweet.
Good commutes this week. Hoping hurricane Dorian stays away over my Labor Day weekend. 🤞
Ride on. ☮
Bicycle in front of Windmill Station sign 
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday August 27, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190827/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190827/</guid>
      <description>I am a creature of habit. Work Monday through Friday, bike commute on Tuesdays and Thursdays, and I eat lunch at Subway every weekday. The veggie spinach wrap is awesome. That wrap with an unsweet iced tea is probably my favorite meal. Refreshing and tasty.
Just think of how many problems we could solve if everyone adopted a plant based diet.
Good commute today. Cooler temperatures still hanging around.
Ride on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gray Charleston</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190825/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190825/</guid>
      <description>A lower pressure system off the coast brought cool temperatures (63℉), damp air, a breeze and gray skies. Took a leisurely ride down to Charleston over to the West Ashley Greenway and back home. Good way to spend Sunday morning.
Ride on. ☮
Photo album
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Donnelley WMA Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190824/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190824/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been contemplating a ride to Hunting Island, Beaufort, or Savannah GA. I chose today&amp;rsquo;s ride to the Donnelley Wildlife Management Area for more time on Hwy 17. The road surface is not good and traffic is pretty heavy until you get past Jacksonboro SC. A ride to Beaufort is going to be pretty monotonous but it is doable. We&amp;rsquo;ll see.
Donnelly WMA is pretty cool. I looped around it on a pretty good gravel road.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday August 22, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190822/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190822/</guid>
      <description>My Garmin Edge 520 quit charging so I picked up a Wahoo Elemnt. I really like the device set-up. Settings are all maintained via the Android app.
Funny how a little bit of change throws you off. This morning I forgot my gloves. I turned around about a mile out to get them. I was thinking about what would happen to my palms if I were to come off my bike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday August 20, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190820/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190820/</guid>
      <description>Nice commute. The ride home was cooler for an August afternoon. We had a few rain showers around noon which helped keep temperature below normal.
I am determined more than ever to meet my 10,000 mile goal for 2019. Chipping away at my pace deficit. I am at 6,253 which is 102 miles behind pace. Hoping that the Labor day holiday will get me ahead of pace. Onwards and upwards!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Moultrie West Dike</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190818/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190818/</guid>
      <description>Note to self. Don&amp;rsquo;t ride the Lake Moultrie dike the day after it rains. The dike wasn&amp;rsquo;t muddy but was like glue. When it wasn&amp;rsquo;t soggy it was super rough with new gravel that is more golf ball size rock than gravel. Don&amp;rsquo;t know where Santee Cooper gets their gravel but this latest batch is not bicycle friendly. Oh well, the scenery and temperatures were nice.
Easy Sunday morning.
In other cycling news&amp;hellip; I found a good bike washing method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soggy Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190817/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190817/</guid>
      <description>Drizzle right from the start of the ride. Actually thought I would have had more rain than I did. The steadiest downpour was around Remount and Rivers in North Charleston. Kinda refreshing.
The highlight of the ride was a huge owl flyby in the Dunes West subdivision. Magnificent animal.
Ride was pleasant. Finished up the ride with a stop at the Summerville Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market to buy the last two Cookie Chick oatmeal cookies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday August 15, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190815/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190815/</guid>
      <description>Old Yeller fresh from the LBS is shifting like a Ford Pinto low on transmission fluid. What a way to start the day. The rear derailleur had a mind of its own. Shifting and skipping when it felt like it. Frustrating! My LBS let me down big time. I&amp;rsquo;m going to see what I can do with it tomorrow after work. The weekend is here it is time to ride.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday August 13, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190813/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190813/</guid>
      <description>Rode to work on my backup bike because Old Yeller was in the shop getting cables. All the cables were sticking and this weekend I could take no more. After work I picked up Old Yeller from Mike&amp;rsquo;s Bikes on Folly Rd.
Commute was good. The ride home was a smoking hot 95°F. Looking forward to the Thursday commute on Old Yeller. It shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be as hot and there is also a higher chance of rain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bushy Park</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190811/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190811/</guid>
      <description>Rode to Bushy Park. Each time I ride there I ask myself why. Bushy Park Rd has one of the worst surfaces around. Really rough ride. Other than that it was a good time.
Had to take Old Yeller back to Mike&amp;rsquo;s Bikes. I need new cables. All cables but the front disc brake cable are sticking badly. The LBS mechanic mentioned last time I had it in that the cables were sticking but he got them working.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isle of Palms Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190810/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190810/</guid>
      <description>Rode on the beach of Sullivan&amp;rsquo;s Island just before sunrise. Beautiful.
Hopped over to the Isle of Palms and then up the connector to Rifle Range Rd. To avoid the busiest section of Hwy 41 I rode through Dunes West subdivision on Park W Blvd. The route is a little longer but worth avoiding the traffic.
Had a puncture in Moncks Corner SC. Slapped a new tube on, inflated with a CO2 cartridge and was rolling again in no time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday August 8, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190808/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190808/</guid>
      <description>It is August. Of course it is hot. Took it easy on the way home. Poured as much water on my head as down my throat. Good commute.
Ride on. ☮
  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday August 6, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190806/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190806/</guid>
      <description>Good commute. No automobile altercations and weather is great.
Ride on. ☮
   Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Moultrie West Dike</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190804/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190804/</guid>
      <description>Rode to Lake Moultrie for a ride along the west dike. Always a good time. Started later than usual so I wore my sun protection gear, sun sleeves and skull cap.
Ride on. ☮
Train crossing Main St Moncks Corner SC 
  Relive &#39;Lake Moultrie West Dike&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bowman Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190803/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190803/</guid>
      <description>The Keen sandals were good on the commutes this week so I tried them on a century ride. The sandals worked out well. Instead of my feet being in sweat soaked hot Adidas shoes they were airing out in the wind. 👍👍
I incorrectly thought it was going to be raining all day. There was rain off the coast and I assumed it would be heading inland so I changed my route.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday August 1, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190801/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190801/</guid>
      <description>August already. Slow down. I want summer to last.
Good commute.
Ride on. ☮
Moncks Corner Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market 
  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday July 30, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190730/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190730/</guid>
      <description>Glad to have Old Yeller back for my commutes this week.
Bought a pair of KEEN sandals. My Adidas shoes would be soaked with sweat and caked hard with salt. First commute in sandals was good. Nice and cool.
Good commute.
Ride on. ☮
Keen sandal 
  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Century Saturday 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190727/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190727/</guid>
      <description>Two century rides in a row having something left in the tank at the end. The wind was favorable for the most part. That probably has a lot to do with it. I&amp;rsquo;ll take it. Great ride.
Ride on. ☮
Bicycle on Diversion Canal bridge Hwy 45 
Trail between Hwy 45 and Hwy 52 
Childsbury Towne Heritage Preserve 
  Relive &#39;Century Saturday 💯&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday July 25, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190725/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190725/</guid>
      <description>Cooler temperatures and less humidity than normal for July in South Carolina. Felt great. Even had a tailwind on the way home. Very rare. I&amp;rsquo;ll take it.
Fingers crossed that Mike&amp;rsquo;s Bikes will call me tomorrow and tell me Old Yeller is ready. 🤞
Good commute.
Ride on. ☮
  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday July 23, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190723/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190723/</guid>
      <description>Old Yeller is getting a new drivetrain. Riding the Defy 3 until I get back my main bike which hopefully will happen before the weekend.
Strong headwind on the way home. Change in the weather is coming. A little less heat and some rain.
Good commute.
Ride on. ☮
  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edge of America Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190720/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190720/</guid>
      <description>Goose bumps were had while riding on the beach. First time beauty has had that affect on me.
This. was. an. absolutely. perfect. ride.
Riding over the James Island connector bridge there was a Waning Gibbous moon opposite the rising sun.
Temperatures were warm but not hot, blue sky, light winds, no altercations with automobiles, and I felt great, unlike last Saturday. I don&amp;rsquo;t think it can get any better than this but I&amp;rsquo;ll keep trying.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday July 18, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190718/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190718/</guid>
      <description>Spotted a fox running across the parking lot this morning. Always a pleasant surprise.
Another hot one on the way home, 93 °F. Good commute.
After dinner I tried my first GU Energy Stroopwafel. 👍👍 Should be a good fuel on the bike.
Ride on. ☮
GU Energy Stroopwafel 
   Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday July 16, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190716/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190716/</guid>
      <description>First day back on the bike since my 120 mile ride Saturday. I needed a couple of days to recover from that tough, tough, century ride.
Hot ride home. Maximum temperature according to Garmin was 95 °F. Good commute.
Checked my mileage goal. I have 5,239 of my goal of 10,000 miles in 2019. I&amp;rsquo;m 158 miles behind pace.
Ride on. ☮
   Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>McClellanville Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190713/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190713/</guid>
      <description>I love McClellanville. Such a beautiful coastal town. Fantastic homes on the tree lined Pinckney St.
My fortieth century had a brutally tough finish. My legs were cramping and I was running on empty the last two hours of this 8 hour ride. Had to stop to stretch and recover a couple of times. I never had to do that before. Here&amp;rsquo;s to the next 40 less painful century rides. 🍺</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday July 11, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190711/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190711/</guid>
      <description>Good commute to work. Ride home was tough with temperatures in the 90&amp;rsquo;s °F with persistent headwind. Still better than driving.
Received an email today from Strava and Relive today. Relive can no longer use the Strava API. They reportedly violated several terms of the API. Relive made some software changes recently and made it much easier to create a video with their service. In addition to the tracking data Relive started transferring the title and photos from Strave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday July 9, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190709/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190709/</guid>
      <description>Saw Ms. Fox this morning hanging out on Stony Landing Rd. Really cool animals. Hopefully her 2 friends are doing OK. Didn&amp;rsquo;t see them today.
Great commute. Rained after lunch which provided a cooler than normal ride home. Sweet.
Ride on. ☮
   Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Santee Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190707/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190707/</guid>
      <description>Alarm went off at 3 AM and I was on the road to Santee SC at 4:00 AM. This century was soooo much less difficult than Thursday&amp;rsquo;s century. I wish I knew why. I&amp;rsquo;ll take it.
Low traffic, cool weather, and good roads. Great ride.
GoPro is really donking up. Half of my footage is just white video. Time for a new camera.
Ride on. ☮
Bike on Bonner Ave near Santee SC</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>US Independence Day Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190704/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190704/</guid>
      <description>Awoke a tick or two before 3 AM and was on the road to Edisto Beach at 4:08 AM. Had the road pretty much to myself on the way there.
On Palmetto Blvd a few folks were getting their morning run and walk in and a few were cycling. On the beach folks were walking, collecting shells, and setting up for the day. Edisto Beach is a pretty chill place to be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday July 2, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190702/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190702/</guid>
      <description>Saw 3 foxes on Stony Landing Rd probably searching for rabbits. Would have loved to see the footage but my GoPro Hero6 is failing more than succeeding lately.
Sloppy start in the AM. It had just finished raining in Summerville. As I got closer to Moncks Corner it was dry as a Arizona bone. Kinda warm on the ride home, 93°F.
Good commute. Ride on. ☮
  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Century Saturday 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190629/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190629/</guid>
      <description>I woke up at 3 AM and was on the road at 4:18 AM. This was a near perfect ride. I felt good all the way to the end. No altercations with automobiles. Great weather. All in all a chill ride.
A couple of turkeys crossed in front of me on Hard Pinch Rd. I stopped the GoPro after that to mark the event for later retrieval. The file is corrupt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday June 27, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190627/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190627/</guid>
      <description>Before getting on the road home it rained a little bit. Temperatures were lower than usual. Made for a pleasant ride home.
Replaced my ridiculously over priced rear view mirror. The old one was dark in spots and generally hazy. Enjoyed a better view during today&amp;rsquo;s commute.
I joined the Rails To Trails Conservancy a few weeks ago. Received a t-shirt, magazine and sticker today. 👍
Ride on. ☮
Rear view mirror replaced</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday June 25, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190625/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190625/</guid>
      <description>Good commute.
After work, against my better judgment, I ate at Taco Boy on opening day. Wasn&amp;rsquo;t too crazy. Had a couple of vegan tacos and a Dos Equis. I didn&amp;rsquo;t see any local brews on tap. I&amp;rsquo;ll go back after the newness wears off.
Ride on. ☮
   Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday Funday</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190623/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190623/</guid>
      <description>Other than a close call with a Wendy&amp;rsquo;s customer, today was a good day. Much better than yesterday&amp;rsquo;s storm filled ride. Partly cloudy skies, moderate temperatures, 4 blue birds, 1 red headed woodpecker, sunflowers, and mostly scenic Low Country was the story for this ride.
My external battery I use to power my GoPro camera died. Yesterday&amp;rsquo;s rain was too much for it.
Ride on. ☮
Sunflower on the West Ashley Greenway</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday Ride</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190622/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190622/</guid>
      <description>The plan was to wake up early to beat the heat for a century ride. The plan went to sh*t. I didn&amp;rsquo;t check the radar until my ride was well underway. There was a line of thunderstorms coming from the north and west. Determined to stick to my route I ventured on. I met my match. The storm was pretty fierce in Cross SC so I wimped out and came back home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday June 20, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190620/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190620/</guid>
      <description>Can&amp;rsquo;t remember the last time it took me over an hour to get home. 61 minute commute home. The wind got the best of me today.
Looking forward to the weekend. Ride on. ☮
   Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday June 18, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190618/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190618/</guid>
      <description>Part of Hwy 17-A approximately between Cypress Garden Rd and Black Tom Rd is getting resurfaced. I didn&amp;rsquo;t notice anything wrong with the tarmac at least not in the area they are working on. Closer to Summerville the top of the asphalt is coming up big time. Will be interesting to see if this project goes that far. I&amp;rsquo;m not complaining. Any new tarmac is welcomed.
Received a can of chain degreaser and a chain cleaning tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Father&#39;s Day 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190616/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 19:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190616/</guid>
      <description>What a great day. Rode to Mt Pleasant for a family gathering. Had a nice cross tailwind most of the way. The traffic on Mathis Ferry Rd wasn&amp;rsquo;t as bad as I anticipated. It is a beautiful tree lined road. The entire route is pretty good considering how busy Mt Pleasant traffic is.
After a couple of black bean burgers it was time to head home. The wind was mostly favorable on the way home too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Certified South Carolina</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190615/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190615/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve passed this Certified South Carolina sign many times on County Line Rd. Today I stopped to snap a picture. Chopped off some of the sign. Will try again.
Not real energetic rides but glad I made them. Great weather today. It was actually a little too chilly this morning with a low temperature of 50 °F. The ride home was more to my liking with an average of 84 °F.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday June 13, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190613/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190613/</guid>
      <description>Unseasonably cool. 62 °F on the AM commute and 75 °F on the PM commute. Misty this morning. Was soaked by the time I got to the office. Headwind returned for the ride home.
Good commute. Ride on. ☮
   Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday June 11, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190611/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190611/</guid>
      <description>Another weather lucky day. I woke at 3 AM looked at the radar and said I can get to work before that rolls in.
The afternoon rain looked to almost be stationary to the south.
Another rain free commute. And for a bonus I had a rare tailwind on the ride home. Made pretty good time.
45:55 Moving Time
21.2 mph Avg Moving Speed
26.4 mph Max Speed
Ride on. Oh yeah, do no harm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Childsbury Towne Heritage Preserve Again</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190609/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190609/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m really digging the ride to the Childsbury Towne Heritage Preserve. If I recall correctly I&amp;rsquo;ve cycled to it 3 weekends straight. Hwy 402 and Dr Evans Rd have a nice surface and low weekend traffic. On the way I stopped by the new YMCA in Cane Bay. From the outside this looks like a super nice facility. My favorite amenity is the water bottle refill station out by the tennis courts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday Morning Ride</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190608/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190608/</guid>
      <description>The forecast called for rain but it didn&amp;rsquo;t happen. Rode to Charleston and hit part of the West Ashley Greenway before meandering back to the Summerville Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market and home.
 Charleston Battery 
East Bay St Charleston 
 Relive &#39;Saturday morning ride&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday June 6, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190606/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190606/</guid>
      <description>We had a couple of weeks of dry weather. Looks like we&amp;rsquo;ve switched to a rain cycle. Another cloudy rainy day. I avoided most of it. 👍
Good smooth commutes this week. Ride on. ☮
   Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday June 4, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190604/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190604/</guid>
      <description>I thought I might get wet on the way home. A few drizzles and some water on the road but for the most part the rain avoided me. Good commute.
Ride on. ☮
  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belle Isle Plantation Cemetery Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190602/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190602/</guid>
      <description>I have seen the Belle Isle Plantation Cemetery sign many times cycling Highway 45. Today I took that turn. This is where Francis Marion and his wife are buried. Also known as The Swamp Fox he was a military officer who served in the American Revolutionary War (1775-1783). Towards the end of this ride I was in the Francis Marion forest.
It may surprise some but this part of South Carolina has some pretty good roads for riding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Friday May 31, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190531/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190531/</guid>
      <description>On the commute home there was a thunderstorm off in the distance. I heard some thunder, felt a few raindrops, and battled the wind.
Good commute. Ride on. ☮
  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Wednesday May 29, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190529/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190529/</guid>
      <description>Four straight days of 100℉. Thankfully there was some cloud cover on my way home. The Garmin recorded a high of 99℉.
While on Hwy 17-A nearing Summerville I had someone sitting on their horn. I assume their anger was directed towards me. It was kinda of comical when I passed the car while it was waiting on traffic. They blew their horn the second time behind me. I really don&amp;rsquo;t see what the big deal is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strawberry Chapel and Childsbury Town Site</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190527/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190527/</guid>
      <description>Super nice route. First time traveling the length of Sawmill Rd. It had the poorest tarmac but the ride is chill. I saw a nice snake catching some rays. Hwy 402 and Dr Evans roads are super sweet recently paved roads. What else can I say about this route. It is a good one and one I will repeat.
Today is Memorial Day in the US, a federal holiday for remembering and honoring people who have died while serving in the United States Armed Forces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Century Ride before the Century Temperatures 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190525/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190525/</guid>
      <description>With triple digit temperatures in the forecast I got an early start. I was on the road by 4:20 AM. I finished the ride a little after 11 AM. It was 91℉ already.
It was a pleasant ride. My favorite segments were Hwy 402 and the West Ashley Greenway. On the way home I stopped by the Summerville Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market for 2 Cookie Chick oatmeal raisin cookies. Ride on. ☮</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday May 23, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190523/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190523/</guid>
      <description>Looking forward to the Memorial Day Weekend. Not sure where but I know it will start early in the morning. Forecast high Memorial Day is 99℉.
Good commute today. On Stony Landing Rd this morning a rabbit was being squirrely and almost ended up in my spokes. It changed directions and disaster was averted.
Ride on. ☮
Old Berkeley High School being refurbished for Department of Education 
  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday May 21, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190521/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190521/</guid>
      <description>The Garmin reported a maximum temperature of 93℉. I believe it and prefer it to winter temperatures that is for sure. Good commute. No issues.
Ride on. ☮
   Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Moultrie West Dike</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190519/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190519/</guid>
      <description>Another absolutely gorgeous day in the Lowcountry. Not as hot as yesterday. Rode on the west dike of Lake Moultrie which was fantastic. On the peninsula that I frequent I was surprised by the number of trees down across the path. Several trees have been blown over since my last visit a couple of months ago.
On the way home I wanted to avoid Hwy 176 as much as possible. Rode through the new Volvo campus to hop on Hwy 27 but missed the turn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tricounty Triangle</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190518/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190518/</guid>
      <description>From stress to serenity. The sun, sweat, sights, scents, and sounds of the lowcountry make me smile.
Good ride through Berkeley, Charleston and Dorchester counties, capped off with a stop at the Summerville Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market for 2 Cookie Chick cookies. Ride on. ☮
 West Ashley Greenway Charleston SC 
West Ashley Greenway Charleston SC 
Ashley River Charleston SC 
 Relive &#39;Tricounty Triangle&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday May 16, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190516/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190516/</guid>
      <description>Everyone seemed to be a little more uptight today. I survived. Good commute. Ride on. ☮
   Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday May 14, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190514/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190514/</guid>
      <description>Today was dry and cooler. The 90&amp;rsquo;s ℉ are coming this weekend. Bring it on.
Started earlier than usual. I arrived at work 4:56 AM. Good commute. Ride on. ☮
   Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eutawville Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190511/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190511/</guid>
      <description>This century ride was less strenuous than last week&amp;rsquo;s century ride. Unfortunately I don&amp;rsquo;t know why. Was it my diet this week, my hydration, my fuel, my pace, the wind, the temperature or the phase of the moon. I wish I knew so I could replicate it.
The route to Eutawville was super nice except for the 10 miles on Hwy 176. I started at 5 AM to get off of Hwy 176 as early as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday May 9, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190509/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190509/</guid>
      <description>Morning routine is wake-up 4:30 AM, check radar, shower, dress, and cycle to work. This morning I pretended I didn&amp;rsquo;t see the radar. There was a line of rain headed my way. I chose to ride anyway. Just a little bit of rain on sections of the ride. No biggie. I kept thinking about my Good Friday ride to Myrtle Beach in the rain. Nothing will compare to that downpour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday May 7, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190507/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190507/</guid>
      <description>The local newspaper published a depressing story on how dangerous our state is for pedestrians and bicyclists. Not that I need a reminder. I question my sanity every day but continue to ride.
Had a nice chat with a neighborhood cyclist who just moved here from New Jersey. He works at Volvo and is a couple of years older than me. He was wondering where all the cyclists were. I told him about a couple of group rides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>McClellanville Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190504/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 14:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190504/</guid>
      <description>So nice to be back on Old Yeller. I always enjoy visiting McClellanville. They were having their shrimp festival. I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to partake but did a walk through and then saddled up for a tough ride home.
It is getting pretty warm. My pant legs were covered in salt. I need to start my rides earlier.
Ride on. ☮





  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday May 2, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190502/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190502/</guid>
      <description>The commute was good but afterwards was better. I picked up Old Yeller from Mike&amp;rsquo;s Bikes. I got a new Shimano Tiagra derailleur and a cable, for free. It was free because the derailleur hanger snapped Saturday and destroyed the derailleur. Mike&amp;rsquo;s Bikes has 30 day warranty on repair work. 👍 This is on top of the new cassette and chain from maintenance the week before. I paid for that work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday April 30, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190430/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190430/</guid>
      <description>Old Yeller is at the LBS getting a new derailleur after the hanger snapped Saturday. Riding the Giant Defy 3 again this week. Absolutely perfect weather today. Super nice!
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caw Caw Mechanical</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190427/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190427/</guid>
      <description>My Saturday was going so well. I started my ride late enough to drop by the Summerville Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market. Purchased two cookies from the Cookie Chick and stored them in my top tube bag for later. The ride to the Caw Caw Interpretive Center was great. Caw Caw was beautiful with not a cloud in the sky. After walking the park and eating an oatmeal cookie I continued my ride.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday April 25, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190425/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190425/</guid>
      <description>While on the ride home Mike&amp;rsquo;s Bike called to tell me my Giant Anyroad 1 was ready. After a quick shower I bolted down to Folly Rd to pick Old Yeller™ up and drop off the Defy to get the rear wheel trued.
Looking forward to hopping back on Old Yeller and its new drivetrain.
Oh yeah. Good commute today. More great weather.


  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday April 23, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190423/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190423/</guid>
      <description>Old Yeller is at the LBS getting a new drivetrain. Riding the Giant Defy 3 this week. Absolutely perfect weather today. Super nice!
  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summerville Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190421/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190421/</guid>
      <description>After a nice Saturday in Myrtle Beach it was time for the ride home. Was on the road at 5:04 AM but quickly turned back to get my phone. After that false start the ride was so much nicer than Friday&amp;rsquo;s ride. Very light traffic, no rain, and comfortable temperatures made for a chill ride. It turned overcast around 8:30 but the clouds broke up about 1.5 hours later. There was a persistent light headwind all the way home but hey I&amp;rsquo;m not complaining.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Myrtle Beach Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190419/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190419/</guid>
      <description>I knew I was going to get rained on but it was much heavier than anticipated. The rain started at mile 51 and got heavier and heavier. Going over the Waccamaw river bridge in Georgetown the rain felt like needles.
The wind for most of the ride was a favorable cross tailwind. On the easterly section of Saints Delight Rd and coming into Georgetown it was a stiff headwind.
Traffic on Hwy 17 from Georgetown to Myrtle Beach was heavy with plenty of water ponding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday April 16, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190416/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190416/</guid>
      <description>Beautiful blue sky on the way home.
This is the only day I&amp;rsquo;ll bike to work. I have Good Friday off so I&amp;rsquo;m biking to Myrtle Beach. The weather forecast is not looking good, rain and wind. At least it won&amp;rsquo;t be cold. I am mentally preparing for a tough ride. Hopefully it won&amp;rsquo;t be too bad. Ride on. ☮
  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lazy Sunday</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190414/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190414/</guid>
      <description>Watched Paris-Roubaix for 6 hours. Not very productive of me but it was a great race. Afterwards I braved the rain and wind for a short ride. The rain didn&amp;rsquo;t last long but the wind did.
Ran up on some dudes performing wheelies on their motorcycles behind a warehouse. They were having a blast. Ride on. ☮

   Relive &#39;Lunch Ride&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Loop Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190413/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190413/</guid>
      <description>It is starting to heat up. Need to acclimate to the rising temperatures and humidity. Will need to start my rides earlier to beat the heat of the day.
This was my 30th century ride since starting them in May of last year. This one was as tough as any. Somehow I had a headwind most of the ride even though the route was a loop. How is that possible? Perfect timing I guess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday April 11, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190411/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190411/</guid>
      <description>My black silicone watch band tore so I put on a band that matches my bike. High viz all the things!
Another beautiful day in the lowcountry for all outdoor activities. I was on the road at 4:13 AM. Very little traffic at that time in the morning and what traffic there is seems to be a little more laid-back. Did I mention how great the weather is. Good commute. Ride on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday April 9, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190409/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190409/</guid>
      <description>I was mentally prepared to get soaked today. Fortunate timing kept me dry for the most part. The ride to work was quick thanks to a tailwind. The ride home wasn&amp;rsquo;t too shabby either. Very enjoyable commute. Ride on. ☮
   Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gear</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/gear/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/gear/</guid>
      <description>Below is my gear list. Stuff I use on a regular basis. Links to product website when possible otherwise to Amazon.
Bikes  Giant Anyroad 1 2017 (main) AKA Old Yeller Giant Defy 3 2016 (backup) Dahon Speed Uno folding bike Unicycle  Bags  Topeak TopLoader Top Tube Bag Topeak Midloader Topeak Aero Wedge Topeak Backloader  Lights  Topeak Aero Combox (fork lights) Cygolite Hotshot Pro (rear light) Cycle Torch Shark 500 (head light) Ascher USB Rechargeable Bike Light Set (backup lights)  Computer  Garmin Edge 520 Wahoo Elemnt Bolt K-EDGE Garmin &amp;amp; GoPro Mount Pixel 3 phone  Camera and accessories  GoPro Hero 7 Anker PowerCore 13000 C Samsung 256GB Memory Card Sunlite foam handlebar grips OTTOLOCK bike lock (low security but light)  Tires and tubes  Continental Gatorskins 700x32c Specialized Armadillo 700x32c Continental 42mm Presta Valve Tube  Clothing high viz yellow when available  Gore jacket Gore helmet cap Gore overshoes Gore gloves Pearl Izumi Lobster Gloves Giro gloves Pearl iZUMi Elite Thermal Cycling Legwarmer Pearl iZUMi Men&amp;rsquo;s Escape Quest Cycling Shorts Owayo custom cycling jersey Clear safety glasses Tinted safety glasses  Maintenance  Topeak Joe Blow Sport III Floor Pump GODESON Tire Pressure Gauge Park Tool Chain Checker CC-3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shadowmoss</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190406/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190406/</guid>
      <description>A heavy fog rolled in this morning about the time I was leaving for a family gathering in the Shadowmoss subdivision. Rode through some rain showers on the way home.
I saved a 6 foot step ladder. On Hwy 165 two trucks blew past me. One was loaded with construction materials and ladders. Both trucks were probably going about 60 mph but the second one felt the need to go even faster so he gunned it to pass the first truck.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday April 4, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190404/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190404/</guid>
      <description>Caterpillars, caterpillars everywhere. The insects not the machines. Don&amp;rsquo;t know why they are on the road but I do my best to avoid them.
Today started at 3:30 AM. I was at my desk at 5 AM. Home by 5 PM. Great weather. The rain moves in tomorrow. Ride on. ☮
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Wednesday April 3, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190403/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190403/</guid>
      <description>I was thinking in the shower about bicycle commuting. It takes some effort.
 Get up 2 hours early to avoid morning traffic Take 2 showers instead of 1 Bicycle 32 miles (this is the good part) Risk life cycling with automobiles Battle the elements: wind, rain, heat, and cold  This morning was in the 30&amp;rsquo;s℉. I thought we were done with the 30&amp;rsquo;s. Oh well it was almost 70℉ on ride home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Moultrie Sunday March 31, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190331/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190331/</guid>
      <description>The headwind on the way home threw a web blanket on this ride. Brutal. The ride to and on the lake was great. Ride on. ☮


 Relive &#39;Lake Moultrie West Dike&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daniel Island Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190330/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190330/</guid>
      <description>Spring has sprung. It was chilly this morning but when the 9 o&amp;rsquo;clock hour arrived the temperature rose to the sweet spot.
Loving the new surface on Hwy 402. Cainhoy Rd is pretty scenic for the first half. Clements Ferry Rd, Hwy 41, and Hwy 17 are no fun. Daniel Island is OK if you like big huge fancy houses. I enjoyed the water scenes. A good day. Ride on. ☮</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday March 28, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190328/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190328/</guid>
      <description>Great weather on the ride home. Love this time of year or heck anytime of year that isn&amp;rsquo;t winter. Bring on the heat. Ride on. ☮
 
  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday March 26, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190326/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190326/</guid>
      <description>Couple of traffic accidents on Hwy 17-A on the way home. Hope everyone is OK. Ride on. ☮
   Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camera Set-up</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190324a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190324a/</guid>
      <description>This is the winning combination for an almost worry-free all-day video recording system.
 GoPro Hero 6 camera Anker 13,000mAh battery 256GB storage card K-Edge Garmin/GoPro combo mounted USB-C cable  The 13,000mAh battery eliminates GoPro battery swaps every hour. I put some a strip of Velcro on the bottom of the Anker battery to eliminate noise and wear against the top tube. It slides between my top tube bag and handlebar stem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colonial Dorchester State Historic Site</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190324/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190324/</guid>
      <description>Another beautiful day in the SC Lowcountry. Visited Colonial Dorchester State Historic Site




  Relive &#39;Colonial Dorchester State Historic Site&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angel Oak Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190323/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190323/</guid>
      <description>Great day for anything outdoors. Angel Oak was today&amp;rsquo;s destination. There were quite a few folks visiting the 500 year old tree. The ride was pleasant. I was yelled at just once. Everyone else was cool. Ride on. ☮


  Relive &#39;Angel Oak Century 💯&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday March 21, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190321/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190321/</guid>
      <description>Misty morning and clear afternoon. Pretty good commute if I forget about bubba babbling about getting off the road or end up in pieces. Jeez. 98% of automobile drivers behave properly. About once a day some dude, usually in a truck, has to tell me to get off the road. This time the passenger opened his door on Hwy 17-A and yelled. Stay classy bubba. Oh well. Ride on. ☮</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday March 19, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190319/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190319/</guid>
      <description>Cool, strong, headwind this morning had me contemplating why I ride my bike to work when I have a perfectly good electric vehicle. The tail/crosswind on the way home made me forget all about the struggle I had 11 hours earlier.
Had blast on the ride home. Spliced the slightly interesting video clips together with Kdenlive. Good commute. Ride on. ☮
   Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mulberry Plantation</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190317/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190317/</guid>
      <description>Nice spin on an overcast cool Sunday morning. Ride on. ☮


  Relive &#39;Mulberry&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Folly, Sullivan, IOP Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190316/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190316/</guid>
      <description>Cycled to and on Folly Beach, Sullivan&amp;rsquo;s Island, and the Isle of Palms (IOP). Had a nice tailwind to Folly. Tide was low. I was able to ride my bike on the beach. Good number of folks were enjoying the beach but still a little chilly to enjoy the water.
Great day on the saddle. Ride on. ☮
  Photo album 
 Relive &#39;Folly, Sullivan, IOP Century 💯&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday March 14, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190314/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190314/</guid>
      <description>I have named my Priority 600 The Beast. It is big, heavy, and hard to move. Don&amp;rsquo;t know if it was tired legs, headwind, The Beast or all of those things that made the ride home tough.
Regardless, I survived. Ride on. ☮
   Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday March 12, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190312/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190312/</guid>
      <description>Beautiful weather today made for an enjoyable commute. Except for bubba yelling at me to get off the f&amp;rsquo;ing road at Black Tom Rd &amp;amp; Hwy 17-A intersection it was a chill ride home.
My Anker 10,000mAh battery only lasted about 5 months. I&amp;rsquo;ve been attempting to charge it for 3 days without luck. The way I mount it on my bike it catches sweat so the connectors are corroded. Probably will buy another and flip it upside down this time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Moultrie West Dike</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190310/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190310/</guid>
      <description>Tree pollen is everywhere. On long straight roads you can see the wind blowing pollen clouds across the road.
Had a scare entering Black Tom Rd off the rocks. My bike was not changing gears properly. Turned out the chain came off derailleur jockey wheel.
Except for the pollen the weather is perfect. Good ride on the Lake Moultrie West Dike. Ride on. ☮



  Relive &#39;Lake Moultrie West Dike&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walterboro Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190309/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190309/</guid>
      <description>Had a little bit of rain and a rainbow at the start but the rain moved on and was followed by sunshine and mild temperatures.
The Hwy 17-A Avoidance route to Walterboro gets an A+ for light traffic and scenery but a C- for road surface. The asphalt was rippled, dimpled, cracked, and full of pot holes. Can&amp;rsquo;t have everything.
The Walterboro Wildlife Sanctuary was a nice treat. Good trails and boardwalks over cypress swamps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday March 7, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190307/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190307/</guid>
      <description>Chilly start. Temperatures were in the twenties this morning. Super nice this afternoon. Clear blues skies and mild temperatures.
This is the second commute on my Priority 600 with Pinion gearbox. While I&amp;rsquo;m riding the 600 I keep bemoaning the resistance I feel compared to Old Yeller. The commute takes about 5 minutes longer on the 600. I need to get over the added weight and resistance. Riding to lunch and dinner on the 600 is perfect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rockville Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190303/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190303/</guid>
      <description>Ride Summary  Mile 40 puncture from small wire Pulled out the wire with my teeth Mile 50 air horned by a couple of bubbas Mile 60 chased by dogs Mile 70 water cage weld snapped Mile 96 car right turned in front of me at 21 mph (no contact)  The ride started out in a damp fog. After I got through Charleston the wind was mostly at my back which was super nice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cruising Summerville March 2, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190302/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190302/</guid>
      <description>Took the Priority 600 out for a short slow spin around Summerville. Increased the air pressure on 650b tires from 40 to 60 PSI. Strange that there isn&amp;rsquo;t any inflation recommendation printed on the tire. Didn&amp;rsquo;t make much of an improvement in rolling resistance. Ride is not as comfy so I may revert to 40 PSI.
Also rode it to Which Wich for a belly wedge. Pretty fun bike. Not the fastest or lightest bike but still pretty fun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Friday March 1, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190301/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 23:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190301/</guid>
      <description>Intrigued at the prospect of fewer drivetrain issues I bought a Priority 600 with a Pinion gearbox. Assembled last night and rode to work today. Initial reaction is it is a smooth ride but slow. The rolling resistance with the big 650b tires is noticeable as well as the resistance of the belt drive. At this point I don&amp;rsquo;t see it replacing Old Yeller. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure I&amp;rsquo;m going to get rid of the Defy 3 though.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday February 26, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190226/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190226/</guid>
      <description>Breaking news. Riding a bike is fun. It is really fun when you have a tailwind. Had a blast on the commute home. Good commute.
Ride on. ☮

  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fresh Tarmac Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190223/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190223/</guid>
      <description>Mist and fog had me wet and cold on the first third of the ride. The air dried as the morning progressed even though it looked like it could rain at any moment.
The last time I rode Hwy 402 the road surface was in terrible shape. They have since resurfaced the road. It is smooth asphalt with a nice size shoulder. There are a couple of sections that have already been repaired.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bent Derailleur Hanger Repaired</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190221/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190221/</guid>
      <description>Old Yeller fell over after Tuesday&amp;rsquo;s commute. Taking a photo and the wind knocked it over bending the derailleur hanger. Took a 3 hour lunch to Mike&amp;rsquo;s Bikes on Folly Rd. They had about 50 hangers in stock but none fit mine. The technician used a derailleur hanger alignment gauge to whip it back in to shape. He also replace a jockey wheel. I finished up the day at work and went for an evening ride.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday February 19, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190219/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190219/</guid>
      <description>The low temperature on the PM commute (41℉) was cooler than the AM commute (44℉). The wind was kicking all day. Headwind on the AM ride and a tailwind on the way home. Difference of 14 minutes. Always happy with a sub 50 minute commute. 1:02:53 vs 49:04 moving time.
Became an East Coast Greenway Alliance member today. I would love to safely cycle from Charleston to Beaufort one day. 🤞</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gators and Armadillos</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190217/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190217/</guid>
      <description>While repairing my two punctures yesterday I realized it was time for new tires. The Specialized Armadillo tires had a few cuts, holes and dry rot. I replaced them with Continental GatorSkin DuraSkin tires. There is nothing wrong with the Specialized Armadillo brand. It was just more convenient and quicker to add the Gatorskins to my Amazon cart instead of going to Specialized&amp;rsquo;s website.
I drove the Bolt EV back to the location of my first puncture yesterday to do some investigating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worst Century Best Human Ever 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190216/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190216/</guid>
      <description>Double puncture. The first at mile 81 the second at mile 82. Both were staples in the rear tire. On the first puncture I replaced the tube. On the second I used a patch. My mini pump was pretty much useless. I was near a pay pump on the first one and got it rideable. On the second I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get enough air in it to ride so I started walking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Friday February 15, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190215/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190215/</guid>
      <description>Southeastern Wildlife Exposition (SEWE) started today. I think I&amp;rsquo;ll stay clear of downtown Charleston tomorrow.
Mild winter continues. Another good commute.
Another restaurant chain in Summerville, Culver&amp;rsquo;s. Never eaten at one. Glanced at the menu. Meh. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll be frequenting Culver&amp;rsquo;s.
Ride on.
   Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday February 12, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190212/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190212/</guid>
      <description>Happy to be riding Old Yeller again. Much more comfortable than the Defy 3. Speaking of which I picked up the Defy 3 from my LBS yesterday. They installed a new drive train and new tires. It now has 28&amp;rsquo;s instead of 25&amp;rsquo;s so it should be a little more comfortable.
Good commute today. Foggy this morning. Warm and windy on the way home. Ride on.
  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bike Swap</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190209/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190209/</guid>
      <description>The last I heard from my LBS was that it might be Monday before the parts arrive for my Giant Anyroad 1 bicycle. I cycled to Mike&amp;rsquo;s Bikes on the Giant Defy 3 just to check on the Anyroad 1. Much to my surprise and delight Old Yeller was on the rack getting some finishes touches. I was smiling ear to ear. As much as I appreciate having a backup bike it is no where near as comfortable and fun to ride as my primary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday February 7, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190207/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190207/</guid>
      <description>Another warm day. 75℉ on the ride home with a stiff head wind. Good commute on the Defy 3. Ride on.
My LBS called about Old Yeller. The rear brake caliper is weak. They are going to replace it but not with a stock Giant caliper. Parts are ordered. The tech said they might be in tomorrow. I&amp;rsquo;m betting it will be Monday. These extended maintenance events are frustrating.
  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Wednesday February 6, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190206/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190206/</guid>
      <description>Another gorgeous day. Another day without Old Yeller. Good commute on the Defy 3. Ride on.

  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday February 5, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190205/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190205/</guid>
      <description>Absolutely perfect weather. Highs in the 70&amp;rsquo;s and clear blue sky. What a way to start the Year of the Pig.
I almost ran over a rabbit. One hopped out in front of me on Hwy 17-A. I missed it by inches. I didn&amp;rsquo;t hear a thud so I assume and hope it got across the highway safely.
Good commute. Lets do it again tomorrow. Ride on.

  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday January 29, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190129/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190129/</guid>
      <description>The weather forecast called for rain around 5PM which would have been perfect if I left by 4PM. By lunch time I knew the rain was going to be here sooner than that. I left work a couple hours early to beat the rain. Drizzled most of the way home but no downpour. Stiff headwind accompanied the drizzle. Not one of my best commutes.
Thursday&amp;rsquo;s forecast calls for a low of 28℉.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solar Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190126/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190126/</guid>
      <description>A mostly clear blue sky made this winter century possible. If it had been overcast I would have cut this ride short. Good day in the saddle.
When you ride 100 miles you can eat what you want. Today I wanted a Veggie Lover Pizza and a beer.
 Relive &#39;Solar Century 💯&#39;  


 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Friday January 25, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190125/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190125/</guid>
      <description>32℉ this morning. 48℉ and mostly sunny on the way home. Good commute.
Called Mike&amp;rsquo;s Bikes about my creaking steering. They are ordering parts and will call me when they are in to try to minimize my down time. I appreciate that.
  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Wednesday January 23, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190123/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190123/</guid>
      <description>A bit of rain and headwind on the way home but at least it was warm. Good commute.
Schedule is off this week due to Monday&amp;rsquo;s holiday. Tomorrow morning&amp;rsquo;s forecast is rain with wind gusts of 57 mph so I guess I&amp;rsquo;ll drive the Bolt EV. Friday is looking good though. Ride on.
  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Martin Luther King Jr Day</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190121/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 13:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190121/</guid>
      <description>Holiday ride. I missed the Nexton TT segment KOM by 14 seconds. If I&amp;rsquo;d only pushed a little harder. Oh well.
Kind of chilly for this southern boy. At least the sun was shining. Not a cloud in the sky. Average temperature of 39°F.
Called my local bike shop about my steering. When I turn it has a creak. The bearings are probably rusty, warn and due for replacement. The owner said I&amp;rsquo;ll need to bring the bike in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I want my data</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190120/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190120/</guid>
      <description>I checked my chain for wear with my Park Tool Chain Checker CC-3.2. It is past .75% wear. Time for a new one.
How many miles do I have on this chain? Seems like a simple question. Unfortunately Garmin doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide a way to export my data. I signed-up with VeloViewer which is a 3rd party analysis website. The annual pro subscription is $13.40 USD. I&amp;rsquo;m impressed so far. They have some nice tools, charts, and most importantly ability to export all my activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Georgetown Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190119/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190119/</guid>
      <description>This ride was on my bucket list. Wanted to make a round trip to Georgetown SC from Summerville SC. Knocked it off the list today. My mother&amp;rsquo;s family is from Georgetown and it holds a special place in my heart and brain. I have many wonderful childhood memories in Georgetown. Now I&amp;rsquo;ve added one more.
Great average temperature of 54℉. It was mostly cloudy. Good to see the sun every now and again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday January 17, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190117/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190117/</guid>
      <description>According to my Garmin it was 26℉ this morning and 64℉ on the way home. Guess which segment I enjoyed more?
On the way home I was passed, at a high rate of speed, by a couple of dozen police vehicles with sirens blaring. They were mostly Berkeley County Sheriff vehicles. The others were unmarked. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what was going down but I assume it was pretty serious.
Looking forward to the 3 day weekend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday January 15, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190115/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190115/</guid>
      <description>Another overcast chilly January day. Low of 33°F this morning. The traffic lights were not kind this morning. I was stopped by every one of them heading out of Summerville. It is hard to stay warm when you are waiting on traffic signals.
Winds were calm which was welcomed.
Ride on.
  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gloom Factor 9</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190113/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190113/</guid>
      <description>Waited for the rain to end. Wasn&amp;rsquo;t looking forward to today&amp;rsquo;s ride but went anyway. As usual, I&amp;rsquo;m glad I did. Typical January day with an overcast sky and cool temperatures hovering around 40℉. Hope next weekend is better.
 Relive &#39;Gloom Factor 9&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday January 10, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190110/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190110/</guid>
      <description>The heatwave had to end sometime, unfortunately. Garmin registered 30.2°F for the minimum during the morning commute. The sun was shining and a tailwind was blowing on the way home. Pretty good commute for January. Ride on.
   Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strava Year In Sport 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190109/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 19:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190109/</guid>
      <description>I have mixed feelings. Don&amp;rsquo;t know whether to feel a level of accomplishment or be embarrassed. Spent about 500 hours or 20 days in 2018 on my bicycle. Those 8.5 thousand miles were mostly fun so what the hay.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday January 8, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190108/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190108/</guid>
      <description>Another great day in the South Carolina Lowcountry. No drama commute. Ride on.
   Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Francis Marion National Forest Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190106/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190106/</guid>
      <description>Today&amp;rsquo;s century ride was perfect. I even had a little energy left at the end. I&amp;rsquo;m usually spent and struggling by mile 80. I&amp;rsquo;ll attribute feeling good all the way to the end to:
 An abundance of sunshine A lack of headwinds An early start Cool temperatures Nutrition (although I didn&amp;rsquo;t do anything different)  I went to bed last night excited that today was going to be awesome. I was not disappointed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>King of the Mountain</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190105/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190105/</guid>
      <description>Snagged the Red Bay Rd KOM with the help of a strong tailwind.
So nice to see the sun again. Looking forward to tomorrow. More sun, less wind, and more miles.
  Strava KOM Android Screenshot
  Bicycle - Ashley River - Herbert H Jessen Public Boat Landing
 Sawmill Branch Canal Trail washed out
 Ashley River - Herbert H Jessen Public Boat Landing
 Relive &#39;Ashley River&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday January 3, 2019</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190103/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190103/</guid>
      <description>One year ago today we were getting snowed on. It couldn&amp;rsquo;t be further from that today. Maximum temperature was 70 ℉. Sweet.
Left the apartment this morning with two left hand gloves. Didn&amp;rsquo;t bother to go back. No gloves necessary. The ride home was sloppy. Rained periodically throughout the day. No rain on the way home though. Ride on!
  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edisto Beach Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190101/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 14:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190101/</guid>
      <description>What a way to start off the new year. A century ride to the beach with temperatures in the 70&amp;rsquo;s °F. Crazy weather and I love it.
The route to Edisto Beach is fairly scenic if you can ignore the roadside litter. There are cypress swamps, marshes, beautiful oak trees, a variety of birds and of course there is the ocean.
Good day on the saddle.
Photo album
  Relive &#39;Edisto Beach Century 💯&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fog Filled Lake Moultrie</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181230/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 19:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181230/</guid>
      <description>I thought I was going to take the day off the bike but I got the itch and had to scratch it.
Ride started at 4 PM which put me riding home in the dark. Around the lake it was foggy and misty. I startled several white tailed deer below the dike. They scurried off into the woods. The dike was pretty muddy and slow going in spots. The wind was favorable for the most part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bushy Park</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181229/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181229/</guid>
      <description>Other than the nail through the tire towards the end of the ride it was all good. Great temperatures for late December, 57°F average.
 Nail through rear tire - Hwy 78
 Bike on Bushy Park pier
 Could only get 20 PSI with the mini pump.
  Relive &#39;Bushy Park&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kingstree Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181224/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181224/</guid>
      <description>All century rides are tough but the head winds on the way to Kingstree made this one especially challenging. Considered cutting my ride short more than once. Glad I toughed it out. Was concerned about getting home before the temperatures started dropping. Towards the end of a century it is hard to keep your body temperature up since you don&amp;rsquo;t have the energy but it worked out on this ride. Arrived home before 5 PM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunny Sunday Charleston Loop</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181223/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181223/</guid>
      <description>Beautiful blue sky, pleasant temperatures and a drama free ride. What&amp;rsquo;s not to love?
That moment in almost every long ride when I realize how awesome the world is and how lucky I am to be riding my bike in it. 👍 Today it was when I turned onto South Aviation Ave and saw how blue the sky was over the airport runways.
 Bike on Charleston Battery
 Arthur Ravenel Jr bridge</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunny Saturday in Summerville</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181222/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2018 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181222/</guid>
      <description>I had a flat tire a couple of weeks ago. The replacement tube had a slow leak. I missed something. Put the tube in water to find the leak and position me to the area on the tire to search for the culprit.
Found a tiny wire had penetrated the tire and into the tube.

I replaced the front disk brake pads last week and they are really grippy so I decided to replace the rear brake pads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Friday December 21, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181221/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181221/</guid>
      <description>The wind was whipping today nearly knocking me over a few times.
Even with an awesome tailwind I can&amp;rsquo;t snag a KOM. There are Strava 3 segments on the way to work. I am 2nd, 3rd, and 4th on the all time rankings. I thought today I might get my first KOM but I was still 34 seconds slower than the leader on the smaller of the 3 segments. Oh well, the ride to work was a lot of fun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday December 18, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181218/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181218/</guid>
      <description>Thought more than once about driving to work but saddled up. I&amp;rsquo;m glad I did. Another good commute in the books.
   Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunshine baby, sunshine!</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181216/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181216/</guid>
      <description>Beautiful day for a ride to Lake Moultrie. Clear blue skies with an average temperature of 54.9 °F.
Before the ride I had a little maintenance to do. Replaced the front disc brake pads. They were screeching on the ride home yesterday. The new pads are super grippy. Love &amp;lsquo;em. Degreased and lubed the chain. Inflated my 700x32c tires to 80 PSI. I had a flat yesterday and the little hand pump can only do so much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BFC 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181215/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181215/</guid>
      <description>Today was good, real good. I put some miles on my bike, temperatures were in the 60&amp;rsquo;s ℉, and I celebrated Christmas with my family. Perfect
Photo album
  Relive &#39;Ride to BFC&#39;  Relive &#39;Ride from BFC&#39;   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday December 13, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181213/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181213/</guid>
      <description>Nothing like a bike ride to relieve work place stress. The ride home was just what the doctor ordered. Ride on.
   Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday December 11, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181211/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181211/</guid>
      <description>Wet and chilly (34°F) ride to work. Dry and sunny ride home.
I was on the road by 4:46 AM. Waking up so early is tough but totally worth missing rush hour traffic. So much safer and less stressful. Ride on.
   Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After the Rain</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181209/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181209/</guid>
      <description>For the second weekend in a row it rained and rained some more. It stopped around 3 PM today allowing me to squeeze in a ride. The Garmin says the average temperature was 35.8°F. Where does it come up with these temperatures? It was in the low 40&amp;rsquo;s. The wind was blowing mostly favorably.
7,874 miles logged in 2018. I want to hit 8k before the year ends. That shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a problem as long as the weather cooperates just a little.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drain the Novocaine</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181207/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181207/</guid>
      <description>Broke tooth number 4 - 2nd bicuspid (2nd premolar) Wednesday night. Dentist repaired it this morning. Took a short ride to expedite wearing off the numbness.
  Relive &#39;Drain the Novocaine&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday December 4, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181204/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181204/</guid>
      <description>There was a down power line across Hwy 17-A this morning. Firemen secured the area. I took a detour onto Horseshoe Rd.
On the commute home I got a work alarm had to deal with. Not a very smooth commute either way. Oh well. The weather was good.
  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday November 29, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181129/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181129/</guid>
      <description>Garmin computer reported a low of 27°F and an average of 29°F on the commute this morning. I believe it. I did not enjoy the AM ride. The PM ride was much better. The temperatures are on the rise over the new few days but unfortunately so is the chance of rain.
  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday November 27, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181127/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181127/</guid>
      <description>Garmin computer reported a low of 32°F on the commute this morning. I kinda doubt that. I&amp;rsquo;m thinking it was mid to upper 30&amp;rsquo;s. Average temperature on the way home was 41°F. Thursday morning is forecasted to be in the upper 20&amp;rsquo;s. We&amp;rsquo;ll see if I brave that commute.
  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IOP Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181124/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181124/</guid>
      <description>It rained before I got on the road and it looked like it was going to be a dreary wet day. Thankfully I was deceived. There was a 3 hour period of weather perfection. The sun was shining and temperatures topped out at 71°F. It was so nice. I removed my sleeves from my jacket and took off my gloves at the beach. When I hit North Charleston the clouds returned along with some wind so I put the sleeves and gloves back on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181122/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181122/</guid>
      <description>I am thankful for family, friends, health, employment, animals, earth and bicycles. Ride on.
 Relive &#39;Thanksgiving&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday November 20, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181120/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181120/</guid>
      <description>Moncks Corner put out there Christmas decorations just in time for Thanksgiving.
Commute was good. Traffic was a smidgen lighter due to the upcoming holiday. I have a 4 day weekend. Too bad the best weather day is Thanksgiving day. I&amp;rsquo;ll squeeze in some miles between the rain showers.
New lighter colored carpet was installed in my place of employment. I purchased a mat for my office where I park my bike in the bikehand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marion Moultrie Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181118/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181118/</guid>
      <description>Rode a section of dike on both Lake Marion and Lake Moultrie. Discovered dramatically that the Lake Marion dam is closed to the public. Santee Cooper is South Carolina&amp;rsquo;s state-owned electric and water utility that runs the dam. I was stopped by a Santee Cooper employee and told to turn around. I begged and pleaded for him to let me slide fearing that I may not have the fitness to tackle a 150 mile ride.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley River</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181117/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181117/</guid>
      <description>Planning on riding a century tomorrow so today&amp;rsquo;s ride was a short one. This is my second ride with the new bike fit. So far, so good. The real test will be tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s attempt at a century ride.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Wednesday November 14, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181114/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181114/</guid>
      <description>This must be what riding a penny-farthing feels like. My new bike fit has me higher and more upright. Felt like my quadriceps were working harder today. So far, so good.
Windy day. Head wind on the way to work and tail wind on the way home. 16.4 MPH vs 21.3 MPH. Enjoyed the ride home 100 times more than the ride to work. There was rain to our northwest and offshore but not a drop in Moncks Corner or Summerville.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bike Fit and Maintenance</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181113/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181113/</guid>
      <description>Matty Floyd of Affordabike in Charleston performed a bike fit on me. First bike fit I&amp;rsquo;ve had. It was something I felt I should do at least once so I took the day off to get it done. I can&amp;rsquo;t remember the last time I took a day off.
Matty with the help of the GURU Dynamic Fit Unit made some changes to my fit. Raised my seat post, installed a new stem, adjusted by hoods, etc&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m sitting allot higher on the Giant Anyroad 1 bicycle now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edge of America Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181111/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181111/</guid>
      <description>Temperatures min/avg/max 37.4°F / 50.6°F / 57.2°F. Windy but mostly in my favor. Had a quick easy ride to Charleston and then to Folly Beach. I prepared myself mentally for a headwind on the ride home but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t as bad as expected. Great day in the saddle.
 Photo album
Relive &#39;Edge of America Century 💯&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bonneau</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181110/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181110/</guid>
      <description>Overcast, windy and cool. Rode up to Bonneau and took the Lake Moultrie dike back. To cap off the ride I visited the Cookie Chick at the Summerville Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market. Yummy.
 Photo album</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday November 1, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181101/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181101/</guid>
      <description>Mild temperatures. Winds kicking as a cold front approaches. Good commute.
  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday October 30, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181030/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181030/</guid>
      <description>42.8°F to start the day and 64.4°F at the finish. Good commute. Ride on.
  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kiawah Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181028/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181028/</guid>
      <description>Temperatures min/avg/max 41.0°F / 56.7°F / 69.8°F. Clear blue skies and light winds. First time cycling to Kiawah Island. Maybank Rd is fairly safe, Bohicket Rd not so much. Once you get to Kiawah there are paved bike paths. Their novelty wore thin and I took the road on the way out of Kiawah. I&amp;rsquo;m not a big fan of golf courses and huge houses which is what Kiawah is all about but the ride was nice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday October 25, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181025/</guid>
      <description>Low temperature this morning was 41.0 °F. I donned my Gore jacket, Gore gloves, and Five Ten MTB shoes. All good.
Looking forward to rolling into the weekend. Tomorrow is looking like a rainy day. Saturday and Sunday should be rain free. Ride on.
  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday October 23, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181023/</guid>
      <description>Nothing special about today&amp;rsquo;s commute. I was feeling cool air blowing into my shoe this morning. I guess it about time for some new ones. I have some Five Ten MTB bike shoes that have a nice hard sole but they are heavy. I may give them another try.
  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jamestown Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 15:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181021/</guid>
      <description>48.2 °F at the start with a stiff headwind. I thought more than once about turning around in Moncks Corner. I&amp;rsquo;m glad I didn&amp;rsquo;t. The middle section of the ride was good. Warmed up into the 60&amp;rsquo;s with mostly a tail wind. Rode some gravel, rock, and mud on Tiger Corner Rd in the Francis Marion Forest. The headwinds returned once I got through Charleston. The temperature dropped a little as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday October 18, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181018/</guid>
      <description>Cold front was rolling in this morning. Headwinds blow. The commute home was sweet. Wind assisted personal best of 44:24 moving time and an average speed 21.9 mi/h.
  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday October 16, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181016/</guid>
      <description>Maximum temperature on the commute home was 84.2 °F according to Garmin. I think it was closer to 90 °F. All I know for sure is the weather is awesome for mid October. More of this please!
  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ACE Basin Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181013/</guid>
      <description>A friend suggested I visit the ACE Basin so that is what I did. I had not been there since 2014. To my delight it hasn&amp;rsquo;t changed a bit.
Not a cloud in the sky all day long. I donned arm warmers and gloves this morning. It was a good decision. Temperature started at 50.0 °F and maxed out at 84.2 °F according to Garmin.
A few new-to-me roads in today&amp;rsquo;s route.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Friday October 12, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181012/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181012/</guid>
      <description>Thursday tropical storm Michael was passing to the west of us. I contemplated riding to perhaps get a tail wind assisted KOM but I came to my senses. I drove my EV to work yesterday and cycled today.
55.4 °F was the low temperature during my AM commute. I don&amp;rsquo;t like what is coming. I don&amp;rsquo;t like it at all. I rather sweat than freeze any day. It won&amp;rsquo;t be long before the Gore jacket and gloves are needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday October 9, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181009/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181009/</guid>
      <description>Fender bender at Carnes Crossroads intersection caused a traffic jam for what seemed like more than a mile on Hwy 17-A. Good day to be on two wheels.
   Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Santee National Wildlife Refuge Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181006/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181006/</guid>
      <description>This ride had a little of everything. There was rain at the start, gravel trails, muddy trails, sandy trails, overgrown trails, good tarmac, terrible tarmac, a fenced off bridge, and an illegal ride across Lake Marion on I-95. What a day.
Photo album
 Relive &#39;Santee National Wildlife Refuge Century&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday October 4, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181004/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181004/</guid>
      <description>Nice weather. Productive week at work so far. Two good commutes and 64 miles logged. Looking forward to the weekend. Not sure where I&amp;rsquo;m riding but I&amp;rsquo;m riding.
Upgraded my Garmin 520 to version 12.80. It wiped out my settings. Most importantly my sensors. I had to set the sensors up again. Software upgrades should not wipe out user settings. First world problems.
Rock on!

  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday October 2, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181002/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181002/</guid>
      <description>For what I assume was for Fire Prevention Week Whitesville FD was hanging old glory above Hwy 17-A on the Moncks Corner side of Carnes Crossroads. Thank-you fire fighters!
Glad I was riding my bike. Automobile traffic was a CF. Good commute.

  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Moultrie and Bushy Park</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180930/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 21:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180930/</guid>
      <description>My chain was dry from yesterday&amp;rsquo;s rainy ride. A head wind was kicking my butt. I contemplating abandoning today&amp;rsquo;s ride but I convinced myself to at least buy some oil for the chain. I ran into Publix at Cane Bay for some oil. All they had were quart bottles of automobile oil. I bought one and oiled the chain. Things started to pick up. My chain was quiet, the wind was subsiding, and my energy level was on the rise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charleston Triangle September 29, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180929/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180929/</guid>
      <description>Stormy Saturday. I avoided the rain until mile 47. Light showers were on and off the rest of the way home.
Summer is over and days are shorter. I no longer need to start so early. Old habits die hard. I woke up at 3 AM and was on the road at 4:10 AM. The most scenic sections of my ride, Charleston Battery and West Ashley Greenway, were in the dark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Wednesday September 26, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180926/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180926/</guid>
      <description>Good temperatures, sunny skies, and tolerable traffic make for a good commute.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>McClellanville Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180923/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180923/</guid>
      <description>Humans are awesome. There are so many cyclists that inspire me. Lael Wilcox is the latest that touched me. Last night I watched a mini documentary on her Navad 1000 Across Switzerland race. It gave me the confidence to knock out today&amp;rsquo;s ride.
I woke up at 3 AM and was on the road by 4:18 AM. Took a couple of wrong turns in Bethera. It was still dark and the route was new to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday September 20, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180920/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180920/</guid>
      <description>Grant Ford wrote Morning Trek for me in return for a small donation towards his writing projects. I&amp;rsquo;m happy with my return on investment. It captures some of the joys of cycling.
#Morning Trek A breath of cool air, the smell of pavement entrance and entice the morning senses with freedom from the daily enslavement of cars and trucks and motorized fences. With the strength of will, the body exerts upon the gears of destiny and fate to consume the miles combustion preverts; you breathe the clean air, your spirit to sate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday September 18, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180918/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180918/</guid>
      <description>It was pouring down rain around 4 AM. I went back to sleep and when I awoke at 5 AM the rain had stopped. I checked RadarScope. There were storms to the south and to the north but nothing between Summerville and Moncks Corner so I stuck to my plan. The road was wet but not a drop of rain fell on me. RadarScope is awesome. Good ride to work. A couple of hours later my back tire went flat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charleston Ride</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180916/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180916/</guid>
      <description>Hopefully Florence was the only tropical storm this year. We dodged another bullet.
Nice breezy ride to Charleston on the Giant Defy 3. Was hoping to drop off Old Yeller at Mike&amp;rsquo;s Bikes today but they aren&amp;rsquo;t answering the phone. They may not be open.



 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cure for Cabin Fever</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180914/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180914/</guid>
      <description>My employer closed the offices today. Didn&amp;rsquo;t take long for cabin fever to infect me. Went for a ride keeping close to home in case Florence sped up. When you are one with the wind it is an exhilarating feeling. When the wind is in your face it isn&amp;rsquo;t much fun.
I started out on Old Yeller but her crank is creaking really bad. Must have a shard or damaged bearings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday September 11, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180911/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180911/</guid>
      <description>Traffic was light with Hurricane Florence heading towards the southeastern and mid-Atlantic United States. I wish the traffic was this light everyday.
The cover photo for today&amp;rsquo;s log was taken on the way back from dinner. It is I-26 exit 199 with all lanes heading west to Columbia SC. Lane reversals started at noon September 11, 2018.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bee City Zoo</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180908/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180908/</guid>
      <description>Biked to Bee City Zoo on some roads I had not traveled. The route limited the amount of time spent on busy two lane highways 78 &amp;amp; 61. Campbell Thickett Road was the most interesting. It turns into a clay gravel road. One the roughest roads I&amp;rsquo;ve cycled. Plenty of craters and the clay is harder than concrete.
Bee City Zoo has a wide variety of animals. Everything appeared well maintained.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday September 6, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180906/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180906/</guid>
      <description>Biked to work just one day this week due to me being a light weight after my Labor Day century ride. I&amp;rsquo;ll get two commutes next week. ☮
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labor Day Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180903/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180903/</guid>
      <description>First time riding on the Lake Marion dike and The Santee Dam. Took me a little while to find the gate to the dike. It was still dark when I arrived. I ended up at Wilson&amp;rsquo;s landing which is several miles from where I needed to be. The entrance to the dike is a yellow gate behind a Santee Cooper garage to the right of the Harry&amp;rsquo;s Fish Camp entrance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tri-County Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180901/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180901/</guid>
      <description>Woke up around 3 AM and was on the road at 4:40 AM. From Summerville I rode through Moncks Corner, Bonneau, St Stephen, Pineville, Cross, Holly Hill, and Harleyville. It was a little chilly this morning until the sun came up. Not looking forward to summer ending.
I think I fueled too much too quickly. My stomach was a little sore.
At the end of my ride I rode by the Summerville Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market for some Cookie Chick cookies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Thursday August 30, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180830/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180830/</guid>
      <description>There was a fatal automobile accident at the Black Tom Rd and Hwy 17-A intersection this morning. Rest in ☮. I reached the scene about 20 minutes afterwards. The police had the intersection taped off. All traffic was diverted. I was able to cycle around the barrier and get to work.
My Topeak backloader bag was not strapped as tight as it should have been and sounded like a frog for most of the AM commute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Tuesday August 28, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180828/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180828/</guid>
      <description>Good work commute. Already dreaming about where I&amp;rsquo;ll ride over the upcoming Labor Day holiday three day weekend.

  Relive &#39;Commute AM&#39;  Relive &#39;Commute PM&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Folly Beach Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180825/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180825/</guid>
      <description>Woke up around 3 AM and was on the road at 4:18 AM. Nice tail wind for 70 miles. Tough head wind on the last leg of the ride. Shifting on Old Yeller is a little slow but other than that she is riding like a champ. Good day in the saddle.
 Photo album
Relive &#39;Folly Beach Century&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180823/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180823/</guid>
      <description>Cycling yields quality spirits. I am happy with the way the photo in front of Watkins Package Store developed. 📷 It was a split decision to take a photo here. So much so I almost wipe out when I turned off the road into a sand mound. Crisis averted and photo snapped.
Up at 5 AM and pedaling by 5:21 AM. Had a head wind on the way to work and a tail on the way home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180821/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180821/</guid>
      <description>Made it to work in 46 minutes thanks to a tail wind. The wind didn&amp;rsquo;t shift during the day so I had a stiff head wind on the way home. The wind giveth and taketh away.
I haven&amp;rsquo;t commuted on the bike lately in lieu of evening rides. This commute was a little different in that I carried my clothes to work in my Topeak Backloader bag. Normally I store clothes in my office when I drive the EV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Well, I&#39;m a steamroller, baby ♪♫♬</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180819/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 19:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180819/</guid>
      <description>Ran into some rain on the last 3rd of Sunday&amp;rsquo;s ride. Cypress Gardens Rd in under repair. There were cones down the center of the road and made it difficult for cars and trucks to pass me. I got off the road at Lazy Hill Rd so the long line of cars could get in front of me.
First two thirds of the ride were pretty chill. I&amp;rsquo;ll take it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Middleton Place Gardens</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180818/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 08:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180818/</guid>
      <description>Woke up before 3 AM and was on the road by 4:10 AM. Rode down to Charleston and took Highway 61 home. I have taken Highway 61 only one other time, Thanksgiving day 2017. It is not a good road for cycling. It is very scenic but dangerously narrow. Today&amp;rsquo;s trip up Highway 61 was before 7 AM and traffic was light. I counted only 24 automobiles passed me in the lane I was traveling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday Evening Ride</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180814/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 17:21:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180814/</guid>
      <description>A pretty strong thunderstorm rolled through the area. After the rain quit the temperatures really dropped. The Garmin 520 recorded a low temperature of 66.2 °F and I believe it. I knew this ride would be short because I have a work thing tonight starting at 10 PM. I tried to keep the effort high. My average cadence was 90 rpm with a maximum cadence of 112 rpm. Good enough for a 57 year old.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday Afternoon Ride</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180812/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 17:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180812/</guid>
      <description>Almost bit off more than I could chew. My intention was to knock out an easy 30 mile ride under overcast skies. A few minutes into the ride the clouds cleared and the heat returned. I finished up with 56 miles. After yesterday&amp;rsquo;s century ride I was pretty whipped. The end of today&amp;rsquo;s ride was tough going.
 Relive &#39;Sunday Afternoon Ride&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Century Saturday 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180811/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 11:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180811/</guid>
      <description>This is my 4th weekend century in a row. I&amp;rsquo;m getting to the point if I don&amp;rsquo;t ride 100 miles I feel lazy.
Today&amp;rsquo;s ride started at 4:57 AM. Nice to have the roads all to myself for a while. There was a summer shower in West Ashley but the rest of the ride was dry. Good day.
 Photo album
Relive &#39;Century Saturday&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Round The Ville</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180807/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 22:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180807/</guid>
      <description>A nice unremarkable ride around my town.
 Relive &#39;Round The Ville&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kingstree Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180804/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 23:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180804/</guid>
      <description>Rode to Kingstree SC for the second time this year. Traffic was light. Temperatures were pleasant. Wind was calm. Riding a century every weekend is becoming a habit. Not sure why.
For my post ride meal I ate eggs, grits, and toast at Waffle House. It was delicious but pretty much anything tastes good after a century ride. I was expecting Waffle House to be a little livelier it being midnight on a Saturday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Folly Beach</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180802/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 21:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180802/</guid>
      <description>Mike&amp;rsquo;s Bikes installed a new drivetrain and performed a general tune-up on my Giant Anyroad 1. I picked up Old Yeller after work and headed to Folly Beach and later over to The Charleston Battery. Nice smooth comfy ride.
 Photo album
Relive &#39;Folly Beach&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mt Pleasant Pier</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180731/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 23:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180731/</guid>
      <description>Old Yeller is still in the shop getting a new drivetrain so I took the backup bike for a night ride to the Mt Pleasant Pier. Comfortable temperatures, nice sky, and a tailwind home. Pretty much a perfect summer evening. I was concerned about my lights dying but they hung on to the very end around 11 PM.
 Photo album
Relive &#39;Mount Pleasant Pier night ride&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Montague</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180729a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 22:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180729a/</guid>
      <description>Old Yeller is in the shop getting a new drivetrain so I took the backup bike for a night ride. The Giant Defy 3 rode pretty well. Not as comfy as the Giant Anyroad 1 but I&amp;rsquo;m fortunate to have a decent backup.
The temperatures were pleasant. I could see lightning off in the distance for most of the ride but I avoided the rain. 20 minutes after getting home it was pouring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bike Check and Product Annoyances</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180729/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180729/</guid>
      <description>Shifting was less than stellar during yesterday&amp;rsquo;s ride. Checked the chain and it is at .75% wear. Time for a replacement.

I see some wear on the cassette as well. I may get that replaced. I will drop off the Giant Anyroad 1 at Mike&amp;rsquo;s Bikes today.

The Park Cyclone Chain Scrubber works well but the rivets that hold the clips fall out. I&amp;rsquo;ve lost one rivet. The other one falls out occasionally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charleston Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180728/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180728/</guid>
      <description>Mapped out my route Friday night and pretty much stuck to it. This is my third century ride for July 2018. It was a enjoyable ride except for Highway 402. It is the worst road surface I&amp;rsquo;ve ever ridden. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I will ride that highway again until they pave it which will probably be a very long time from now.
My favorite segments were the West Ashley Greenway, Charleston Battery, and Arthur Ravenel Jr Bridge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Breeze</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180724/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 22:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180724/</guid>
      <description>Afternoon thunderstorms cleared for a nice evening ride. I dropped by the Ashley River. Good times.
I overestimated the charge in my two rear lights. They both died about 30 minutes prior to the end of my ride. That was a little dicey. I need to make a habit when I get home to immediately remove my lights from my bike and connect them to the charger. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll do it later&amp;rdquo; doesn&amp;rsquo;t work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Moultrie Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180722/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180722/</guid>
      <description>Frequently I get on my bike without a plan. Today was one of those days.
I do like to ride through Cane Bay on Sunday to check on the progress near Black Tom Rd. So that is were I headed. They have asphalt almost to Black Tom Rd. Looking good.
I then headed towards Moncks Corner and decided to get on the Lake Moultrie dike. Once I got to Bonneau I wanted to find where I could continue on the dike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charleston Triangle</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180721/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180721/</guid>
      <description>Had a nice tailwind to Charleston and mostly head and cross winds home. Temperatures were great. The Garmin says the average was 69.9 °F. I find that a little hard to believe. It was nice but not that nice. Rode the West Ashley Greenway. I love that segment.
On the way home I stopped by the Summerville Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market to pick up a couple Cookie Chick cookies. They weren&amp;rsquo;t selling any oatmeal based cookies today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rain Avoidance Routing</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180719/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 21:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180719/</guid>
      <description>Cloudy evening with rain threatening. I was able to avoid the rain and settled for some drizzle. Mission accomplished.
Still considering a night century. Perhaps Saturday or Sunday night.
 Relive &#39;Rain avoidance routing&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knight Rider</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180715/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 22:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180715/</guid>
      <description>Pleasant 73.5°F average temperature and low traffic. This has me thinking about riding a night century.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turkeys, bison, rabbit, heron, cranes</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180714/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180714/</guid>
      <description>The ride was filled with wildlife sightings. At the bottom of the Lake Moultrie dike I spotted a flock of turkeys. Along Highway 311 I spotted a cotton tail rabbit and a herd of bison on a farm. Along Highway 453 between Holly Hill and Harleyville I saw a wide variety of birds including heron and crane. There are sections of cypress swamps along Highway 453 providing a nice break from the industrial environment of that highway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180710/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180710/</guid>
      <description>The Garmin 520 recorded 59°F as the low temperature. That is crazy low for July. I almost needed my arm warmers. High temperature on the ride home was 86℉ which was pleasant.
I must admit waking up before 5 AM to beat the traffic is getting old. Still waiting on a road to connect to Black Tom Rd that may provide a safer and later ride.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tour de Charleston</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180707/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180707/</guid>
      <description>I was thinking of a short ride this morning since I rode a century on Wednesday but one road led to another ending with 72 miles in the books. It was a good uneventful ride. Had a head wind on the way home. Felt a little tired but not tired enough to skip a detour to the Summerville Farmer&amp;rsquo;s market for a couple of Cookie Chick cookies.
Tour de France 2018 started today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edisto Beach Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180704/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180704/</guid>
      <description>I woke up at 4 AM and was on the road by 5 AM. The rain started at mile 25 and didn&amp;rsquo;t let up much until I returned to Summerville. But hey at least I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about the heat. It was a cool ride in many ways. I love the scenery. Traffic was light for the most part. On the way home when the rain was really coming down a kind human in a pickup truck with a bicycle in the back asked if I wanted a lift.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley River</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180701/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180701/</guid>
      <description>Took a late morning ride to the Ashley River. Passed a snake on the Sawmill Branch trail. I should have stopped and snapped a picture. A road cyclist passed me on a section of the Sawmill Branch trail. I fell behind by about 20 seconds and was struggling to keep up with him while he looked like he was out for a casual Sunday spin. Oh well. Where the end of the trail empties onto a rock road, me and my 32c tires kept rolling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Moultrie Then Blinding Torrential Rain</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180628/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 22:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180628/</guid>
      <description>Trip to Lake Moultrie. Rode the dike from Pinopolis to the Hatchery. Took Highway 6 then Old Whitesville Road to 17A. Nearing Black Tom Rd the rain began. On Black Tom Rd the rain was torrential and I could not see where to turn off. After a couple of misses I found the turn. I rode through the mud for about a mile and then hit pavement for a smooth ride home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crit Races and Nextburg Loops</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180626/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 22:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180626/</guid>
      <description>The weather was pleasant for the criterium racers, not as hot as it has been the last 10 days. I watched the category 5 and 4 races.
After watching the races I felt like riding in circles so I cycled 3 Nextburg loops. Nextburg is what I&amp;rsquo;m calling Nexton Parkway to Jedburg Rd. The road names between Nexton Parkway and Jedburg Rd are Drop Off Dr and Red Bay Rd. This was my first proper ride on the All-City Big Block since installing the drop handlebars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drop Handlebars</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180625/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 22:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180625/</guid>
      <description>Replaced the Kalloy 700mm Riser handlebars with Giant Connect XR drop handlebars. These are the same handlebars that are on my Giant Anyroad 1 bicycle. I am using the Tektro RL520 lever set and have Sunlite Road foam grips for simplicity and comfort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday Evening Ride</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180624/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 22:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180624/</guid>
      <description>Started my Sunday ride around 8 PM. The sun went down around 8:30 along with the temperatures. There was a nice breeze and my legs felt alive. I ate a few bugs. I can use the protein. Traffic was a little hairy on Hwy 52 in Goose Creek but other than that traffic was mostly light being Sunday evening. The moon was at 87% illumination and on the other side of the sky was a lightning show.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low Energy</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180623/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180623/</guid>
      <description>My legs were dead this morning. Don&amp;rsquo;t know if it is the heat or the 40 mile ride Thursday night on the single speed. Hopefully tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s ride will be better. Took some different roads on this Charleston trip. Rode by the airport, Park Circle, and came back home on Dorchester Rd.
Photo album
 Relive &#39;Low Energy&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Too hip for PLA</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180621/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 22:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180621/</guid>
      <description>After flying over the handlebars performing a crotch skid I decided the fixed gear life was not for me. I installed a White Industries ENO 16 tooth freewheel on my All-City Big Block single speed bicycle and went for a ride. Much more enjoyable with the freewheel than the fixed gear. I can always flip the wheel around to go back to fixed if I&amp;rsquo;m feeling reasonably dangerous.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heat Advisory Headwind</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180619/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180619/</guid>
      <description>Rode the bicycle to work since I dropped off my Chevy Bolt EV yesterday for scheduled maintenance. Left work a little after 3PM and cycled to Rick Hendrick Chevrolet in Charleston to pick up the Bolt. There was a heat advisory and a headwind. The Garmin recorded 100.4 °F as the high and 94.0 °F as the average. Not sure what the humidity was but it was high. I faced a headwind today which I guess is fair since I had a tailwind yesterday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rick Hendrick Chevrolet</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180618/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 19:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180618/</guid>
      <description>Dropped off my Chevy Bolt EV at Rick Hendrick Chevrolet on Savannah Hwy in Charleston for regular scheduled maintenance. Rode my bike home. Nice ride with favorable winds and traffic lights.
I will cycle to work in the morning and probably leave around 3 PM to cycle back to Rick Hendrick Chevrolet. Tomorrow is going to be a scorcher. The ride will be a bit of a challenge.
Photo album</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pimlico</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180617/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180617/</guid>
      <description>Sunday&amp;rsquo;s ride started at 6:15 AM just in time to catch a foggy misty sunrise. I came out the back of Nexton, through Cane Bay, hopped on the newly paved Black Tom Rd, crossed Hwy 17-A onto Gaillard Rd to Old Hwy 52 to Cypress Gardens Rd. In Pimlico at the end of Albert Storm Dr there is a trail leading to the Cooper River. I went mudding and stopped for a photo of the river.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>West Ashley Loop</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180616/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180616/</guid>
      <description>Saturday&amp;rsquo;s ride started off around 6:45 AM. Temperature and humidity were comfortable at the start but rose quickly.
I was baffled by the amount of traffic on Hwy 165. It is normally pretty sparse. The opposite lane was streaming with cars. I searched the web when I got home and discovered that there is a Lacrosse event June 16 &amp;amp; 17, 2018 t the Hyde Park Farm &amp;amp; Polo Club. This promotional video makes Lacrosse look pretty exciting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Moultrie Dike</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180615/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180615/</guid>
      <description>After the work week was complete I rode my Giant Anyroad 1 up to the Watermark Bar &amp;amp; Grill in Bonneau SC. From work I took Hwy 52, Jessamine Dr, a wrong turn on Powerhouse Rd, Old Black Oak Rd to the Lake Moultrie dike. The dike is a nice gravel ride which my 32c tires handle nicely. The ride to the bar was hot. Drank a couple of Yuenglings with friends, paid my tab and headed back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Bike Day</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180613/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180613/</guid>
      <description>Resist no more. Purchased an All-City Big Block from Mike&amp;rsquo;s Bikes located on Coleman Blvd in Mt Pleasant SC.
Been thinking about a fixed gear for some time. I blame it on fixed gear YouTube videos. They make it look like so much fun. This is my first fixed gear. It is like learning to ride all over again. I just keep repeating to myself while riding, no coasting, no coasting, no coasting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180612/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180612/</guid>
      <description>Gloomy overcast day. No sun but no rain either. Had a bit of a tailwind on the way home giving me a decent moving time of 47:29.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bushy Park</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180610/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180610/</guid>
      <description>On the road at 6 AM Sunday for a ride to Bushy Park. I went through Cane Bay / Del Webb so I could check up on the development near Black Tom Rd. Still no pavement in the last development. Had to ride a mile of dirt to Black Tom Rd. Good to see Black Tom Rd resurfacing progressing nicely. I&amp;rsquo;d say they are about 70% complete. Now if they could work on Bushy Park Rd that would be ace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unseated</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180609/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180609/</guid>
      <description>Saturday&amp;rsquo;s ride started off good enough at 6 AM. Roads were wet but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t raining until I got on Meeting St in North Charleston. It rained pretty heavy for a mile or two then eased up. 22 miles in my rear wheel unseated while I was going over the railroad tracks on Meeting St near Magnolia Cemetery. The bump also knocked my seat out of place. Luckily I stayed upright.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180607/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180607/</guid>
      <description>Good ride into work in under 50 minutes moving time. Always pleased with sub 50 minute rides. The ride home had a rain delay. Planned to leave work at 4 PM but a shower popped up and rained pretty hard. Worked for another hour. The road was steaming for the first few miles and all dry the rest of the way home. After showering I cycled over to Taco Bell for some black bean burritos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180605/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180605/</guid>
      <description>Was treated to a beautiful sunrise on the way to work. The ride home was nice too with temperatures in mid 80s ℉ and relatively low humidity.
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summerville Farmers&#39; Market and Ashley River</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180602/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180602/</guid>
      <description>Grabbed a Peanut Butter Toffee Chip cookie and a Cranberry White Oatmeal Chocolate cookie from the Cookie Chick stand at the Summerville Farmers&amp;rsquo; Market. Ate one on the spot and saved the other for after lunch. On the way to the river I got stung on my left ankle by what I assume was a bee. No big deal. After stopping for a photo at the river I headed down Ladson Rd, College Park Rd and Hwy 17-A back home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180601/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180601/</guid>
      <description>Long day. Woke up at 4:00 AM and was on the road by 5:00 AM. Left the office around 5:20 PM.
My bike has a clicking squeaky noise. I&amp;rsquo;m guessing it is from the saddle. Took the saddle off and removed a good bit of dirt. Hopefully that was cause.
Temperatures are on the way up. It was approaching 90 ℉. May 2018 was the wettest month ever in Charleston SC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wet Wednesday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180530/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180530/</guid>
      <description>Rain and more rain. As of this writing this is second wettest May of all time for Charleston SC. Bring on a dry hot June.
I brought my Nvidia Shield to work for a coworker to borrow. I packed it in my Topeak Backloader bicycle bag and it stayed dry. Yay! I was able to cycle to lunch without getting rained. Yay again! The ride home was a soaker but at least the winds were calm and the temperature was a comfortable 69.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subtropical Slider</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180528/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180528/</guid>
      <description>Cycling too fast for conditions. I went for a ride to Ravenel SC on Memorial Day 2018. The ride didn&amp;rsquo;t start out too great. The roads were wet as we were getting rain bands from subtropical storm Alberto. Turning off of Jedburg Rd we took a slide. I had just put on new bar tape the day before. The tape only lasted about 9 miles. LOLZ. The bike is fine. I was fine and continued on with the ride without further incident.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memorial Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180526/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180526/</guid>
      <description>Woke up around 3 AM and could not go back to sleep. I knew I wanted to ride a century today and my excitement cost me some sleep. Oh well. I was on the road by 5 AM which was a good thing. The summer is coming on strong. The earlier in the day I ride the better. The entire ride was on 4 lane highways. The traffic was light from home to Kingstree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180524/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180524/</guid>
      <description>Tried a new route on the morning commute. I got off of Hwy 17-A at Gaillard Rd over to Old Hwy 52. Nice change of scenery. It was not quite a mile longer.
The afternoon commute got off to a slow start. Before I could work up a sweat I was stopped by not one but two trains. The first freight train was long and slow. Towards the end with just a dozen cars left to pass the crossing a second freight train coming from the opposite direction appeared.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180522/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180522/</guid>
      <description>Nice rides to work and back. No uptight automobile drivers. Damp tarmac and a little drizzle on the way home. No worries.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charleston Battery</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180520/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180520/</guid>
      <description>Enjoyed a pleasant Sunday ride to the Charleston Battery. Not much wind, temperatures were around 70℉ and automobile traffic was light.
Relive &#39;Charleston Battery&#39;   Photo album</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Savannah</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180519/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180519/</guid>
      <description>It was raining this morning with a forecast of showers all day so I drove the Chevrolet Bolt EV down to Savannah GA. I parked the car at a convenience store and plugged in to their charger. I hopped on my bike to explore Savannah. Riding around the city was pretty nice but it got old after a while having to stop every block. I left the city and headed down to the Savannah National Wildlife Refuge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Bike to Work Day</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180518/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180518/</guid>
      <description>Today was National Bike to Work Day. I usually bike to work on Tuesday and Thursday but I switched this week to Wednesday and Friday to align with BTWD. We had on and off again rain all day. I managed to escape all but a few drops here and there. Pretty nice rides. Below is a snippet of my ride home. I&amp;rsquo;m not proud of this part of my ride but I just don&amp;rsquo;t feel like stopping in traffic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wednesday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180516/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180516/</guid>
      <description>Picked up Old Yeller from Mike&amp;rsquo;s Bikes yesterday. It has a new rear derailleur, chain, rear tire, and cassette. The ride to work was super smooth. Really glad to have the Giant Anyroad 1 back. It is so much nicer than my backup bike, Giant Defy 3. I can&amp;rsquo;t recall an average MPH of 20 so I think this was a personal best. There is something motivational about a new drivetrain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bushy Park</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180513/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180513/</guid>
      <description>Cycled through Cane Bay on my way to Bushy Park. Had to walk for a couple of hundred yards over a sandy road in the neighborhood under construction. Looking forward to when there is a paved road to either Black Tom Rd or 17-A. The rest of the ride was pleasant. Not as hot as yesterday and traffic was light.
 Photo album</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mmmm Cookies</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180512/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180512/</guid>
      <description>Started my morning ride off with cookies from the Cookie Chick at the Summerville Farmers Market. Cookie Chick bakes the best cookies. I ate an oatmeal rum cookie and saved a toasted almond cookie for after lunch. Good stuff. My main bike is still at the LBS so I rode the backup bike. Fortunate to have a backup bike. My primary bike seems to spend allot of time at the LBS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday Commute, Post Chipotle Ride and Topeak Chain Tool</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180510/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 19:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180510/</guid>
      <description>Thursday&amp;rsquo;s commute was uneventful. I rode to Chipotle for dinner and afterwards rode up Hwy 78. I was going to take N Maple St to the Nexton Parkway but couldn&amp;rsquo;t find N Maple St. Looked at Google Maps when I got home and realized I should have traveled a few more blocks. I headed back up 17-A and took Holiday Dr to Nexton Parkway instead. Even though I had been on Nexton Parkway many times this was the first time with automobile traffic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180508/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180508/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday&amp;rsquo;s commute was uneventful. I snapped a photo of The Corner Cafe Bakery in Moncks Corner SC. It recently closed. A Starbucks recently opened and I assume that might have played into The Corner&amp;rsquo;s decision to close. I had a rare tailwind on the way home which enabled me to break my 50 minute barrier again. Nice!
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snapped Rear Derailleur Hanger</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180506b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 19:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180506b/</guid>
      <description>A microfiber cloth flew out of my top tube bag right into my rear derailleur causing the hanger to snap. I was pulling my phone out of the bag at the time. I usually have the microfiber cloth stored in a sandwich bag but not today. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t injured. My plan was to use my chain tool to remove a section of the chain so I could ride back home. Unfortunately I have lost the pin for the chain tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garmin Insights</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180506a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 07:17:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180506a/</guid>
      <description>The Garmin Connect mobile app for Android has a feature called Insights. You can compare your fitness stats to others. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how many users there are and if there was an opt-in option for this. Some folks recommend not comparing yourself to others which is good advice. Just do your own thing and stay moving. Seeing how you stack up to others is kind of interesting and hard to resist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Folly Beach</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180505/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180505/</guid>
      <description>Another beautiful day in the lowcountry. Blue sky, low humidity and temperatures topping off in the 80&amp;rsquo;s ℉. I cycled to Folly Beach. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be happier with the way my Giant Anyroad 1 bicycle performed after being serviced yesterday at my LBS. Mike&amp;rsquo;s Bikes on Coleman Blvd Mt Pleasant replaced my rear bearing balls and cups. The drive train was silky smooth and quiet. Super nice ride.
 Photo album</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintenance Friday and Why I Don&#39;t Use Clipless Pedals</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180504/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180504/</guid>
      <description>Heard noise from my rear hub on my Thursday commute. Took the Giant Anyroad 1 into Mike&amp;rsquo;s Bikes. They replaced the bearing balls and cups. I had introduced water and dirt into the bearings when I washed my bike with a pressure washer. I thought I was being gentle with the washer. Obviously not gentle enough. Lesson learned. Being an apartment dweller I don&amp;rsquo;t have access to a water hose. That is why I was going to the car wash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180503/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180503/</guid>
      <description>Wheee - just having fun! Gorgeous weather continues. I didn&amp;rsquo;t like the way my rear hub was sounding so I dropped off my Giant Anyroad 1 bike at Mike&amp;rsquo;s Bikes in Mt Pleasant. Asked them to check all the bearings. Hopeful it will be a one day turn around so I can have it for the weekend. If not I&amp;rsquo;ll be riding my Giant Defy 3 and wishing I was on my Anyroad 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180501/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180501/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday&amp;rsquo;s commute had a big temperature swing. According to my Garmin 520 bicycle computer the minimum temperature was 39℉ and the maximum temperature was 82℉. That is a 43℉ swing.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley River</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180429/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180429/</guid>
      <description>Rode to the Ashley River. Temperature was about 10 degrees cooler than yesterday and a little more wind. Still had a clear blue sky. Pretty nice.
 Photo album</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Moultrie Loop</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180428/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180428/</guid>
      <description>Absolutely a gorgeous day for a long ride. Started out in the low 50&amp;rsquo;s ℉ and ended in the mid 70&amp;rsquo;s ℉. There wasn&amp;rsquo;t a cloud in the sky and the winds were light. Perfect! I chose to loop around Lake Moultrie.
 Photo album</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180426/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180426/</guid>
      <description>My Thursday commute was dry, comfortable, and uneventful. I got up at 5 AM and was on the road by 5:30 AM. I think I will stick with this schedule. I&amp;rsquo;d like to sleep an hour later but it is not worth the increased traffic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180424/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180424/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday commute started out wet with mist and a couple of showers. The ride home was dry, unlike my shoes, and partly cloudy. One thing is for sure the traffic is far better at 5:30 AM than at 6:30 AM. The traffic is lighter and a little less frantic. Absolutely worth getting up at 5 AM for.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Moultrie</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180422/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180422/</guid>
      <description>Sunday ride to the lovely Lake Moultrie. So grateful to have this lake within riding distance from my apartment. The dike surface is gravel and dirt. As long as it hasn&amp;rsquo;t rained it is easy to navigate. I must say my Giant Anyroad 1 with 32c tires handles the terrain comfortably. Got up on the dike at the end of W Dike Rd in Pinopolis SC and exited at the Hatchery Boat Ramp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charleston Triangle</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180421/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180421/</guid>
      <description>Saturday ride to Charleston Battery and over to West Ashley Greenway. I love the West Ashley Greenway. It is a 8.25 hike and bike trail. Mostly paved with a few gravel sections. Took the longer route home up Highway 165. The route has a triangle shape. The average temperature was 64℉ with partly cloudy skies. Pretty much perfect weather for a long weekend ride.
 Photo album</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Best on AM Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180419/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 19:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180419/</guid>
      <description>Had a rare tailwind this morning and it helped me achieve my personal best moving time of 46:59. I also had a little help from a slow moving 18 wheeler.
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contemplating the Commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180418/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180418/</guid>
      <description>Contemplating my twice-a-week bicycle commute. It is 16.2 miles between Moncks Corner and Summerville. Most of the ride is on Hwy 17-A which is a busy 4 lane highway. The section from my apartment in Summerville to Cypress Gardens Rd is the busiest section. Cypress Gardens Rd intersection to Moncks Corner is lower traffic and a pleasant ride.
Pros  4 hours of exercise a week Green Commute Enjoyable Accomplishing 2 things a once (commute and exercise)  Cons  Dangerous Abuse from drivers (yelling, honking, revving, close drive by)  The benefits are many but sometimes feel that I am being irresponsible to my family and to my employer by risking my life on my bike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laps in the wind</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180415/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180415/</guid>
      <description>Recovering from an FBI event Thursday night. Ate some Golden Flake peanuts that sat in my car seat all afternoon soaking up the sun and transforming into some evil shite. This ride was 3 laps on along the I-26 frontage roads, Drop Off Dr and Red Bay Rd. Windy AF. Weak.
At the start of this ride the Garmin Edge 520 powered off for some unknown reason. That is the second Strava embed below with only 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday evening ride in lieu of a Friday commute</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180412/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180412/</guid>
      <description>Meeting some friends after work Friday so instead of a Friday commute I rode Thursday evening. This is my first ride with my Topeak Toploader. I like it. Nice to have my phone, gels, and batteries easily accessible. Much better than reaching around my back to my jersey pockets. The only time my knees touched the bag was when I got sloppy out of the saddle.
 Photo album</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute Wednesday April 11, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180411/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180411/</guid>
      <description>[Broke my cheap clear sunglasses] (https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/nfURpwsIbLAyPhASAA_PphbFkkcZAiCYWSvPTwsd8UpJtDCxqWtQCA_Hzg67TkO6NqSqa23hNofjbzt6CsFJOlnEAn_Phz01SqnyPdEm3b4fE-CjSH7iQTNAj1vsfJTmu_5mTIxTZnM=w2400) before I got out the door. On the ride to work I got honked at once and yelled at once. A passenger in a truck yelled &amp;ldquo;Get on the sidewalk!&amp;quot;. Yeah, that ain&amp;rsquo;t happening. 16 miles on a sidewalk would not be fun.
We&amp;rsquo;ve got new pavement on Main St in Moncks Corner SC. So nice. The road was in really bad shape. Love cycling on new tarmac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Larry&#39;s Giant Subs</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180410/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 19:34:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180410/</guid>
      <description>Rode across town to Larry&amp;rsquo;s Giant Subs on Old Trolley Rd Summerville SC. Dropped my cheap sunglasses on the road scratching them pretty good. Slammed a turkey sub. Ran into a childhood friend and his son. Good to catch up with him.
I&amp;rsquo;m not a real fan of eating and immediately riding. It was a short ride of 6 miles so wasn&amp;rsquo;t too bad but I prefer the restaurants on my side of town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trial a longer, potentially safer route to work</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180408/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180408/</guid>
      <description>I commute twice a week from Summerville to Moncks Corner SC via Hwy 17-A which is a busy 4 lane highway. The video was taken during my trial to stay off highways as much as possible. I came out the back of Nexton, through Cane Bay, through Del Webb, onto Black Tom Rd, and finally back onto Hwy 17-A. This route is about 20 miles vs my normal route of 16 miles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overnight bicycle tour Santee SC</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180331/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180331/</guid>
      <description>Cycled to Santee SC Saturday and spent the night at the Holiday Inn. Took Hwy 6 to Santee SC and Hwy 176 on the way home. Hwy 176 is one of my least favorite roads but it is the shortest route. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t too busy on Easter Sunday.
  Photo album</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overnight bicycle tour Georgetown SC</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180324/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180324/</guid>
      <description>Cycled to Georgetown SC Saturday and spent the night at the Hampton Inn. Saturday was chilly with a headwind. The sun peaked out a few times. Sunday morning it was raining until about checkout time 11 AM. I got on the road and had a nice tailwind home. Not allot a sun but a good ride.
  Photo album</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>