<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About on PLA Cycling Log</title>
    <link>https://pla.bike/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About on PLA Cycling Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 17:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pla.bike/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Gear</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/about/gear/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/about/gear/</guid>
      <description>Below is my gear list. Stuff I use on a regular basis. Links to product website when possible otherwise to Amazon.
Bikes  Giant Anyroad 1 2017 (main) AKA Old Yeller Giant Defy 3 2016 (backup) Dahon Speed Uno folding bike Unicycle  Bags  Topeak TopLoader Top Tube Bag Topeak Midloader Topeak Aero Wedge Topeak Backloader  Lights  Topeak Aero Combox (fork lights) Cygolite Hotshot Pro (rear light) Cycle Torch Shark 500 (head light) Ascher USB Rechargeable Bike Light Set (backup lights)  Computer  Garmin Edge 520 Wahoo Elemnt Bolt K-EDGE Garmin &amp;amp; GoPro Mount Pixel 3 phone  Camera and accessories  GoPro Hero 7 Anker PowerCore 13000 C Samsung 256GB Memory Card Sunlite foam handlebar grips OTTOLOCK bike lock (low security but light)  Tires and tubes  Continental Gatorskins 700x32c Specialized Armadillo 700x32c Continental 42mm Presta Valve Tube  Clothing high viz yellow when available  Gore jacket Gore helmet cap Gore overshoes Gore gloves Pearl Izumi Lobster Gloves Giro gloves Pearl iZUMi Elite Thermal Cycling Legwarmer Pearl iZUMi Men&#39;s Escape Quest Cycling Shorts Owayo custom cycling jersey Clear safety glasses Tinted safety glasses  Maintenance  Topeak Joe Blow Sport III Floor Pump GODESON Tire Pressure Gauge Park Tool Chain Checker CC-3.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>