<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Century on PLA Cycling Log</title>
    <link>https://pla.bike/tags/century/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Century on PLA Cycling Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 11:20:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pla.bike/tags/century/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Century Saturday 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180811/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 11:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180811/</guid>
      <description>This is my 4th weekend century in a row. I&amp;rsquo;m getting to the point if I don&amp;rsquo;t ride 100 miles I feel lazy.
Today&amp;rsquo;s ride started at 4:57 AM. Nice to have the roads all to myself for a while. There was a summer shower in West Ashley but the rest of the ride was dry. Good day.
 Photo album
Relive &amp;lsquo;Century Saturday&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kingstree Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180804/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 23:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180804/</guid>
      <description>Rode to Kingstree SC for the second time this year. Traffic was light. Temperatures were pleasant. Wind was calm. Riding a century every weekend is becoming a habit. Not sure why.
For my post ride meal I ate eggs, grits, and toast at Waffle House. It was delicious but pretty much anything tastes good after a century ride. I was expecting Waffle House to be a little livelier it being midnight on a Saturday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charleston Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180728/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180728/</guid>
      <description>Mapped out my route Friday night and pretty much stuck to it. This is my third century ride for July 2018. It was a enjoyable ride except for Highway 402. It is the worst road surface I&amp;rsquo;ve ever ridden. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I will ride that highway again until they pave it which will probably be a very long time from now.
My favorite segments were the West Ashley Greenway, Charleston Battery, and Arthur Ravenel Jr Bridge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Moultrie Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180722/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180722/</guid>
      <description>Frequently I get on my bike without a plan. Today was one of those days.
I do like to ride through Cane Bay on Sunday to check on the progress near Black Tom Rd. So that is were I headed. They have asphalt almost to Black Tom Rd. Looking good.
I then headed towards Moncks Corner and decided to get on the Lake Moultrie dike. Once I got to Bonneau I wanted to find where I could continue on the dike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edisto Beach Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180704/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180704/</guid>
      <description>I woke up at 4 AM and was on the road by 5 AM. The rain started at mile 25 and didn&amp;rsquo;t let up much until I returned to Summerville. But hey at least I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about the heat. It was a cool ride in many ways. I love the scenery. Traffic was light for the most part. On the way home when the rain was really coming down a kind human in a pickup truck with a bicycle in the back asked if I wanted a lift.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memorial Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180526/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180526/</guid>
      <description>Woke up around 3 AM and could not go back to sleep. I knew I wanted to ride a century today and my excitement cost me some sleep. Oh well. I was on the road by 5 AM which was a good thing. The summer is coming on strong. The earlier in the day I ride the better. The entire ride was on 4 lane highways. The traffic was light from home to Kinstree.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>