<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Century on PLA Cycling Log</title>
    <link>https://pla.bike/tags/century/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Century on PLA Cycling Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 16:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pla.bike/tags/century/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Georgetown Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190119/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190119/</guid>
      <description>This ride was on my bucket list. Wanted to make a round trip to Georgetown SC from Summerville SC. Knocked it off the list today. My mother&amp;rsquo;s family is from Georgetown and it holds a special place in my heart and brain. I have many wonderful childhood memories in Georgetown. Now I&amp;rsquo;ve added one more.
Great average temperature of 54℉. It was mostly cloudy. Good to see the sun every now and again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Francis Marion National Forest Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190106/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190106/</guid>
      <description>Today&amp;rsquo;s century ride was perfect. I even had a little energy left at the end. I&amp;rsquo;m usually spent and struggling by mile 80. I&amp;rsquo;ll attribute feeling good all the way to the end to:
 An abundance of sunshine A lack of headwinds An early start Cool temperatures Nutrition (although I didn&amp;rsquo;t do anything different)
  I went to bed last night excited that today was going to be awesome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edisto Beach Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190101/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 14:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190101/</guid>
      <description>What a way to start off the new year. A century ride to the beach with temperatures in the 70&amp;rsquo;s °F. Crazy weather and I love it.
The route to Edisto Beach is fairly scenic if you can ignore the roadside litter. There are cypress swamps, marshes, beautiful oak trees, a variety of birds and of course there is the ocean.
Good day on the saddle.
Photo album
  Relive &amp;lsquo;Edisto Beach Century 💯&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kingstree Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181224/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181224/</guid>
      <description>All century rides are tough but the head winds on the way to Kingstree made this one especially challenging. Considered cutting my ride short more than once. Glad I toughed it out. Was concerned about getting home before the temperatures started dropping. Towards the end of a century it is hard to keep your body temperature up since you don&amp;rsquo;t have the energy but it worked out on this ride. Arrived home before 5 PM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IOP Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181124/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181124/</guid>
      <description>It rained before I got on the road and it looked like it was going to be a dreary wet day. Thankfully I was deceived. There was a 3 hour period of weather perfection. The sun was shining and temperatures topped out at 71°F. It was so nice. I removed my sleeves from my jacket and took off my gloves at the beach. When I hit North Charleston the clouds returned along with some wind so I put the sleeves and gloves back on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marion Moultrie Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181118/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181118/</guid>
      <description>Rode a section of dike on both Lake Marion and Lake Moultrie. Discovered dramatically that the Lake Marion dam is closed to the public. Santee Cooper is South Carolina&amp;rsquo;s state-owned electric and water utility that runs the dam. I was stopped by a Santee Cooper employee and told to turn around. I begged and pleaded for him to let me slide fearing that I may not have the fitness to tackle a 150 mile ride.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edge of America Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181111/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181111/</guid>
      <description>Temperatures min/avg/max 37.4°F / 50.6°F / 57.2°F. Windy but mostly in my favor. Had a quick easy ride to Charleston and then to Folly Beach. I prepared myself mentally for a headwind on the ride home but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t as bad as expected. Great day in the saddle.
 Photo album
Relive &amp;lsquo;Edge of America Century 💯&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kiawah Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181028/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181028/</guid>
      <description>Temperatures min/avg/max 41.0°F / 56.7°F / 69.8°F. Clear blue skies and light winds. First time cycling to Kiawah Island. Maybank Rd is fairly safe, Bohicket Rd not so much. Once you get to Kiawah there are paved bike paths. Their novelty wore thin and I took the road on the way out of Kiawah. I&amp;rsquo;m not a big fan of golf courses and huge houses which is what Kiawah is all about but the ride was nice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jamestown Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 15:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181021/</guid>
      <description>48.2 °F at the start with a stiff headwind. I thought more than once about turning around in Moncks Corner. I&amp;rsquo;m glad I didn&amp;rsquo;t. The middle section of the ride was good. Warmed up into the 60&amp;rsquo;s with mostly a tail wind. Rode some gravel, rock, and mud on Tiger Corner Rd in the Francis Marion Forest. The headwinds returned once I got through Charleston. The temperature dropped a little as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ACE Basin Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181013/</guid>
      <description>A friend suggested I visit the ACE Basin so that is what I did. I had not been there since 2014. To my delight it hasn&amp;rsquo;t changed a bit.
Not a cloud in the sky all day long. I donned arm warmers and gloves this morning. It was a good decision. Temperature started at 50.0 °F and maxed out at 84.2 °F according to Garmin.
A few new-to-me roads in today&amp;rsquo;s route.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Santee National Wildlife Refuge Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181006/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181006/</guid>
      <description>This ride had a little of everything. There was rain at the start, gravel trails, muddy trails, sandy trails, overgrown trails, good tarmac, terrible tarmac, a fenced off bridge, and an illegal ride across Lake Marion on I-95. What a day.
Photo album
 Relive &amp;lsquo;Santee National Wildlife Refuge Century&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>McClellanville Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180923/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180923/</guid>
      <description>Humans are awesome. There are so many cyclists that inspire me. Lael Wilcox is the latest that touched me. Last night I watched a mini documentary on her Navad 1000 Across Switzerland race. It gave me the confidence to knock out today&amp;rsquo;s ride.
I woke up at 3 AM and was on the road by 4:18 AM. Took a couple of wrong turns in Bethera. It was still dark and the route was new to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labor Day Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180903/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180903/</guid>
      <description>First time riding on the Lake Marion dike and The Santee Dam. Took me a little while to find the gate to the dike. It was still dark when I arrived. I ended up at Wilson&amp;rsquo;s landing which is several miles from where I needed to be. The entrance to the dike is a yellow gate behind a Santee Cooper garage to the right of the Harry&amp;rsquo;s Fish Camp entrance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tri-County Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180901/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180901/</guid>
      <description>Woke up around 3 AM and was on the road at 4:40 AM. From Summerville I rode through Moncks Corner, Bonneau, St Stephen, Pineville, Cross, Holly Hill, and Harleyville. It was a little chilly this morning until the sun came up. Not looking forward to summer ending.
I think I fueled too much too quickly. My stomach was a little sore.
At the end of my ride I rode by the Summerville Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market for some Cookie Chick cookies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Folly Beach Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180825/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180825/</guid>
      <description>Woke up around 3 AM and was on the road at 4:18 AM. Nice tail wind for 70 miles. Tough head wind on the last leg of the ride. Shifting on Old Yeller is a little slow but other than that she is riding like a champ. Good day in the saddle.
 Photo album
Relive &amp;lsquo;Folly Beach Century&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Century Saturday 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180811/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 11:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180811/</guid>
      <description>This is my 4th weekend century in a row. I&amp;rsquo;m getting to the point if I don&amp;rsquo;t ride 100 miles I feel lazy.
Today&amp;rsquo;s ride started at 4:57 AM. Nice to have the roads all to myself for a while. There was a summer shower in West Ashley but the rest of the ride was dry. Good day.
 Photo album
Relive &amp;lsquo;Century Saturday&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kingstree Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180804/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 23:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180804/</guid>
      <description>Rode to Kingstree SC for the second time this year. Traffic was light. Temperatures were pleasant. Wind was calm. Riding a century every weekend is becoming a habit. Not sure why.
For my post ride meal I ate eggs, grits, and toast at Waffle House. It was delicious but pretty much anything tastes good after a century ride. I was expecting Waffle House to be a little livelier it being midnight on a Saturday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charleston Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180728/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180728/</guid>
      <description>Mapped out my route Friday night and pretty much stuck to it. This is my third century ride for July 2018. It was a enjoyable ride except for Highway 402. It is the worst road surface I&amp;rsquo;ve ever ridden. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I will ride that highway again until they pave it which will probably be a very long time from now.
My favorite segments were the West Ashley Greenway, Charleston Battery, and Arthur Ravenel Jr Bridge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Moultrie Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180722/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180722/</guid>
      <description>Frequently I get on my bike without a plan. Today was one of those days.
I do like to ride through Cane Bay on Sunday to check on the progress near Black Tom Rd. So that is were I headed. They have asphalt almost to Black Tom Rd. Looking good.
I then headed towards Moncks Corner and decided to get on the Lake Moultrie dike. Once I got to Bonneau I wanted to find where I could continue on the dike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edisto Beach Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180704/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180704/</guid>
      <description>I woke up at 4 AM and was on the road by 5 AM. The rain started at mile 25 and didn&amp;rsquo;t let up much until I returned to Summerville. But hey at least I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about the heat. It was a cool ride in many ways. I love the scenery. Traffic was light for the most part. On the way home when the rain was really coming down a kind human in a pickup truck with a bicycle in the back asked if I wanted a lift.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memorial Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180526/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180526/</guid>
      <description>Woke up around 3 AM and could not go back to sleep. I knew I wanted to ride a century today and my excitement cost me some sleep. Oh well. I was on the road by 5 AM which was a good thing. The summer is coming on strong. The earlier in the day I ride the better. The entire ride was on 4 lane highways. The traffic was light from home to Kinstree.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>