<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>century on PLA Cycling Log</title>
    <link>https://pla.bike/tags/century/</link>
    <description>Recent content in century on PLA Cycling Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 18:30:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pla.bike/tags/century/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Rivers Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20201205/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20201205/</guid>
      <description>Thought about trying another double century but a short and cool December day is not ideal. By 6:00 PM it was 43℉ so I called it a day.
Been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve ridden Cainhoy Rd. Some of it is pretty scenic.
Refueled at the new Spinx convenience store on the corner of Clements Ferry Rd and Hwy 41. Shot over to the Wando river and then took Hwy 41 to the Santee river.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charleston Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20201127/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 16:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20201127/</guid>
      <description>Didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like riding a century mentally or physically this morning. Got on the bike anyway to take advantage of this warm weather. Headed out to Ravenel SC and thought about heading home several times but told myself just keep pedaling. As the miles ticked away, the headwind changed to a tailwind and the temperature cracked 70℉, there was no reason to go home. Amazing how that works.
Rode a few new-to-me quiet country roads today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Donnelley Wildlife Management Area Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20201121/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 16:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20201121/</guid>
      <description>Picture perfect mid November day. Was thrilled to see a couple of gators sunning.
Had special fuel for today&amp;rsquo;s ride. My SIL shipped some delicious home made cookies for Thanksgiving. I ate a couple during the ride. Oh so good.
Great day on the saddle.
Ride on. ☮
  









 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100th Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20201114/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 15:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20201114/</guid>
      <description>Completed my one hundredth century ride. Feels good to accomplish another goal. My first century ride logged on Strava was May 26, 2018. I actually think I rode a few more century rides before this one but I&amp;rsquo;ll call this the first one. 903 days later I completed by 100th. Here they are on VeloViewer.
The remaining two goals for 2020 are 10,000 miles and covid-free. 9,299 miles so far. If I accomplish the last goal I should get the mileage goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Loop Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20201107/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 15:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20201107/</guid>
      <description>Sunny and seventies in November. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t get any better than that. The wind was the only thing not in my favor. Still baffled at how you can have a headwind the entire time on a circular route.
This was my ninety-ninth century ride. Need to decide where my 100th century will take me. Looking forward to celebrating that milestone.
Ride on. ☮






 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trick or Treat Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20201031/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20201031/</guid>
      <description>Was apprehensive about today&amp;rsquo;s ride after last Saturday&amp;rsquo;s pain in the knee ride. Turned out better than expected. My right knee was tender but not painful. Win!
This was century ride number 98. Need to get 2 more before the year ends to accomplish one of my goals.
Laugh of the day as my friend DVT says. It was in the low 50&amp;rsquo;s℉ this morning so I wore fingered gloves and packed half fingered gloves for later in the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Folly Beach Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20201024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 16:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20201024/</guid>
      <description>One of the many great things about sandals is being able to wade in the ocean, river or lake. The cool ocean water felt great.
Gorgeous weather today. Partly cloudy with temperatures peaking in the 80s℉.
The outer back of my right knee starting hurting on the way home. Hopefully a one-off. Likely will take tomorrow off and monitor.
Have I mentioned lately that I like yellow? Roadside daisies have been filling me with joy the last two weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Yeller Rides Again Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20201018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 16:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20201018/</guid>
      <description>Zach at The Bicycle Shoppe finished a herculean repair job on Old Yeller yesterday. So I had to go for a ride. Felt so good to be back on Old Yeller especially with a new drivetrain. Rode like a dream.
Weather was fantastic. Sunny 70&amp;rsquo;s ℉ for most of the ride.
Pretty good weekend with back to back century rides. Not sure I&amp;rsquo;ve done that before. Glad to know it is doable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Loop Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20201017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 15:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20201017/</guid>
      <description>Turning around and going home crossed my mind a couple of times when the cool headwind was like a brick wall. Kept pedaling and it paid off. The second half of the ride the winds were favorable.
Still riding the backup bike but got a call from the bicycle mechanic while I was on Cane Gully Rd that Old Yeller was ready for pickup. There is still work to do but it is rideable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mepkin Abbey Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20201010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 15:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20201010/</guid>
      <description>Always a pleasure to visit Mepkin Abbey. Moss covered oak trees, green grass and a river. What&amp;rsquo;s not to like?
Last night I was going to replace parts on Old Yeller that were damaged last week. Unfortunately one of the screws for the derailleur hanger was stripped. Not having a drill or spare screws the project came to a screeching halt. After this ride on my backup bike I stopped into The Bicycle Shoppe behind my apartment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chill, spill and a whole lotta luck Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20201004/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 15:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20201004/</guid>
      <description>Took a spill at mile 57. While riding through the Riverfront Park I went from concrete to gravel and tried to get back on the concrete and fell over. The lip of the concrete was higher than I thought and acted like a rail. Fell over onto the concrete on my right side. Injured my hip, elbow and ribs. I could still ride pain free but walking was a different story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bald Eagle Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200926/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200926/</guid>
      <description>Bizarre when your route is a loop and you have a headwind the entire ride. Expected the sun to come out sooner. So glad to see it when it finally did.
The highlight of the ride was getting a leadout by a bald eagle on Cane Gully Rd. Such a magnificent bird. Saw a big owl early in the ride. Also impressive. The most entertaining animal goes to the goat. Saw a couple of pastures with goats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Botany Bay Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200920/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200920/</guid>
      <description>Super high tide consumed the Botany Bay beach. One of the visitors on the way back said the water was thigh deep on the walk to the beach. Next time I will schedule my trip to Botany Bay during a low tide. Took a few photos and decided to go to Edisto beach. There was water on Palmetto Blvd with police blocking off the flooded section. Took a quick stroll on the beach and headed back home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seewee Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200912/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200912/</guid>
      <description>Ride turned out easier than I anticipated. 5 hours of sleep after a pretty active week made me think today was going to be a hard one. Thankfully it wasn&amp;rsquo;t.
First time on Doar Rd in Awendaw. Wanted to get to the Atlantic Intracoastal Waterway. Forest Service Rd 260-B was my best bet. Took off down the gravel road and was saddened to see it end before getting to the waterway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flower Power Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200907/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 17:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200907/</guid>
      <description>Whew. This century ride was far less exhausting than Friday&amp;rsquo;s. Main goal was to not repeat Friday&amp;rsquo;s ride. Kept telling myself to slow down. Just take what the road is giving me. So when the headwind stiffened I dropped to a lower gear and maintained my cadence. Felt much better at the end of the ride.
The wildflowers growing on the side of the road were nice. Lots of yellow, blue, and dark red flowers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edisto Beach Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200904/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200904/</guid>
      <description>Burned all my matches about 30 miles in and paid for it dearly. Tried a change to my normal route to Edisto Beach. Took Old Jacksonboro Rd off of Hwy 165. This segment runs parallel with Hwy 17 above it. Everything was fine until Old Jacksonboro Rd crossed New Rd. At that point it turned from pavement to a deep soft sand road. My 32c tires sunk in the sand like a hot knife in butter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charleston Triangle Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200830/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200830/</guid>
      <description>Couldn&amp;rsquo;t decide on today&amp;rsquo;s route. I just headed out the door and made it up as I went. Never felt comfortable with my position and pace but knocked it out. Weather was nice with a little bit of wind.
Ride on. ☮






 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Jolly Folly Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200823/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 23:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200823/</guid>
      <description>Rained a good portion of the day. By the afternoon I was sad that the weekend was coming to a close. Thinking I&amp;rsquo;ve never completed consecutive century rides I should try that tonight. Hopped on my bicycle and rode to the beach.
Passed by a yellow Volkswagen beetle broken down on the side of the road. Had to turn around and get a photo with Old Yeller.
Opening CLIF bar packages is frustrating especially when my hands are sweaty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Armadillo Dance Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200822/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200822/</guid>
      <description>Passed a 100 dead Armadillos on the road in the last few years. This morning I had my first live encounter. In Cross SC on Hwy 6 while still dark I thought I was riding up on a possum. It turned out to be an armadillo. We startle each other. I swerved and it danced. Heard its claws tapping on the pavement while it decided like a squirrel on which way to go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awendaw Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200816/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200816/</guid>
      <description>On the road by 3:40 AM. Heading east on Hwy 402 and Steed Creek roads I could see lightning from an offshore thunderstorm. The stars were bright overhead along with a waning crescent moon. So happy I screamed &amp;ldquo;The universe is mine!&amp;quot;.
After sunrise the clouds moved in and the temperature never rose above 75℉. In hindsight I didn&amp;rsquo;t need to wake up so early.
2020 is more than half over but I finally decided on 4 goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Loop Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200809/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200809/</guid>
      <description>Watched Josh Ibbett&amp;rsquo;s bike check for GBDuro last night. One of his snacks are M&amp;amp;M&amp;rsquo;s. I picked up a small bag at Mac Daddy&amp;rsquo;s in Cross SC. Josh won GBDuro 2020 and I finished my ride so M&amp;amp;M&amp;rsquo;s are a go!
Moved a turtle off Cane Gulley Rd. Has been months since the last time I&amp;rsquo;ve done that. During nesting season I was rescuing turtles every ride. Check out this turtle&amp;rsquo;s stare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>West Ashley Greenway Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200801/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200801/</guid>
      <description>Haven&amp;rsquo;t been to Charleston on my bicycle since the rona took off. Good to ride on the West Ashley Greenway again, even during predawn.
Slept a little over 4 hours last night. Woke up tired and never found my mojo but enjoyed riding through Charleston.
Ride on. ☮






 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>McClellanville Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200726/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200726/</guid>
      <description>Rode to my favorite small town, McClellanville. Out the door at 3:30 AM. Very little wind and pleasant temperatures until the last 1.5 hours made for a pleasant ride.
Felt pretty good after this ride. Wish I could figure out why I&amp;rsquo;m whipped after some century rides. I don&amp;rsquo;t really do anything different but the level of exhaustion varies widely. 🤔
Ride on. ☮





 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Santee Dam Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200718/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200718/</guid>
      <description>Out the door before 4 AM. Saw a couple of deer in Nexton near the same location as last week.
I rode to the Santee Dam. Makes me sad that I can&amp;rsquo;t ride across the dam, legally. It is such a good route to get the Manning. Google Maps navigation still recommends that route. I submitted a flag about it being illegal. The submission probably lands in a bit bucket.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edisto Sunrise Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200705/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200705/</guid>
      <description>Goosebumps on my way to the beach. The sun was rising on my left, a full moon was setting on my right, I was surrounded by water, and the smell of pluff mud was permeating the air. Sensory overload.
To beat the heat was on the road at 3:30 AM. Wanted to be on the beach for sunrise but was a few minutes late. The segment from the Intracoastal Waterway to the beach takes much longer than you&amp;rsquo;d think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awendaw Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200703/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200703/</guid>
      <description>Out the door before 4 AM. While still in Nexton had my first encounter with wildlife. Six deer foraging in someone&amp;rsquo;s yard were spooked by my bike and crossed the road in front of me. Neat to hear 12 hooves clacking on the asphalt.
Nearly a full moon with a warm orange tint. As the ride progressed the fog lowered which signifies no wind. Yay! It was a moist ride.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunrise Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200627/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200627/</guid>
      <description>Didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like riding this week after my 200 mile ride Sunday. Started getting the itch to ride last night. Woke up at 3 AM to avoid the heat of the day.
Hoped to see a spectacular sunrise this morning with a Saharan dust plume reaching the coast. Sunrise was nice but not spectacular.
Did see a fox this morning leaving Nexton and a deer a few minutes after the sunrise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Double Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200621/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 21:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200621/</guid>
      <description>Riding 200 miles is something that intrigued me and started to haunt me after my 160 mile Georgetown ride. What&amp;rsquo;s 40 more miles, right? A lot. I&amp;rsquo;m not getting any younger so I knocked this goal out while I still can.
Scheduling wasn&amp;rsquo;t wise on my part as it was dangerously hot. Bike computer read 104℉ a couple of times.
The first century went pretty well and was enjoyable. The second century, not so much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Santee Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200613/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200613/</guid>
      <description>The morning air was cool and dry for a day in June. Ride started with 3 turkeys and 2 deer showing their faces near Ridgeville. From Ridgeville I traveled through Harleville, Santee, Eutawville, Eutaw Springs, Cross and back home.
Good bit of wind. Sometimes favorable but mostly not.
Crossed paths and momentarily rode with a couple of cyclist from Harleyville. They were must faster than me. I was expecting to find out who they were via Strava Flyby but they must not be on Strava or if they are they don&amp;rsquo;t post publicly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Georgetown Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200607/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200607/</guid>
      <description>Rode to the city where I spent many weekends and holidays as a youth. My mother&amp;rsquo;s side of the family is from Georgetown. Everyone has died or moved away but the city is still near and dear to my heart. Good times.
Heading out of Georgetown I took South Island Rd all the way until it ends at the Yawkey Wildlife Center ferry. It added a couple of miles but it was well worth it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edisto Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200530/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200530/</guid>
      <description>Took the single speed for a century ride.
Recurring theme for Saturday rides is moving at least one turtle off the road. Today&amp;rsquo;s turtle was a little larger than the two last week. As I was telling it to stay off the road it tried to pee on me. Thankfully the stream went between my legs.
I traveled some new-to-me roads: Horseford Rd, Sandridge Rd, Old Beech Hill Rd, and Zion Rd just to name a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>McClellanville Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200523/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200523/</guid>
      <description>Rode to one of my favorite towns, McClellanville. Moved a couple of turtles off the road on the way.
Beautiful sunny warm day in the lowcountry. Temperatures ranged from 72℉ to 97℉ according to my bike computer.
This was my 72nd century ride. They ain&amp;rsquo;t getting any easier.
Good day on the saddle.
Ride on. ☮












 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salty Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200516/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200516/</guid>
      <description>Average temperature was 82℉ with peaks above 90℉. My shorts were covered with salt.
Helped a small turtle cross the road. Saw some goats.
Took a wrong turn off of Calamus Pond Rd. Ended back on Hwy 176, the very road I was trying to avoid. Oh well.
Instead of taking Hwy 52 out of St Stephen I continued on Hwy 45 eventually riding Harristown Rd back to Hwy 17-A. Nice change of scenery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cookie Fueled Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200509/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200509/</guid>
      <description>Cookie Chick SC is usually at the Summerville Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market but for now she fulfills online orders on Saturdays in North Charleston starting at 11 AM. The minimum order is a dozen. I was about 45 minutes early so I rode into Hanahan to burn some time.
Picked up my assorted dozen, ate one, and put the rest in the Topeak backloader.
Had a nice tailwind into Charleston. Took the James Island connector over to Maybank Highway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orangeburg Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200502/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 19:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200502/</guid>
      <description>Not much to see in Orangeburg but it was a ride I wanted to complete at least once. There is an 8 mile stretch on Hwy 78 that is pretty stressful traffic wise. I dreaded that segment on the way up and back. Things chill out once you get on Hwy 178. The majority of the ride is on Hwy 178.
After taking a spin around Orangeburg I took a wrong turn and asked Google navigation to get me home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;on Swamp Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200425/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200425/</guid>
      <description>First time visiting I&amp;rsquo;on Swamp. Scenic ride on a well maintained gravel forestry road. 👍
Crossing the Cooper River I chose the road instead of the multi-use path. There were too many pedestrians and cyclist for the COVID-19 era. I assume it is perfectly legal but probably frowned upon by motorist and police. I survived.
This is the first century ride since March 21, 2020 in which I was exhausted at about mile 50.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cainhoy Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200321/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 15:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200321/</guid>
      <description>Great weather. Temperatures were mostly in the 80&amp;rsquo;s ℉ although the bike computer read 91℉ at one point.
Had to ride through a controlled burn on Cainhoy Rd. Not a smart thing to be doing during a global pandemic causing respiratory illness.
The Ravenel Bridge and West Ashley Greenway multi-use paths were quite congested. Hopefully sweat and snot rockets were not shared.
Ride on. ☮</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Folly Beach Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200314/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 14:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200314/</guid>
      <description>Rather windy on the coast but the temperatures were warm enough to go just jersey, shorts, and sandals. Love it.
Rode the single speed today. Good fun.
Ride on. ☮






 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edisto Beach Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200308/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 17:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200308/</guid>
      <description>With the time change I was able to squeeze in an afternoon century and get home before dark. Nice!
Rode Old Yeller today instead of the single speed. It feels like the rolling resistance is greater on Old Yeller than the Wabi Classic single speed. I think the last couple of century rides on the single speed were easier than today&amp;rsquo;s. The extra gears are nice for bridges and headwinds but if I enjoy riding the single speed more perhaps I just need to toughen up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stono River County Park Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200301/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 16:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200301/</guid>
      <description>Rode the not-yet-open Stono River County Park. It is super nice. There is a long board walk across the marsh. The view is beautiful. There is a bicycle repair station too. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen photographs of stations like this one but this is the first one I&amp;rsquo;ve put my hands on. Love it.
It was windy but not as strong as yesterday. I was able to squeeze in a century ride on the Wabi Classic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Marion Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200223/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 16:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200223/</guid>
      <description>Rode up to Lake Marion and around Lake Moultrie. The single speed is perfect when it is flat and the headwinds are gentle. It is tough when climbing hills and bridges. Headwinds are no fun either. I definitively work harder on the Wabi Classic than I do on the Giant Anyroad 1. The simplicity of the single speed is very appealing. It is also the funnest bike I&amp;rsquo;ve ridden.
Ride on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single Speed Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200118/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 21:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200118/</guid>
      <description>The Wabi Classic continues to surprise me. The 46/18 gearing is about perfect. Getting over bridges and cutting through a headwind is tough but other than that the Wabi Classic feels really good. I&amp;rsquo;m even contemplating making this my main bike. Didn&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;d ever demote Old Yeller but watch out. The simplicity of the single speed is just so attractive. Fun times.
There was a group of about 6 teenage motorcycle riders on the West Ashley Greenway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20200110/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 21:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20200110/</guid>
      <description>I lost my cycling mojo. Monday I worked late and didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like getting up at 4:30 AM Tuesday so I decided to bike to work Wednesday instead. Wednesday morning I got geared-up and headed out for my 20 mile commute. The first 6 miles I was asking myself why am I doing this? It is fricking 31℉ and I&amp;rsquo;m not having any fun. I turned around and went home. I didn&amp;rsquo;t bike to work this week at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191215/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 17:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191215/</guid>
      <description>Didn&amp;rsquo;t think I would log a century ride today. Ride on the Lake Moultrie dike was taxing. It was windy and the trail was spongy from the recent rains. The best segment was on Hwy 45 where I had a nice tailwind. Without that I probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have made this a century ride. For the first time since Tuesday the temperature was comfortable, hanging around in the 60&amp;rsquo;s℉ for a while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Georgetown Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191123/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 17:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191123/</guid>
      <description>Made the most of the mild temperatures by spending all day on the saddle. Rode to my favorite city Georgetown SC. Georgetown is South Carolina&amp;rsquo;s third oldest city behind Charleston and Beaufort. According to Wikipedia it is also the birthplace of former First Lady Michelle Obama&amp;rsquo;s grandfather, Fraser Robinson. Many of Michelle Obama&amp;rsquo;s Robinson relatives still reside in Georgetown. Very cool in my book.
The shortest route is 130 miles but returning on the same route is boring so I chose the longer route home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Murray Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191109/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191109/</guid>
      <description>Drove the Chevy Bolt EV to Swansea, SC and parked at the Lexington County Library. Cleared it with the librarian and hit the road on Old Yeller.
First time cycling this part of the South Carolina. Surprised by the amount of urban sprawl around Lake Murray and the hills on this route. With an average temperature of 46℉ I never felt comfortable. The cool wind, hills, and heavy traffic prevented me from relaxing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Lakes Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191102/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191102/</guid>
      <description>A chilly start at 40℉. On the lake dike it was about 8 degrees warmer. Water is still warm. Nice.
Pretty good ride although I didn&amp;rsquo;t have much punch in my legs so I took it easy.
Ride on. ☮
Photo album
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charleston Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191026/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191026/</guid>
      <description>Incredibly nice weather for late October. Mid 80s℉. I&amp;rsquo;ll take it.
Chose to ride Cainhoy Rd instead of Hwy 41 at the last moment. Good decision. Hwy 41 is straight as an arrow, busier, and less scenic than Cainhoy Rd.
Rode thorough Dunes West subdivision to avoid the busiest section of Hwy 41. I haven&amp;rsquo;t memorized the route through Dunes West yet. I tend to doubt my turns. Had to look at my phone a couple of times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nestor lead out Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191019/</guid>
      <description>Up at 3 AM and on the road by 4 AM to beat the post-tropical cyclone Nestor rain. Worked out pretty well. Rain started at mile 90. Still riding the back-up bike. Can&amp;rsquo;t find the correct freehub for Old Yeller.
The only downside was the Summerville Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market was mostly closed. The vegetable stands were open but the main row with the Cookie Chick didn&amp;rsquo;t open due to Nestor. No cookies for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>South Tibwin Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 03:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191012/</guid>
      <description>A friend suggested I check-out the South Tibwin Hiking Trail so that is what I did today. I had passed the entrance to this trail on my trips to McClellanville but never ventured in. I was pleasantly surprised by the amount of water access. It is beautiful. Accidentally ran over a black snake&amp;rsquo;s tail. I hope it survived. The trail is a mix of grass, pine straw, downed tree limbs, and roots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walterboro Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20191005/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 02:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20191005/</guid>
      <description>Didn&amp;rsquo;t have a route planned when I hopped on the bike this morning. I knew I wanted a couple of cookies from the Summerville Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market. Made a loop around Summerville before heading out to Walterboro. Hwy 17-A is not great.Two lanes, plenty of vehicular traffic at 55+ MPH. I survived the trip there and took a different route home. A strong northerly wind made for a slow ride home. Temperatures were in the 70s ℉ so that was pretty sweet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edge of America Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190928/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 01:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190928/</guid>
      <description>Another beautiful Saturday in the SC lowcountry. Had a nice ride to Folly Beach.
End of Q3 already. I&amp;rsquo;ve logged a century ride for the last 14 weekends. Going to try to keep that streak going until the end of 2019. We&amp;rsquo;ll see.
Ride on. ☮
Photo album
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Santee Coastal Reserve Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190921/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 03:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190921/</guid>
      <description>The Santee Coastal Reserve is another hidden gem. The cape is absolutely gorgeous. Water fowl galore and plenty of gators too. As I rode out on the cape, sunning gators would scurry into the water. The most stunning site was a large flock of white egrets or herons flying. A look-out tower near the South Santee River provides breathtaking views.
As far as the ride goes it was great. I started from Moncks Corner instead of Summerville.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Century Saturday 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190914/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 01:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190914/</guid>
      <description>Wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure I had it in me today. Knew I was at least going to get a couple of cookies from the Cookie Chick at the Summerville Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market. Made the decision to continue the ride after taking a minute to eat one of the cookies. Glad I pressed on.
While emptying the trash from my jersey pocket at the farmer&amp;rsquo;s market my leg brushed against a poisonous plant. I guess it was poison oak or ivy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wee Tee Wildlife Management Area Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190907/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 01:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190907/</guid>
      <description>Oh my. What a hidden treasure. Wee Tee WMA is awesome. You can access it right off of Hwy 17-A north of Santee River. Surprised to see hills surrounding several beautiful lakes. Absolutely beautiful.
My plan was to cut across to St Stephen SC but I ended up back on Hwy 17-A. Not a fan of returning home via the same route so I headed to Andrews SC and caught Hwy 521.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labor Day Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190902/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190902/</guid>
      <description>Bit of a breeze blowing. I planned the route so I would have a tailwind on the way home. I thought a couple of time of turning and going home when the wind was blowing in my face. I&amp;rsquo;m glad I stuck with it. Good ride.
Ride on. ☮
Photo album
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bonneau Ferry Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190831/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190831/</guid>
      <description>Wow, what a beautiful ride. I was having a hard time deciding where to ride. Decided to explore Rice Hope Plantation and Bonneau Ferry Wildlife Management Area. Good decision. Rode miles of gravel roads. The scenery was off the chart. Truly gorgeous area. To cap the ride off I rode the Lake Moultrie west dike.
I love riding my bicycle.
Ride on. ☮
Photo album
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Donnelley WMA Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190824/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190824/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been contemplating a ride to Hunting Island, Beaufort, or Savannah GA. I chose today&amp;rsquo;s ride to the Donnelley Wildlife Management Area for more time on Hwy 17. The road surface is not good and traffic is pretty heavy until you get past Jacksonboro SC. A ride to Beaufort is going to be pretty monotonous but it is doable. We&amp;rsquo;ll see.
Donnelly WMA is pretty cool. I looped around it on a pretty good gravel road.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soggy Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190817/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190817/</guid>
      <description>Drizzle right from the start of the ride. Actually thought I would have had more rain than I did. The steadiest downpour was around Remount and Rivers in North Charleston. Kinda refreshing.
The highlight of the ride was a huge owl flyby in the Dunes West subdivision. Magnificent animal.
Ride was pleasant. Finished up the ride with a stop at the Summerville Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market to buy the last two Cookie Chick oatmeal cookies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isle of Palms Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190810/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190810/</guid>
      <description>Rode on the beach of Sullivan&amp;rsquo;s Island just before sunrise. Beautiful.
Hopped over to the Isle of Palms and then up the connector to Rifle Range Rd. To avoid the busiest section of Hwy 41 I rode through Dunes West subdivision on Park W Blvd. The route is a little longer but worth avoiding the traffic.
Had a puncture in Moncks Corner SC. Slapped a new tube on, inflated with a CO2 cartridge and was rolling again in no time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bowman Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190803/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190803/</guid>
      <description>The Keen sandals were good on the commutes this week so I tried them on a century ride. The sandals worked out well. Instead of my feet being in sweat soaked hot Adidas shoes they were airing out in the wind. 👍👍
I incorrectly thought it was going to be raining all day. There was rain off the coast and I assumed it would be heading inland so I changed my route.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Century Saturday 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190727/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190727/</guid>
      <description>Two century rides in a row having something left in the tank at the end. The wind was favorable for the most part. That probably has a lot to do with it. I&amp;rsquo;ll take it. Great ride.
Ride on. ☮
Bicycle on Diversion Canal bridge Hwy 45 
Trail between Hwy 45 and Hwy 52 
Childsbury Towne Heritage Preserve 
  Relive &#39;Century Saturday 💯&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edge of America Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190720/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190720/</guid>
      <description>Goose bumps were had while riding on the beach. First time beauty has had that affect on me.
This. was. an. absolutely. perfect. ride.
Riding over the James Island connector bridge there was a Waning Gibbous moon opposite the rising sun.
Temperatures were warm but not hot, blue sky, light winds, no altercations with automobiles, and I felt great, unlike last Saturday. I don&amp;rsquo;t think it can get any better than this but I&amp;rsquo;ll keep trying.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>McClellanville Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190713/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190713/</guid>
      <description>I love McClellanville. Such a beautiful coastal town. Fantastic homes on the tree lined Pinckney St.
My fortieth century had a brutally tough finish. My legs were cramping and I was running on empty the last two hours of this 8 hour ride. Had to stop to stretch and recover a couple of times. I never had to do that before. Here&amp;rsquo;s to the next 40 less painful century rides. 🍺</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Santee Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190707/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190707/</guid>
      <description>Alarm went off at 3 AM and I was on the road to Santee SC at 4:00 AM. This century was soooo much less difficult than Thursday&amp;rsquo;s century. I wish I knew why. I&amp;rsquo;ll take it.
Low traffic, cool weather, and good roads. Great ride.
GoPro is really donking up. Half of my footage is just white video. Time for a new camera.
Ride on. ☮
Bike on Bonner Ave near Santee SC</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>US Independence Day Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190704/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190704/</guid>
      <description>Awoke a tick or two before 3 AM and was on the road to Edisto Beach at 4:08 AM. Had the road pretty much to myself on the way there.
On Palmetto Blvd a few folks were getting their morning run and walk in and a few were cycling. On the beach folks were walking, collecting shells, and setting up for the day. Edisto Beach is a pretty chill place to be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Century Saturday 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190629/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190629/</guid>
      <description>I woke up at 3 AM and was on the road at 4:18 AM. This was a near perfect ride. I felt good all the way to the end. No altercations with automobiles. Great weather. All in all a chill ride.
A couple of turkeys crossed in front of me on Hard Pinch Rd. I stopped the GoPro after that to mark the event for later retrieval. The file is corrupt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belle Isle Plantation Cemetery Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190602/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190602/</guid>
      <description>I have seen the Belle Isle Plantation Cemetery sign many times cycling Highway 45. Today I took that turn. This is where Francis Marion and his wife are buried. Also known as The Swamp Fox he was a military officer who served in the American Revolutionary War (1775-1783). Towards the end of this ride I was in the Francis Marion forest.
It may surprise some but this part of South Carolina has some pretty good roads for riding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Century Ride before the Century Temperatures 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190525/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190525/</guid>
      <description>With triple digit temperatures in the forecast I got an early start. I was on the road by 4:20 AM. I finished the ride a little after 11 AM. It was 91℉ already.
It was a pleasant ride. My favorite segments were Hwy 402 and the West Ashley Greenway. On the way home I stopped by the Summerville Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market for 2 Cookie Chick oatmeal raisin cookies. Ride on. ☮</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eutawville Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190511/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190511/</guid>
      <description>This century ride was less strenuous than last week&amp;rsquo;s century ride. Unfortunately I don&amp;rsquo;t know why. Was it my diet this week, my hydration, my fuel, my pace, the wind, the temperature or the phase of the moon. I wish I knew so I could replicate it.
The route to Eutawville was super nice except for the 10 miles on Hwy 176. I started at 5 AM to get off of Hwy 176 as early as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>McClellanville Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190504/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 14:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190504/</guid>
      <description>So nice to be back on Old Yeller. I always enjoy visiting McClellanville. They were having their shrimp festival. I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to partake but did a walk through and then saddled up for a tough ride home.
It is getting pretty warm. My pant legs were covered in salt. I need to start my rides earlier.
Ride on. ☮





  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summerville Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190421/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190421/</guid>
      <description>After a nice Saturday in Myrtle Beach it was time for the ride home. Was on the road at 5:04 AM but quickly turned back to get my phone. After that false start the ride was so much nicer than Friday&amp;rsquo;s ride. Very light traffic, no rain, and comfortable temperatures made for a chill ride. It turned overcast around 8:30 but the clouds broke up about 1.5 hours later. There was a persistent light headwind all the way home but hey I&amp;rsquo;m not complaining.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Myrtle Beach Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190419/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190419/</guid>
      <description>I knew I was going to get rained on but it was much heavier than anticipated. The rain started at mile 51 and got heavier and heavier. Going over the Waccamaw river bridge in Georgetown the rain felt like needles.
The wind for most of the ride was a favorable cross tailwind. On the easterly section of Saints Delight Rd and coming into Georgetown it was a stiff headwind.
Traffic on Hwy 17 from Georgetown to Myrtle Beach was heavy with plenty of water ponding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Loop Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190413/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190413/</guid>
      <description>It is starting to heat up. Need to acclimate to the rising temperatures and humidity. Will need to start my rides earlier to beat the heat of the day.
This was my 30th century ride since starting them in May of last year. This one was as tough as any. Somehow I had a headwind most of the ride even though the route was a loop. How is that possible? Perfect timing I guess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daniel Island Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190330/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190330/</guid>
      <description>Spring has sprung. It was chilly this morning but when the 9 o&amp;rsquo;clock hour arrived the temperature rose to the sweet spot.
Loving the new surface on Hwy 402. Cainhoy Rd is pretty scenic for the first half. Clements Ferry Rd, Hwy 41, and Hwy 17 are no fun. Daniel Island is OK if you like big huge fancy houses. I enjoyed the water scenes. A good day. Ride on. ☮</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angel Oak Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190323/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190323/</guid>
      <description>Great day for anything outdoors. Angel Oak was today&amp;rsquo;s destination. There were quite a few folks visiting the 500 year old tree. The ride was pleasant. I was yelled at just once. Everyone else was cool. Ride on. ☮


  Relive &#39;Angel Oak Century 💯&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Folly, Sullivan, IOP Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190316/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190316/</guid>
      <description>Cycled to and on Folly Beach, Sullivan&amp;rsquo;s Island, and the Isle of Palms (IOP). Had a nice tailwind to Folly. Tide was low. I was able to ride my bike on the beach. Good number of folks were enjoying the beach but still a little chilly to enjoy the water.
Great day on the saddle. Ride on. ☮
  Photo album 
 Relive &#39;Folly, Sullivan, IOP Century 💯&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walterboro Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190309/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190309/</guid>
      <description>Had a little bit of rain and a rainbow at the start but the rain moved on and was followed by sunshine and mild temperatures.
The Hwy 17-A Avoidance route to Walterboro gets an A+ for light traffic and scenery but a C- for road surface. The asphalt was rippled, dimpled, cracked, and full of pot holes. Can&amp;rsquo;t have everything.
The Walterboro Wildlife Sanctuary was a nice treat. Good trails and boardwalks over cypress swamps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rockville Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190303/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190303/</guid>
      <description>Ride Summary  Mile 40 puncture from small wire Pulled out the wire with my teeth Mile 50 air horned by a couple of bubbas Mile 60 chased by dogs Mile 70 water cage weld snapped Mile 96 car right turned in front of me at 21 mph (no contact)  The ride started out in a damp fog. After I got through Charleston the wind was mostly at my back which was super nice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fresh Tarmac Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190223/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190223/</guid>
      <description>Mist and fog had me wet and cold on the first third of the ride. The air dried as the morning progressed even though it looked like it could rain at any moment.
The last time I rode Hwy 402 the road surface was in terrible shape. They have since resurfaced the road. It is smooth asphalt with a nice size shoulder. There are a couple of sections that have already been repaired.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worst Century Best Human Ever 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190216/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190216/</guid>
      <description>Double puncture. The first at mile 81 the second at mile 82. Both were staples in the rear tire. On the first puncture I replaced the tube. On the second I used a patch. My mini pump was pretty much useless. I was near a pay pump on the first one and got it rideable. On the second I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get enough air in it to ride so I started walking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solar Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190126/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190126/</guid>
      <description>A mostly clear blue sky made this winter century possible. If it had been overcast I would have cut this ride short. Good day in the saddle.
When you ride 100 miles you can eat what you want. Today I wanted a Veggie Lover Pizza and a beer.
 Relive &#39;Solar Century 💯&#39;  


 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Georgetown Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190119/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190119/</guid>
      <description>This ride was on my bucket list. Wanted to make a round trip to Georgetown SC from Summerville SC. Knocked it off the list today. My mother&amp;rsquo;s family is from Georgetown and it holds a special place in my heart and brain. I have many wonderful childhood memories in Georgetown. Now I&amp;rsquo;ve added one more.
Great average temperature of 54℉. It was mostly cloudy. Good to see the sun every now and again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Francis Marion National Forest Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190106/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190106/</guid>
      <description>Today&amp;rsquo;s century ride was perfect. I even had a little energy left at the end. I&amp;rsquo;m usually spent and struggling by mile 80. I&amp;rsquo;ll attribute feeling good all the way to the end to:
 An abundance of sunshine A lack of headwinds An early start Cool temperatures Nutrition (although I didn&amp;rsquo;t do anything different)  I went to bed last night excited that today was going to be awesome. I was not disappointed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edisto Beach Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20190101/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 14:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20190101/</guid>
      <description>What a way to start off the new year. A century ride to the beach with temperatures in the 70&amp;rsquo;s °F. Crazy weather and I love it.
The route to Edisto Beach is fairly scenic if you can ignore the roadside litter. There are cypress swamps, marshes, beautiful oak trees, a variety of birds and of course there is the ocean.
Good day on the saddle.
Photo album
  Relive &#39;Edisto Beach Century 💯&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kingstree Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181224/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181224/</guid>
      <description>All century rides are tough but the head winds on the way to Kingstree made this one especially challenging. Considered cutting my ride short more than once. Glad I toughed it out. Was concerned about getting home before the temperatures started dropping. Towards the end of a century it is hard to keep your body temperature up since you don&amp;rsquo;t have the energy but it worked out on this ride. Arrived home before 5 PM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IOP Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181124/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181124/</guid>
      <description>It rained before I got on the road and it looked like it was going to be a dreary wet day. Thankfully I was deceived. There was a 3 hour period of weather perfection. The sun was shining and temperatures topped out at 71°F. It was so nice. I removed my sleeves from my jacket and took off my gloves at the beach. When I hit North Charleston the clouds returned along with some wind so I put the sleeves and gloves back on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marion Moultrie Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181118/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181118/</guid>
      <description>Rode a section of dike on both Lake Marion and Lake Moultrie. Discovered dramatically that the Lake Marion dam is closed to the public. Santee Cooper is South Carolina&amp;rsquo;s state-owned electric and water utility that runs the dam. I was stopped by a Santee Cooper employee and told to turn around. I begged and pleaded for him to let me slide fearing that I may not have the fitness to tackle a 150 mile ride.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edge of America Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181111/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181111/</guid>
      <description>Temperatures min/avg/max 37.4°F / 50.6°F / 57.2°F. Windy but mostly in my favor. Had a quick easy ride to Charleston and then to Folly Beach. I prepared myself mentally for a headwind on the ride home but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t as bad as expected. Great day in the saddle.
 Photo album
Relive &#39;Edge of America Century 💯&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kiawah Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181028/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181028/</guid>
      <description>Temperatures min/avg/max 41.0°F / 56.7°F / 69.8°F. Clear blue skies and light winds. First time cycling to Kiawah Island. Maybank Rd is fairly safe, Bohicket Rd not so much. Once you get to Kiawah there are paved bike paths. Their novelty wore thin and I took the road on the way out of Kiawah. I&amp;rsquo;m not a big fan of golf courses and huge houses which is what Kiawah is all about but the ride was nice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jamestown Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 15:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181021/</guid>
      <description>48.2 °F at the start with a stiff headwind. I thought more than once about turning around in Moncks Corner. I&amp;rsquo;m glad I didn&amp;rsquo;t. The middle section of the ride was good. Warmed up into the 60&amp;rsquo;s with mostly a tail wind. Rode some gravel, rock, and mud on Tiger Corner Rd in the Francis Marion Forest. The headwinds returned once I got through Charleston. The temperature dropped a little as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ACE Basin Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181013/</guid>
      <description>A friend suggested I visit the ACE Basin so that is what I did. I had not been there since 2014. To my delight it hasn&amp;rsquo;t changed a bit.
Not a cloud in the sky all day long. I donned arm warmers and gloves this morning. It was a good decision. Temperature started at 50.0 °F and maxed out at 84.2 °F according to Garmin.
A few new-to-me roads in today&amp;rsquo;s route.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Santee National Wildlife Refuge Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20181006/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20181006/</guid>
      <description>This ride had a little of everything. There was rain at the start, gravel trails, muddy trails, sandy trails, overgrown trails, good tarmac, terrible tarmac, a fenced off bridge, and an illegal ride across Lake Marion on I-95. What a day.
Photo album
 Relive &#39;Santee National Wildlife Refuge Century&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>McClellanville Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180923/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180923/</guid>
      <description>Humans are awesome. There are so many cyclists that inspire me. Lael Wilcox is the latest that touched me. Last night I watched a mini documentary on her Navad 1000 Across Switzerland race. It gave me the confidence to knock out today&amp;rsquo;s ride.
I woke up at 3 AM and was on the road by 4:18 AM. Took a couple of wrong turns in Bethera. It was still dark and the route was new to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labor Day Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180903/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180903/</guid>
      <description>First time riding on the Lake Marion dike and The Santee Dam. Took me a little while to find the gate to the dike. It was still dark when I arrived. I ended up at Wilson&amp;rsquo;s landing which is several miles from where I needed to be. The entrance to the dike is a yellow gate behind a Santee Cooper garage to the right of the Harry&amp;rsquo;s Fish Camp entrance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tri-County Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180901/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180901/</guid>
      <description>Woke up around 3 AM and was on the road at 4:40 AM. From Summerville I rode through Moncks Corner, Bonneau, St Stephen, Pineville, Cross, Holly Hill, and Harleyville. It was a little chilly this morning until the sun came up. Not looking forward to summer ending.
I think I fueled too much too quickly. My stomach was a little sore.
At the end of my ride I rode by the Summerville Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market for some Cookie Chick cookies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Folly Beach Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180825/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180825/</guid>
      <description>Woke up around 3 AM and was on the road at 4:18 AM. Nice tail wind for 70 miles. Tough head wind on the last leg of the ride. Shifting on Old Yeller is a little slow but other than that she is riding like a champ. Good day in the saddle.
 Photo album
Relive &#39;Folly Beach Century&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Century Saturday 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180811/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 11:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180811/</guid>
      <description>This is my 4th weekend century in a row. I&amp;rsquo;m getting to the point if I don&amp;rsquo;t ride 100 miles I feel lazy.
Today&amp;rsquo;s ride started at 4:57 AM. Nice to have the roads all to myself for a while. There was a summer shower in West Ashley but the rest of the ride was dry. Good day.
 Photo album
Relive &#39;Century Saturday&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kingstree Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180804/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 23:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180804/</guid>
      <description>Rode to Kingstree SC for the second time this year. Traffic was light. Temperatures were pleasant. Wind was calm. Riding a century every weekend is becoming a habit. Not sure why.
For my post ride meal I ate eggs, grits, and toast at Waffle House. It was delicious but pretty much anything tastes good after a century ride. I was expecting Waffle House to be a little livelier it being midnight on a Saturday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charleston Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180728/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180728/</guid>
      <description>Mapped out my route Friday night and pretty much stuck to it. This is my third century ride for July 2018. It was a enjoyable ride except for Highway 402. It is the worst road surface I&amp;rsquo;ve ever ridden. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I will ride that highway again until they pave it which will probably be a very long time from now.
My favorite segments were the West Ashley Greenway, Charleston Battery, and Arthur Ravenel Jr Bridge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Moultrie Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180722/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180722/</guid>
      <description>Frequently I get on my bike without a plan. Today was one of those days.
I do like to ride through Cane Bay on Sunday to check on the progress near Black Tom Rd. So that is were I headed. They have asphalt almost to Black Tom Rd. Looking good.
I then headed towards Moncks Corner and decided to get on the Lake Moultrie dike. Once I got to Bonneau I wanted to find where I could continue on the dike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edisto Beach Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180704/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180704/</guid>
      <description>I woke up at 4 AM and was on the road by 5 AM. The rain started at mile 25 and didn&amp;rsquo;t let up much until I returned to Summerville. But hey at least I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about the heat. It was a cool ride in many ways. I love the scenery. Traffic was light for the most part. On the way home when the rain was really coming down a kind human in a pickup truck with a bicycle in the back asked if I wanted a lift.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memorial Century 💯</title>
      <link>https://pla.bike/posts/20180526/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pla.bike/posts/20180526/</guid>
      <description>Woke up around 3 AM and could not go back to sleep. I knew I wanted to ride a century today and my excitement cost me some sleep. Oh well. I was on the road by 5 AM which was a good thing. The summer is coming on strong. The earlier in the day I ride the better. The entire ride was on 4 lane highways. The traffic was light from home to Kingstree.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>